so another thing i want to show you is
the
schedule so this is also um
a unique feature implemented by color so
let's allow you to
schedule a call to be involved later in
the blockchain so there's no need to
have like off-chain timers involving
smart countries
on certain time you can just schedule a
call and you
will be called in later
so this is the interface of the
assistant contract so it takes address
uh how much uh native token you will
have to send uh
in our state will be they say token the
guest limit for follicle
so you uh the transition fee for less
amount of gas limit will be
reserved up front and if and after the
call is executed if there are any
leftovers it will get refined later
and there's a storage limit so let's see
the state rent features
and also you'll need to accola even
it's not enabled so you just pass a big
value for now
for the test net
so let's see some element delay so many
my markup blocks before let's
schedule a call will be called so you'll
notice
and this number is a number of blocks
after the current box so if you pass 0
this means the
schedule call will be scheduled in the
next block
if you pass 1 this means that you'll be
called in the two blocks after the
current block
and the input data so is what the
just including the selectors and the
parameters to
so to use the scheduler is super simple
this is a recurring payment smart
contract the idea is basically you
if you want to for example budgeting do
some budgeting
you have say ten thousand dollars for to
spend in the next six months
you probably don't want to have all of
them available because you might
just spend often in the next two day
so you can deploy the circulating
payments by countries log to all your
money
and for every week and send yourself
some amount of money back
so yeah there's a payable so you can
let's receive the native token
ensure that's receiving enough token
save some parameters the pre the period
how many times this payment should
happening
and the destination the receiver address
then you can just use the scheduler
smart contracts to schedule calls so in
this case you'll call itself
this country itself uh the value is zero
in this case
uh the second standard storage limit
just passing some big enough number to
get things working
and the period and then the input data
so we want to call the pay
function so just encode signature the
pay function without any arguments
and in the pay function we don't want
anyone just call us so make sure the
sender
is the smart country itself so other
people kind of call us
to trigger a early pay
and if the remaining account is equal to
one so this is the last call the pay
in next case it will just self-destruct
send everything
to the recipient address and at the same
time disregardless country
just be a nice citizen to free up or use
to free up our used compress
to save some storage usage
and otherwise we'll just send this
amount of money to the tool
and reduce remaining account and
schedule another call to be called later
yep so this is basically the schedule
called smart contract
very simple very easy to use the
scheduler feature
and in the unit test well we have some
unit test
seminar setup so let's also deploy this
to your local test net
and run the unit test to verify if
everything works
because this assumes um
thus the united states is run with
instances
so that it will generate a new block um
when the new transition
is entering a transition pool so
in this case we're using a system remark
smart transition
to trigger a new block
um yeah so this is
all a lot sort of example source of
oracle which is also
a very similar scheduler you will just
offer the
simple simple interface git price and
you can use this
to get to access the price data from
oracle
so you can work in in our wiki we should
have documents of all the system smart
contracts
so of all address and they are also
available
in the ebay here as well so you can just
try those smart countries
in the columbia yeah
so that is um
yeah most all the things i'm gonna show
you so basically you can use akala ebn
um so on the ebay playground to
deploy and run your smart contracts to
try things you can use remix
to build to just do your smart control
development you can even just deploy
them
to the js um step inside remax
for debugging other things if you are
not using the native feature
you need feature of archive and just
compile them
and save the json file upload to the car
ebn to be executed
or you can just using
the waffle to build your smart
controllers
and write a simple scrap using the
using the volte.js to deploy your smart
contracts to
our public testnet or your local owned
local testnet
and this will work with your existing
eso js project