so next thing i'm going to show you um
is how to deploy a uni swap to the akala
blockchain
i would like to use the units of ripple
directly but unfortunately the uni swap
ripple is using the very old version of
easters
so there needs a lot of water to migrate
into the
newer version to be compatible with both
djs so i'm just
taking the artifacts from the unit slope
ripple
so those are the json file
um so actually let me just run it so
this will
deploy the unit contract to
our test net so
so this is the all the setup required um
so in the deploy um smart uh deploy.js
you can see
the code it's just a pretty standard eso
stress there's nothing special
to akala it's just a normal ethereal
project so you can see um
here i'm creating uh uh the yasay token
contracts for the
color and the top token this is the
country address
so this is a system contract so we can
pick the country address
so you can see this is a bunch of sales
to keep things simple
and we'll deploy the units of factory
contracts and we deploy the uni support
contracts
just put in the control address
approve um so we can
do some transfer add some liquidity
and just prints much more information up
so this is basically the scrap to deploy
units work
on our test net so you can see
it deploys the router to the suggest
so i'm going to change it address here
and run this square so this square will
basically
takes the units to broker again do some
proof
uh check some balance and do a unit
slope trade
that's in this case you try to sell some
of those to buy some sale token
um so it would try to sell exactly one
dot to buy
hong kong to buy a sound amount of sa
and this will print the balance to
verify if the trade is success
so it's running on this net so you can
see um the before
balance the trade after balance so the
dos amount reduced by one
the ac amount increased by roughly one
yep you can check the liquidity
pool in the trading period
you can see um this one charges some
amount of liquidity fee as well
so this is basically um how you can
like write a scrap to trade unit
with the scrap so obviously you can't
easily connect this to your existing
ui to get things working
um in the setup js we don't do too much
in special special things so
what we do especially basically create a
provider so this
case in this case this is uh ether's
provider so it's offered the implemented
by the body
implementing the provider interface
abstract provider interface of esos
so it's abstract provider so it works
with css
js and this takes a websocket provider
which is basically in a node url
wait for community create the
creator signing keep here so you will be
using the one coming from the
environment variable which i have
defined
myself or it just takes the test
keep here if you're running this on your
local test name
and create a signing key create a signer
and this is the again
abstract signus from the ethers
yes and that's pretty much it so now you
with this will
then you can just use it as a normal
um wallet
and this should just work with your
existing deployment scrapper and other
scrap they're using ethers js so this is
basically
um how you can deploy
the unit swap contracts into our test
net
and or if you want you can also deploy
this to your local network so
you just if you don't set up any
environment