[Music]
and this is one the reason that i we
think why crew is so useful
when it's become a project you can
unlock the utility of your kusama token
and start to
um to to to borrow against your your uh
your
summer token so this is the borough
borrowing interface
uh you can see an overview of your
current position so you can see
you have um i have already borrowed open
a position on ram bdc
i borrow roughly um three thousand
dollars against
zero point one run bdc that's a little
bit risky but i mean that's what um the
system allows
um you can actually create loans using
any sort of asset that will be
available um in the governance process
allowed to be using crypto
and in this particular interface here i
have dot
l dot which we'll be covering later and
this will be definitely it would be like
kusama
el kikuzama and bitcoins so what i'm
going to
demo here is that i'm going to borrow
more uh
against my 0.1 ram btc position here
so you can see um the current bitcoin
oracle rate is
roughly that number i'm still quite safe
to borrow a little bit more against that
0.1 ram bdc
so i'm going to press generate more i'm
going to press hey i would like to
probably ten dollars more
and i press confirm and this is where
the signing comes up i'm gonna type in
my key
password and sign the transaction and
boom i have ten dollar more that i can
spend and this is how fast um
and production network looks like and
all this is happening on the fly for
real
um and you can actually see this on the
on the on the block scanner that's
provided by sub scan
so um this is amazing right this is um
much much
more um responsive much much more user
friendly
also i can also replay right i can pay
back i set a position if i think um
i'm going to reduce a little bit of risk
here i can pay about 100 year ausd
that's like reducing my calculation
ratio
and any asset that will be available
through the governance process can be
borrowed against
different assets would have different
risk parameters so for example bitcoin
might have a risk parameter
on the medieval credit ratio on the
liquidation ratio on the liquidation fee
uh dots l dots ksm lksm they might all
have different
ratio they'll be managed and governed by
the governance process
so that is uh essentially how you borrow
against um
kratchos uh in guru
yeah let so maybe one thing we can do
this concept
of collateralization and taking loans is
probably new to a lot of people i know
it was new to me
um at one point and basically like to to
make this as simple as possible
um like i think many of us are aware of
how like a home
loan works where typically you might put
like 10 down or 20
down that cash that you put down is what
you're putting
down in order to get the full the full
loan of whatever you're getting for that
house
but with the way this works in crypto um
we're actually over you're over
collateralizing
the loan so that's why these collateral
ratios are over
100 and you're what you're doing like
what it really means of collateral
is that you're actually taking bitcoin
something like bitcoin
you don't need to sell it but you can
pull out
ausd a stablecoin with your bitcoin
still there
not sold and then you can take the ausd
and either
you can send that to people you can make
payments you can use that to provide
liquidity within our decks but
that's essentially what this collateral
ratio means
yeah essentially give you more utility
um to the asset that you are holding to
that you might not want to sell or in
short term
and for example for fukusama for for
lksm those are perfectly great collector
for you to gain more utility
out of your 16 kusama holdings you can
go long you can go short you can
it's i mean the option is it's in your
hand to decide how you're going to use
this collector um to trade and write
with the market
what about interest so are you paying
interest when you're taking out
these loans and how does that work yes
so the interest essentially is what we
call the stabilization fee
um if you take a long there will be
definitely some interest occur
um and this is also the interest used to
manage the
supply and demand of the stablecar as
well as like the
um the way to maintain that the
stablecoin will be packed to to
a dollar in value and the interest um
all the state
stabilization fee will be managed by the
governance process
really depends on demands and supplies
and do you know your interest rate
before you take out the loan
obviously definitely so let's say that
we want to create a lot we're going to
create some ldl ksm and spectro
i'm going to put in maybe 5l uh l ksm
here and i'm going to take maybe a two
dollar loan
you can already see that um um
the amount of money that you can borrow
the interest rate in here the
liquidation penalty
yeah if things goes wrong that where how
you can but in chance that if you over
capitalize and the position becomes
risky
you might get liquidated so this is the
um the
the the figure that you're able to see
before you
create a lawn and the final confirmation
stage you will be
once again so go ahead and confirm all
the numbers
and press confirm and this is how you
open a long position so
i just created a loan using my lksm and
received like two
dollars so you can say if i now go back
to the interface
i have two position open one with
bitcoin one with um
lksm those is like um and i totally have
borrowed
probably like few thousand dollars
against both um lksm
and ram btc okay that makes sense
and someone asked where does that
interest actually go
well the n26 actually go to the treasury
um
and being managed by the network right
it's uh it's essentially
uh controlled by the network for the
long prosperity of the network
the interest ultimately would be the
surplus within this system
and if you read our white paper
regarding the decentralized solving
wheels fund
the interest is ultimately hold managed
by the token holders
okay the liquidation concept i think is
new to a lot of people
what happens if the token that is
basically collateralized
the value drops so liquidation in this
sense does not mean that you kind of
like lose everything that you put down
that's why there was a liquidation
percentage so in the example rotate just
showed it said 20
yeah i think to better um think about
liquidation it's more of like
uh if you collect allies and you borrow
against your bitcoin and then pick a job
to a particular price
a fraction of your collector will be
sold and you will see that if you were
just like sold those collectors
at that price you would still hold on to
the the money they borrow against it's
just like
you sold those characters at a penalty
you