hey everybody this is brett a developer
at akala
and in this video i'm going to be
talking about how addresses work on
polkadot and kusama
so if you're coming from the world of
ethereum you might be used to addresses
looking something like this
but in the world of poken kusama you
might be used to something like this
a bunch of different addresses with a
bunch of different formats all from one
account
so how does that work well let's start
with an analogy
here we have a bird and in english we
can write the word bird like this
in chinese we might write it like this
and in spanish we might write it like
this
a bunch of different ways to write the
same exact thing and they all represent
the same thing
well your addresses in polkadot and
kusama kind of work the same exact way
your wallet will hold your public and
private key and all the different
formats you see depending on the chains
you attach to are all just different
representations of that same public key
for example here we have this public key
and on polka dot it would be represented
like this with a format starting with a
one
kusama would be represented like this a
format starting with a capital letter
and in the substrate generic address it
would be something like this
starting with the number five so that's
pretty cool that means that you can use
one address or one account across all
the different chains
and while that is true it's not
recommended
typically it's better to have distinct
accounts with their own private keys for
each network
the biggest reason is security if one of
your accounts becomes compromised
then the assets in your other accounts
are safe so let's see this in practice
here i'm on the polkadot.js website and
we're going to create two new accounts
really quickly so you see that i have a
distinct uh seed phrase right here i'm
going to click save
give it a name let's call it make this a
kusama account
and give it a password
and we're going to create one more
account for polka dot
again see it's another distinct seed
phrase different from the previous one
it's going gonna call it polka dot
i'm gonna give it a password
and now you'll see that i'm connected to
the polka dot network and when i
reload the page
both of the addresses pop up and again
this is not what we recommend doing
it's recommended you have a distinct
account with its own private key just
like these two
and that they're only set up for one
network each so we're going to change
this one
to only be viewed on kusama and this one
to only be viewed at polka dot
and now if i reload this page again
you'll notice that only the polka dot
extension account pops up
and on the kusama side
only the kusama network extension pops
up
okay that's it for this video i hope
everyone learned something and let us
know if there's any other videos you'd
like us to cover
thanks