Hi everyone, this is Bette. You are here,
congratulations! You are witnessing the
launch of the decentralized web,
the first ever crowdsourced parachain
auction on Kusama, Polkadot canary
network.
Now of course Acala canary network,
Karura, is at the very forefront of this
unprecedented launch.
By supporting Karura's crowdloan here
you will be helping us
to launch the DeFi hub of Kusama,
which will allow you to trade, stake, lend
and borrow
and earn various youths on your digital
assets.
But of course no promises, expect chaos
and expect
Karura. Now let me run you through
number of ways to participate in the
Karura crowdloan.
If you have a referral link, you can use
that to join the event directly,
otherwise you can just go to our website
acala.network to participate.
There are three ways we recommend to
participate in the event
to maximize your rewards, but it's
permissionless event
so you can well make your own judgment
on how you would like to participate.
Well, obviously, you can participate just
directly on this website
using polkadot.js extension or
you can participate via our partner
exchanges
or via our partner mobile wallets.
We will continue to add official
partners to the list
as they become ready. Please, do reach out
to the exchanges and
wallets for any support questions.
Before you start though, do check if you
have the extension
installed and also have some free KSM
in your wallet to participate.
The Karura crowdloan will airdrop a
minimum of
12 KAR rewards for 1 KSM contributed in
the event.
Okay, now let's connect to the extension.
Please read and accept the terms and
conditions regarding the event and also
the privacy policy,
before you proceed. Your acceptance will
be a
signed message from your current account.
It won't be sent on chain
and won't cost you anything.
If you have contributed to the event
already, you shall see a balance on top
and estimated KAR rewards. Then just put
in the KSM
contribution amount. Notice the lease
period
is 48 weeks, so if Karura successfully
wins the auction,
your KSM will be locked for 48 weeks
and 30% of all rewards are transferable
up front, the remaining will be vested.
You can contribute multiple times
during the entire crowdloan period.
If you used a referral link, the referral
code will be filled in automatically.
Otherwise you can just grab a code from
our discord community
and you'll receive 5% bonus.
Now you can just
submit the contribution transaction to
the Kusama relaychain.
This may take a few seconds as it will
wait for Kusama to finalize and confirm
your
contribution transaction.
And that's all done! Please do share
your great achievement on Social Media.
In any case,
congratulations again and thank you for
making history
with Karura!