I'm joined here by Ruitao,
CEO and Co-founder of Acala. I'm
Dan Reecer and today we're going to be
talking about
Ruitao, his kind of background, career,
some personal life and then a little
bit of his thoughts around
Acala and Karura. Ruitao, do you want to
get us started and
maybe introduce yourself? Thanks Dan and
hello everyone.
This is Ruitao, one of the Co-founders of
Acala network. I'm actually living in New
Zealand. I moved to New Zealand about
18+ years ago and pretty much
lived in New Zealand ever since then.
I love this place.
Personally, I'm an engineer, I'm a nerd
and also I've been an
entrepreneur for pretty much my whole
life. About seven years ago, I
discovered blockchain and started to
believe that this was/is inevitable. So I got
fully committed on blockchain, about
seven years ago,
and we started our collab
two years ago.
It has been a great ride and
this is what we've been working very
hard for the past two years and this is
what we get
at this stage that you will see today.
Awesome. Just so people can get to
know you a little bit better, could you
maybe tell us a few things that you like
to do in your free time,
when you're not working, which is most of
the time?
I think I have like two addictions.
I would call them addictions. So one
is
snowboarding. I don't actually quite like
other sports but snowboarding. It is
something that really gets me going.
Before Covid, I went snowboarding
every year
in the Northern hemisphere and in the
Southern hemisphere.
There's one bonus you get for living in
New Zealand: you get actually two
winter seasons. Usually when it is
summer in the
Northern hemisphere, we can ski in the
beautiful mountains in New Zealand,
and then, when it's summer in the
New Zealand time, we can go to the
Northern hemisphere to snowboard.
that's one of
my biggest addictions or
hobbies, I would say - snowboarding.
The other hobby that I have is that,
since I'm a nerd / an engineer,
I was really fascinated of creating
my own hobby software or
or hardware or a hybrid of those two.
For example in our office on my desk
I have
a box made of like primitive
electronic parts they actually display
the crypto price. It's a crypto tracker
that I make from for myself
and it is made of Lego.
I do have some MCU that's behind it, but
it's actually made of Lego.
That's why I call it real money Lego,
as a joke.
Those are my two I would say biggest
addictions: snowboarding and
make electronics. Where do you snowboard
in the Northern hemisphere?
In Japan or my favorite
spot is in Colorado.
I think there's a number of reasons I
love Colorado. First,
people are
so nice
in Colorado. Second, because in the
middle of the US continent,
the snow quality is guaranteed
to be awesome.
There's no wind, usually there's very
nice weather every day. That's my
favorite
ski place. Out of all this ski fields
in Colorado, my favorite is
Breckenridge,
the reason being is actually a real town,
it has a vibrant
community feeling out there. It's not
like a ski resort.
When I go
to Breckenridge, I live
off the mountain in a town.
It feels like you're living in
in a real village rather than living in
a ski resort. So that's my favorite spot.
Good spot. You
talked about skiing or snowboarding
and building kind of like software -
hardware. Is there anything else about
you that
people may not know?
I also play some games
competitively.
I used to, I no longer have time
to play them competitively.
So I play Counter-Strike, CS go,
I also play
StarCraft 2
back few years ago
when it was still
hot. Iplay those two games.
I think i answered the question. One
day on Twitter people ask me what
sort of skin I have
when I'm playing CS go. Well,
I have some
nice skin but
then I decided to commit in crypto.
I traded all my skins
for crypto. That's one of the
best decisions ever.
Once you get into crypto, it's
pretty much 24/7.
You don't have time to play anymore. I
mean, I do still play like if I have
five minutes,
I still play a little bit, but I don't
play it seriously
anymore. Cool.
So one other question.
If you could pick a few characteristics,
how do you think your family or friends
would describe you?
That's actually hard, because I
don't know
what I feel it is going to be accurate, but
I think people will
classify me as like a nerd and if people
get to me know better,
they will think that I'm quite friendly.
I'm also very very easy to
get along with as well. I make jokes
about stuff.
When I play CS go, if I
can find a way to make the whole
team feel happy
by doing some silly jokes, and I know that
we are winning for sure, I would do some
silly jokes.
Things like that. I think I'm a nerd,
but when it comes to actual work, I'm
very serious. I'm serious about what we
are trying to do.
I'm fully convinced that
our belief and our value
proposition is going to be true.
That's like two faces of
me: when I am working
I'm very
serious,
but very easy going; when I'm playing,
I'm trying to have fun and
give me the best
experience for the whole
team that's playing with
me. Perfect.
This is a question that I asked the
other three Co-founders
and it's from this guy Tim Ferriss,
he asked a lot of these people at the
interview.
if you had a huge billboard
that you could put
in front of a billion people and
give a message
to everyone, what do you think you would
put on that billboard?
On the billboard for everyone?
There's so many terms that
I would put, but I think ultimately with the
new firm that we are currently managing, I
will put
"Own your own assets". That's probably the
first that's coming to my mind, because
blockchain is actually the very first
technology
that enables us to own assets digitally.
Before blockchain, nothing is possible.
You think you own your email
account, you don't.
You think you own your facebook
account, you don't. Everything
revolving around
this idea of owning your own assets
is very fascinating and
everyone should be
able to own their own assets.
It applies to even something that's
not in the internet.
If you think about it, you own an asset,
for example you own
a car, you have a title in a car, but
again it still manages through
an authority. But the blockchain is
the very first technology
that enables to
truly own your assets.
I think the very first
idea that I want to preach to the
whole world is that now with blockchain
you can own your own assets.
Exactly.
On all these weeks where
we've been working
a lot and there's a lot on our minds, do
you have
any tactics you use for dealing with
maybe
stress? Or when you're unfocused,
what do you do in those times to
bring yourself back?
Typically I don't get stressed,
because I'm fully convinced that what
we are trying to do
is viable and is inevitable and I want
to be part of that,
but, if I do really get a lot of work and
if I work through
a number of nights, and really
need to have some
break free time, then I would go camping.
That's one of the bonus that you
get for living in New Zealand, right.
There are so many nice places,
quiet places. Within
one / two hour drive, you can
put your tent in the back of your car
and then you can just go camp
for a night. In the
morning you will wake up with
birds
singing,
you will see a lot of nice quiet
scenery.
One of the best things of
camping is that
I will bring some snack with me, I can
watch a movie in the tent, I can have
some snacks and that's like a break free
time for me.
I would say that, if I really get
stressed, I will go camping. I would still
bring my laptop with me, though, in
case I need to respond to messages
in an urgent way I can still do it.
That's probably the best way for me
to get some break free time out of
the
almost 24/7 working cycle.
You're kind of an
advertisement for visiting and living in
New Zealand right now.
I think during Covid
it's a very good place to live in
because
there's pretty much no Covid her,
but I think, after the world will open up
when Covid will be
eradicated, everyone
should visit
New Zealand. It's one of the most
beautiful country in the world.
People are friendly.
The scenery is nice. I just like
every part of it.
It's the place where I live.
We need to get a crypto conference
together there someday.
There's a rich community here.
Maybe we should, right. So, once
we finish all the very
aggressive
pace work that we're currently working
on, maybe we should start to build the community.
Well, actually it's already in progress.
We already have a Polkadot and
Kusama meetup here
in New Zealand. We haven't posted
any events yet, but we will.
Let's move onto a little bit
about your career.
Could you walk us through your
career path and what led you to the
blockchain world and
ultimately starting Acala?
I would say that I have
this entrepreneurial mind
built into my brain.
After graduating from the university, I
only had one job, which
was a financial-related job.
I'm still in very good relation with
my very first boss.
After that, I've been pretty
much on my own.
For the past 18 plus years, I've been
an
entrepreneur and I work for myself.
Before I got into the crypto, I was an
independent app developer. Because
I'm an engineer myself,
I'm also pretty good at
(maybe with a bit of sarcasm)
designing stuff. I'm a
fullstack
app developer. I created a number of apps.
It has been a
very good experience
working
with the app store, with working with
Apple. Pretty much all the apps that I did
were featured
by Apple. I created one app for
myself as a hobby. I created a
ski tracker
that would tell you like what time it is,
what your current speed is
and that at the end of your day
would tell you how
how much ride
you did for that day and would give you a
whole
map of where you've been to in the
mountain. That
was probably one of the last
apps I created. It
was again featured by Apple. I loved the
idea of working on something that can bring
meaningful value for users and for
other people.
I was very surprised to
find that, I when I was
riding in Breckenridge back
I don't know how many years ago,
there's another rider that's sitting
in a shared lift
beside me and he's using the app that I
developed and that's like what makes me
really really happy about that.
Since I was developing the app in
New Zealand, I had to test it.
It was summer in New Zealand and
there was no mountain to test.
So I drive the car upside down
in a tiny park to test if
that worked. So that's it, before
blockchain I was pretty much
into all the areas that have
potentials on new
sectors. I discovered a bit
about Bitcoin when it was less than a
hundred dollars. I don't know when was
that.
By then I wasn't convinced. I thought
it was impossible.
I knew the idea but I didn't
think it would
become something
that's actually viable.
But after Bitcoin rose to
a 1000 dollar / 2000
dollar,
at that point I was convinced.
The impossible happened.
What will come after
that would be the inevitable.
That's when I decided I needed
to get onto this sector,
get into this blockchain movement.
So, I joined a venture in New Zealand. It's a
blockchain startup. This
startup was grow rapidly
during the
2017 ICO boom.
In that period, I learned a lot.
From that experience,
there's a number of things that
I still
consider valuable lessons today.
One thing is
how to stay motivated when
there are so many things happening; how to
stay motivated and create something
that's actually
viable and can bring value for all the
token holders, all the users,
everyone evolved in the ecosystem of the
product that you are creating.
That's something I learned. The other
thing that I also learned is that how
to scale and stay focused.
Because like we are in the
exponential growth
era in this industry,
you can see that companies grow very very
fast, but
growing a company while stay focused,
stay tuned
to your value proposition is
quite challenging.
it's about team building, it's about
bringing together people with the same mindset.
It's the hardest thing to do.
That's the lesson I learned
and I'm very very fortunate to have met
Bryan
and Bette. They are all Co-founders of
Acala. I worked with them
in the previous
project and I know them because I
worked directly with them for over
a year. I would say that
we share the same value proposition, we
share the same
personality and we think we are
a perfect match
for building a team together. At
some point I started thinking:
if I want to create
something
that's actually useful and that
has an
impact in this industry, then I need to
start my own venture. That's when
I had the idea of creating this new venture.
I had Ruitao, I had Bette as Co-founders.
I wanted to work in this sector.
That's when
I started to work on this. About two
years or two and a half years ago,
we started this new venture
with Bette and Bryan.
We got fully committed to this new venture.
We talked about the idea of
what we could or
should work on. I think the core
value of this team is that we believe
that, regardless where we
work on, it needs to be viable, it needs
to have a market
product fit. That's where we see
the finance sector is going to be the
very first sector to have this product
market fit.
About two and a half years ago
we started this new venture and I'm very
fortunate.
At that time,
I went to the very first
hackathon that
took place in China, in Hangzhou. This was
a Polkadot hackathon.
That's where I met the
other Co-founder Fuyao in China.
That's how Acala was
conceived. Pretty much after
that, we've been working
every day
24/7, working on the product,
getting the product out,
getting all the code ready.
Everything went and is going very well.
I see this is only
the beginning, right.
We have the code
pretty much ready to go, but we
haven't launched the network yet.
I think that, once we launch
the network, it is still the very
beginning of what would be possible
in the upcoming two or
three years.
There was a period in there where
you guys,
the three of you, started Laminar. Is that
right? Yes.
Can you talk about starting
Laminar and then how that evolved into
Acala and maybe the process you guys
went through?
You didn't just pick Polkadot
you evaluated several different options.
I think maybe talking about that and how
you chose Polkadot would be interesting
too.
I think back then we already
connected with Parity, so we already knew
Substrate.
But when we started this new venture,
Laminar,
we were thinking about what we should do,
what we should work on,
and, as I mentioned previously, we thought that,
whatever we would work on, we needed to work
on something that's viable and has a
market product fit.
Finance is the first sector that we
could see
it could bring real useful applications on top
of blockchain. No matter what we do,
our belief is that we need to
work on something finance-related.
We thought about all the stuff that we
could do. We had the idea of
bringing a synthetic asset training
protocol that can allow
trader to trade in a leveraged way -
which is
under development still today.
We thought that
we needed to work on something that's like
financial base layer or primitive or
something like that.
We started evaluating that: where do
we wanted to deploy
our solution onto? Back then Ethereum
wasn't that congested
but we researched every
single
viable base layer out there. We did some
research on Ethereum 2.
We did research on Cosmos and, although
we already knew Parity, we also
did an independent assessment about
Substrate and Polkadot.
We think Ethereum 2 is super cool,
but we do not know when it's gonna
become available.
We think Cosmos is also a very good
framework. It allows
builders to build a blockchain
in a very fast way. But again we bounced
into a problem: if we want to
build something that's
bankrate security, how do we boost our
security?
Ultimately we reached the conclusion
that, if you look at Substrate,
it is the best
among all
other base layers. It offers the
flexibility
for developers like us to create
blockchain with
full customizability. It offers
the security needed to deploy a
blockchain
onto Kusama or onto Polkadot network.
It also enables the
interoperability that
will create no
longer a liquidity sylo.
Then we will be working
using Substrate and we're going to
work on Polkadot.
That's pretty much an educated decision.
it's less than a guess, it's
actually more of an informed
educated decision. When we're looking
back two years ago, the Polkadot
ecosystem was very different from what we
know today.
There were few teams that were building
on Polkadot,
only a handful teams
were building. We pretty much
knew all the other teams that were building
in the Polkadot ecosystem.
We saw a lot of stuff that's lacking,
for example there's no stablecoin.
Substrate wasn't very mature
back then, I mean even the
idea project wasn't
in
the reach of light launch.
We thought there were so many
things lacking at that time. If we wanted
to work on something that's finance
related, we're gonna
work on those financial primitives.
That's when we met Fuyao.
Fuyao had the same idea,
we shared the same idea.
That's essentially how Acala network
was born: a set of financial primitives
to make sure that
the whole financial sector, the whole
financial
application can be enabled on top of
Polkadot.
That's awesome. I just learned some
things myself, so appreciate that.
Let's move on to
Acala and Karura.
One thing I was just wondering,
if you were to describe
Karura. So for people's
background who may not be aware, so we're
building
Acala as this DeFi hub for Polkadot and
then Karura is our DeFi hub we're
building for Kusama.
Could you just describe
if you were to pick three
characteristics, how would you
describe Karura in
three words? This is an
interesting question. In three
words.
I would say "wild", that's really the
very first word that I can think of,
that's the nature of Kusama.
The second one I would say "vibrant",
because that's
my feeling for the Kusama community. It's
even more distributed.
Finally, I wouldn't use
the word "chaos", but I would like to use
something ...
let me think
about what world ...
"aggressive", probably is the word.
We would like to roll out
new and brave ideas on Karura. It's the
canary network. It's also
to serve this model of more
fast-paced, more aggressive communities.
Those are probably the
three words that I can think of as my
initial shots.
Just for people's background,
what are some examples of things that we
could do differently on Karura than
Acala. I know there's like collaterals.
Could you explain more about that?
I think that's like the
collaterals which
might be slightly relaxed,
but we still want to make sure
the whole system is secure.
There's a lot of stuff. For example, I
play game, right. I think
gamification plus finance could be a
very very
vital idea, a very very fun idea to explore.
Maybe we can start to
play with some gamification on
finance on Karura.
Nothing is promised, but
I'm thinking about stuff that coming
out of my head right now.
Maybe there might be a lottery
somewhere. If you mint stablecoin, maybe
you get
an extra interest or something like that.
This is the stuff that we can
definitely explore
on the more vibrant and wilder community.
And also evaluating
what sort of character we want to
accept
for a bankrupt security product like
Acala. You're gonna be very very
solid. You have to prove liquidity,
you have to be very very conservative
because you don't want it to fail.
So for example, if the liquidity is not quite
there yet, but we can explore
a number of
characters or things like that
in the Karura network, as long as like if
it doesn't go wrong.
Well, maybe it's another good idea to
explore as well. You can think about a
lot of like
newly opened and very very
hot coins or tokens being accepted as
collateral.
Maybe. These are some of the general
thoughts I have.
Awesome. On a similar question,
let's switch to Acala now.
How would you describe Acala in three
words?
Well in three words again, let me think
about that.
I think the very
first one should be "secure"
or "safe" or something like that. So the
very first way should give
a sense of security. I think that's
the most important thing if you want to
become the financial Layer.
It has to be secure. The second would be
focused on
something that's about
a word we
can use for
"owning your own bank", like as a sense of
ownership. Right. So maybe a "sense of
ownership", that's it.
It's something secure, it's something
solid, but also you can have a part of
that.
If Acala would be your own bank,
you can actually own
a fraction of that by ourselves.
Secure.
Ownership.
The final word that I would
say
is probably like "long-term".
Because we're here and it would align
with
our value proposition. We think the DeFi
movement is on a very early stage
and essentially I believe that the DeFi is
going to
cover pretty much the whole world's
population, that will be translating on top of
blockchain.
Regardless of the trend that was
defined directly or that's
strengthening with some sort
of financial service, they're
actually using
blockchain as a backend. But,
ultimately, the whole financial sector
will be generating on top of blockchain.
If you want to
build something that's part of
this revolution, we would like to
have Acala as one of the
projects
that will exist not only within the the hype
cycle but also have a long-term plan
of seven to
ten years.
I want to be take part of this history.
The last word I would use is
"long-term" or "committed".
Cool. So, we've gone over
both of our networks. We're
running these in parallel and they'll
continue to be run in parallel and,
just for people's background, Polkadot
and Kusama will be bridged,
so there will be assets flowing between
Polkadot and Kusama, and then of course
Acala and Karura on top of those networks.
Let's move on to kind of more
internal stuff.
As I just mentioned, we're building
these two networks.
We have a rapidly growing team of what I
would consider a lot of just
A players. Everyone's hard worker, smart,
we all work really well together, been on
fire recently.
How do you look at our culture?
How would you describe our culture
internally?
On a similar note, how do you evaluate
new hires? What kind of characteristics
do you look for in
potential new hires? I think
pretty much in the whole team we
have a number of
unique
characteristics. So, one characteristic is
there we are very very engineering
driven. That's very
essential for
pretty much all the blockchain staff
- that you have an
engineer-driven culture. Because
it is on a very early stage of movement,
you need to get your hand dirty, you need
to understand
how every single bit of piece works,
essentially for the whole team.
I think Dan understands pretty much how
the product works inside out
and pretty much everyone that's in the
team understands how the product
works inside out.
It's a very engineer focus or
engineer-driven culture.
With blockchain you can code a
bank and that's essentially what we're
doing: a set of engineers
code a bank out of nowhere. That's the
very first
characteristic. The next characteristic is that
we are a very distributed team and
that's the nature of any
blockchain staff as well.
I'm in New Zealand, San is in
Brazil or
in the US, depending on the time of the year.
We have
Robin, we have our contributor in the
United States, we have contributor in
Shanghai, in Albania,
in New York and will be
growing
in the same way: acquiring new
talents in a distributed way.
There's a number of reasons for
that. One of the reason is that the
blockchain market is still a very niche
market
to acquire the best talents. They are
pretty much
not around, they are not like in the
neighborhood, you can't find them in the
local market!
If you want to find the
best teammates, it's pretty much
unlikely to be your neighbor. So we have
a
distributed team.
We also have this sense of
ownership
and accountability. For a distributed
team to move and
to
work in a very productive way, it
is very essential that every one of us
has a sense of accountability,
has a sense of ownership. That is,
realising that what you are working on
has an effect and dependence on you
peer and team members.
As long
as we communicate clearly,
as long as we deliver and a have sense of
we are building this
product together, we can move in a much
much
smoother and productive way. I think,
ultimately,
the final characteristic, that we have in
the current team, is that
it's essentially and literally flat.
In everyday work,
everyone
understands how their part
is contributing into creating these
products and everyone takes that role.
There's
the culture that you can
talk to everyone directly, talking about
how we can make this product better, how
we can
make this product viable, how we
can launch the product properly.
That's essentially
the way we communicate,
that's the way we work with every
team members. We're lucky that pretty
much all the team members that we bring
on today
are very very accountable, very very
responsible and already very good at
what they are doing.
We like to keep it that way, right.
Thats's the lesson
I mentioned that I had learned:
you want to scale but you also want to
scale
in an effective way. You don't want to
bring
players that might drag down the team
morale
or push down the productivity, because, by
then, it will be
very very hard to correct. Every new
team member that we want to bring on
needs
to share the same value
as what we believe such as the true
nature of decentralization, the
opportunity that we are enabling,
the opportunities that
we can bring
to all the people that are not yet
using blockchain. Second,
the new team member also need to have
this same
values of
accountability, responsibility, as part
of the the protocol and of the
product that you will work on,
that you treat it as your own baby and
deliver it.
With blockchain
it is pretty much walking around the clock.
Maybe one sentence can describe that:
"work hard and play hard", when
it's needed. Maybe you will work hard for a
number of weeks, like
we're facing right now as we think
we're going to launch the Karura
network pretty soon, so everyone is in
battle station mode. But, when you are not
that busy, then maybe
learn something, new explore
protocol or something like that. I
think that's pretty much the culture
of the current team members
that's working on the Acala or on
the other products.
Perfect. You kind of touched on
this a little bit, but,
in these times when we're working so
much and
we've got all everything going on, what
would you say
gets you out of bed in the
morning? What it
inspires you to do what you do every day
and keeps you motivated?
About what really keeps me
motivated right now,
I don't know who said
that
but I read the Twitter
some time ago saying:
"hey,
the crypto market is doing great that's
all right but,
the question is that, if
everyone's better off with the crypto
going up,
then who is going to build the crypto?
Who is going to build the products? Who's
continuing to
stay motivated
and deliver products to make this
crypto
a reality for
our future?"
I think what keeps me motivated
it's not
about
hey Bitcoin is going up few thousand
dollars or something like that. It's more
like every
day every morning I wake up and I think
about how to be able to create
a product / a protocol that I have a part in
making but it's not totally owned by me.
It's owned by thousands of people.
It has like millions of users.
Their life
is better because I
created this product.
They're able to exchange faster, they're
able to have higher interest rate in
their bank account.
The millions of users,
or token holders or traders or
whatever committee members,
they are better off because of what I
am creating and I am part of this
movement. That's what made me
stay motivated.
In our office, we
have a
screen, showing all the latest metrics of
the product that we're building -
because we haven't gone live yet.
The metrics that are being shown are
basically how the testnet
is getting hit,
what's the server load, what's
our community
size, which is growing every day.
Those numbers actually make me
stay motivated. I would like to see that,
once we go live,
the number of um transactions they're
able to facilitate,
the number of users, the number of
financial application,
traders that we are able to serve,
grow and that's what keeps me going every
day.
Great. Let's wrap up with one
more question.
If you were to think forward in
terms of how you're mentally preparing
for the next, maybe three to five years,
in terms of where you see
our product going but also DeFi and
blockchain,
how would you describe that future
of
what DeFi might look like?
I think the DeFi movement or
actually I would call it the
the whole financial sector
on blockchain movement, it's very very
early at this stage. If you
compare the existing DeFi market
to the conventional financial
market,
it's peanuts. Well ultimately I do
believe that
the current blockchain is going to
be the backbone of
everything finance-related in the future.
We don't know how it's going to happen.
We don't know when,
how long it will take
for us to get to that stage.
I also believe that
during this movement it's not going to
be like a 100% percent that everyone
will be making transaction directly
on the blockchain. It is also not 100%
that the blockchain is just used as
a server, being set up by a
few financial institutions as well.
I believe in a
in a mix, in a fusion of both.
Someone like me or some engineer, some
new younger generations, they might
prefer to transact directly
with the blockchain and that's possible,
that's viable.
And someone like my mom or
someone that's not that nerdy,
they might want to to choose to get the
benefit of DeFi
or get a benefit for blockchain, but they
will translate through some sort of
crypto finance service provider
or new generation type of bank. I
think this is a movement that will take
take at least
five years, ten years
to move. But again, this is purely a
software movement, so
it might happen sooner than we expected.
We just need to make sure that we are
prepared for that.
Lastly, I would just say that
this is something that's
very very early but the potential that
we are able to achieve,
the potential we're able to bring for
the whole population is limitless.
Think about all the unbanked people in
the world, they are
possibly switch to being able, by using DeFi, to
finally access
financial instruments. For
people that already have access to the
conventional finance sector,
they might be better off with using
transact
with blockchain directly, they might have
interest rates, they might have better
freedom
in what they are doing.
I'm fully committed to this sector
and I will say that maybe
we will be laser focused for the next
six months/ next one year on Acala,
an that is the short term for the
improvement of product and the movement, but in
long-term, we'll all be thinking that we
will be keep improving,
we'll be keep innovating and that's how
we stay relevant in this industry
until at least half of the world
population is connecting to blockchain.
And that will probably take five years,
10 years, but we are committed to do that!
Great. Well I think that's about it. I
learned a lot and appreciate the time.
Let's get back to work.
Well, yeah, let's get back to launch
Karura.
yeah thanks thank you then.