awesome uh yeah so uh good morning
everyone uh this is betty uh co-founder
of akala
and we also have brian a co-founder and
cto of uh
akala here today with us um and
he's actually prepared a full rail cross
uh d5 demo for you
so i'll just be very shocked and very
brief on my introduction
um i guess before diving in um because a
color has been around for a while last
year we run
again the same poker d5 demo we've
already run
a full suite of d5 applications
and then it's great to see this year
everyone you know has got their
application up and running and it seems
you know we're very close to
where the vision is going to be and it's
it's worth sharing you know what we
think
the future might look like um i think
we've got you know bitcoin
uh which is the calculator error that's
one thing and then ethereum
is perhaps the mainframe uh error of
blockchain
and now i think we are entering the
so-called cloud computing
um where everything as a service um
that's where
we're heading i think um so we kind of
believe that you know future will be
multi-chain and then a specialization
uh it's gonna trump uh generalization so
you're gonna
your chain is gonna specialize in a
specific domain and do
uh certain things really well and solve
some problems very well
um and also change shouldn't be rigid it
should be upgradable
so that's that's what we think it's
going to happen and also
where we put our words out and build our
application
so this is the akala stack if you
uh haven't seen this one yet so a color
is still you know a full-fledged
blockchain
but it's ledger and trust is provided by
polka dot so this is what uh
you know i uh originally you know term
as
uh network security or trust as a
service
um and also in the middle of it as
oakare's default offerings
uh they're offered you know a service
like customizable modules right
um so for example you know we've got
this multicollato
uh stablecoin uh backed by dot liquid
dot and then you will also see you know
bitcoin like poker btc
can be used as collateral as well um and
then we
our liquidation is automatic and use a
hybrid of
emm decks um and auctions
um and um and then another thing that i
think brian will actually demo you today
is liquid staking so this is a
a tokenized uh staked dot uh or l dot
uh so it's a bit like die and see that
right allows you to earn staking
rewards while youth farming in d5
chestlessly
and you can also say you know evm is a
module on on our you know
service modules so we're fully evm
compatible
you can build smart contracts or any
type of dap on top of a color
so basically you know akala offers d5
as a service and then
yeah so and as we're demoing today is
probably the beginning of
you will see composable services so that
means
depths are composable with each other
that's a given
um but also smart contracts and depths
from other blockchains will be
composable uh with akala
and anyone you know who's be able to do
crushing
transactions together um so hopefully
you uh you'll get a taste of it today
and uh that's my introduction i'll hand
over to brian
now yeah sexpedit um so let me share my
screen
cool so you should be able to see my
screen now um yeah so
this is our um test net this is not
the mandana test that we're running on
yes so this is what especially make
the powertrain test next so it's
currently uh connecting to our version
of rococo so you can see
um we have some power change connecting
to it and
just um yeah so um so we can show some
questions
demoing so let's get started um so first
thing
you probably want to do is what you want
you should have already some
ss there will be dots or bitcoin uh or
maybe ethereum
so for in this case then you if you have
already a bitcoin you can use uh program
vdc
to um are using bitcoin to mean coca btc
and then using
question transfer to transfer program dc
into
a color so obviously some question
transfer fee will be applied
and then once you've got some program
pdc
there's a few things you can do with it
so one thing of course you can do is
sell it but this
well probably not the best idea so
actually it does make some money without
selling them
so that's where the stable coin protocol
comes handy
so we can start a new along
so using the btc as the devoted
so let's say i can deposit my 0.2
program dc i will be able to borrow
up to in this case 7000
so i can borrow all of it
and then you will see my liquidation
price is
this number and my current ratio is 120
so this is um slightly on a dangerous
size so
maybe it's a good idea to borrow
slightly less so i can pretty
comfortable
um it's unlikely bitcoin price will drop
to 30 000
hopefully um yeah so this the
next second just review there will be
some interest rate charge on the
borrowed
amount that's my probatory issue
so this i can make a transition
yeah so this will um make three thousand
uh sorry five thousand akala usd
uh from the poker pc i have deposited
so now i have some money what can i do
with it
uh we have the swap so there's a dex
which you can use to use the usd to buy
other assets so you'll be able to buy
also question access as well um
including project pdc and
dot cell run btc and few other assets in
the future
so in this case maybe i want to buy some
dots which is obviously a good
idea so i can spend
1000 asd which will buy this amount of
dots
so once that's confirmed when you have
thoughts
if you're not going to use it
immediately it's probably a good idea to
stake them so you're earning the staking
rewards
which is have a reasonably good return
so you can go to a poker network to do
the staking or
another way is using a liquid stating
protocol to do a sticking which is
much more easier so this is the express
ui so you just enter the amount of dots
you would like to stake and
click save button and that's
all you need to do to stake dot and
the protocol are decentralized and
protocol will handle all the data
selections domination nominations etc
but of course you can also vote for your
favorite validators if you want to with
your l dots
so now i've changed all my dots to
eldors and
then you will be able to later and
better vote for the metadata if you want
to
um we are still uh working on the ui for
this
area so this is the advanced screen
so um you can see the uh history
um you can if you want to redeem you can
you can so you can uh just wait for the
whole unbounding period which will be
um seven days okay summer 28 days on
pokeball
and then just wait and which we won't
charge
you an extra redeeming fee but if you
really need the money right now
and up to the certain amounts then you
will be able to redeem them
immediately but we'll be charging you
some
of the redeeming fee because uh you're
skipping the unbounded period
but if you really need money uh need the
dots right now this will be
handy so now you have the outdoors and
the
you the staking rewards
and how could you and like boots like
increase the um
the rates from the thoughts so another
way to do that
is good for example you can do is
add liquidity to our decks so that is
basically lost certain amount of
asd and lot your assets
and then you will be supplying the
liquidity to our decks
and which will um
if people when people make trades you'll
earn additional
fees as rewards we also have the
liquidity
incentive program so you also at the
same time
in addition to the fees you any
additional usd
um as rewards as well
so this is adding the liquidity to
the decks and once and
then at later stage if you want to you
can also redeem the liquidity
reading a token back later
yes so the next thing i want to show you
just a
little quick this is still again working
progress and we're still finalizing all
the details and
finalizing the ui but we have the
governance feature so it will be
somewhat similar to pogba
and kusama but will be slightly more
complicated
we have the hometown council which will
be one the one main engine for the
stable point protocol
for the hallmark also so i managed for
the
liquid staking vertical so as the elder
holders
you'll be able to participate the
homework council
by using your elder to vote for um
as the sa holder account holder you will
be person able to participate the
general counsel and the hong kong
council governors
so yes so those are still working for
ways so it's
not empty but hopefully a later stage
will have much more thing
in our test net to shoot
so now um you have already um
having the thoughts making your profiles
while you sleep
what can you do with um what else can i
do
so another thing you can do is um you as
i
show you i generally a bunch of aoc from
my poker pdc and then next thing if i
want to be
increase my profit by taking some more
risks i can transfer my
akala usd to the laminar network
so let's just transfer to some account
so let's say how to transfer 2000 a
little bit
so let's do a question transfer
from akala to the laminar so you can see
the method is x token transfer to
protein
so this will transfer the money to the
laminar technique
so this will be making a question
transfer and this
will take a slightly bit more time so
while this is
transferring i'm going to quickly show
you uh
on the laminar side so assuming the
transfer already
says that i already got some asd and
then i will be able to
like do a swipe so this will um the
laminar will
allow you to do trading with sensitive
assets so
there will be like for example foreign
exchange or like others like gold and
oil etc
so let's say i want to buy some euro
maybe because
well i'm going to travel to europe
sometime
europe sometimes so maybe i'll have some
euro
so so i can swipe
some aosd to the laminar euro
and i also i also can do some margin
trading so i can for example
i leveraged trade bitcoin or level trade
ethereum or just do
some my forex trading
so i can deposit the money into the
the margin pool um
and then i can just say i can choose up
to 20
times leverage in this case so
to to do a margin trading
yeah so let's open the position i'll
start getting the 20 plus exposure on
the usbjp trading video
this so with the question transfer
should already success so
um let's check the events so you can see
um yep so we have the question token
transferred
here so you can see this is sending
uh uh for example relay message so from
a paragraph to passion
uh message uh relates through the uh
religion which is the roku
of home fork of the roku in this case so
on the laminar side you can see
uh we have a deposit event
should be this one so uh so 2000 aod is
deposited into this account
so this is basically um so the industry
is basically
the equestrian aoc transfer between
color and the lamina
yeah so um that's all of the
demo i'm going to show you so um just
last but not least
um we are also working on
the xcm functional token implementation
so this will allow everything including
other powertrains to
more easily just compose compostable
with each other
so i've like well we have created open
runner module library and created some
of the question
token transfer asset which is kind of
used by quite a few
project things including platinum phalla
and
a few others and so to implement the
question transfer so i'm also creating
some implementation guides and
some implementation plans um to in the
future to
further help everyone um to implement
the question
asset transfer so this will allow
everyone
to be able to compose with each other
more easily
just by integrating our library
so that's all i have for you today