Witam wszystkich
Jestem Dan Reeser, dołączyłem
tutaj wraz z Ruitao Su
Zamierzamy przedstawić całkiem
sporo informacji
o Naszej sieci nazwanej KARURA, którą
budujemy na kusama, możesz też
znać
Nas jako zespół ACALA. My również
przygotowujemy się do
uruchomienia sieci ACALA na polkadot, ale to
nastąpi później, po uruchomieniu KARURA, więc dzisiaj
poświęcimy trochę czasu
na omówienie tego. Pozwól mi zacząć
udostępniać mój ekran
Ja omówię trochę
plan dla nas
a potem możemy iść naprzód i zacząć
więc
dzisiaj mamy kilka
rzeczy
ogólnie na paru slajdach omówię co to jest karua
tak by dać Tobie
pogląd na to
czym są produkty, które
budujemy i to doprowadzi Nas do Ruitao Su
który przedstawi
demonstracje każdego z tych produktów
przede wszystkim
On zacznie od portfela, a potem
omówimy kUSD, który jest
dolarem Karury - stablecoin`em
potem omówimy AMM DEX Karury
a na końcu
omówimy staking płynnego KSM
więc powinno to wyglądać naprawdę fajnie, tak jak
będzie to wyglądać w rzeczywistości, tak aby
zapoznać Was z tym i pokazać
działający produkt
a następnie co zrobimy, to Robin jest tutaj na
czacie, do którego
na końcu wkleimy link, żebyście mogli
w rzeczywistości użyć tych
aplikacji w sieci testowej
by być gotowym na to, co będzie
już niedługo działać w sieci kusama
więc czy chcesz na początku
przedstawić siebie, a następnie ja zrobię
to samo, po czym możemy zacząć
o tak, dziękuje Dan. Witam wszystkich
Jestem Ruitao Su współzałożyciel
zespołu Acala, oczywiście również
pracuje w Karura
Pracuję nad tematem blockchain
od ponad siedmiu lat i mogę powiedzieć
że zaczeliśmy budować sieć Acala
dwa lata temu
Jesteśmy jednymi z pierwszych
programistów Substrate, sam jestem inżynierem
.
Ja jestem tu dzisiaj, bo uwielbiam pisać kod i
jest tego dosyć dużo w moim doświadczeniu
naprawdę lubię budować
najnowocześniejsze rzeczy i jestem bardzo podekscytowany, że
po prawie dwóch latach tworzenia
jesteśmy naprawdę blisko uruchomienia
w sieci Kusama
Super. Dziękuje Ci Ruitao. Ja jestem Dan
Reecer
pracuje jako wiceprezes ds. rozwoju w Acala
i Karura
Jestem w zespole trochę ponad
już kilka miesięcy. A wcześniej
pracowałem
w niepełnym wymiarze godzin w Acala przez około
sześć miesięcy przed przystąpieniem do pracy w pełnym wymiarze godzin
przed przybyciem do Acala spędziłem trochę
czasu pracując w fundacji Web3
pracując nad polkadot i kusama, więc to
to był naturalny rozwój przechodząc
z poziomu warstwy podstawowej do
warstwy jeden poziom wyżej do poziomu parachain i
przygotowywać się do
tego całego szaleństwa i
podekscytowania, które niedługo przyjdzie ze wszystkimi
tymi uruchomieniami
więc pierwsze uruchomienie tego
nad czym
pracujemy, wspomniałem jest to karura
Myślę, że zanim przejdziemy do
szczegółów dotyczących
Karua i Acala. Zawsze
pomocnym jest, aby zawsze zacząć
na najwyższym poziomie. Więc to co
budujemy
jest jednym z tych parachain`ów, takich
trochę jak
te tutaj szare kwadraty, to są parachain`y
albo indywidualne blockchain`y, które
są dostosowane do konkretnego celu
a to, co pokazuje ta grafika, jest czymś w rodzaju
w przyszłości gdzie
będziemy mieli sto lub więcej
parachain`ów podłączonych do Kusamy
i 100 lub więcej parachain`ów podłączonych do
Polkadot
wszystko w jednym. Rodzaj połączonego ekosystemu
ponieważ, jak możesz tutaj zobaczyć
na środku będzie zbudowany
pomost pomiędzy polkadot i kusama, jednak
w tym momencie
te dwa rodzaje wielołańcuchowych sieci
są właściwie
gołe, tam nie ma parachain`ów
połączony z którymkolwiek z nich, ale to
jest tylko początek
i naszym celem w Acala i Karua jest
zostać pierwszym parachain`em w
publicznym slot`cie Kusamy
z Karurą, anastępnie zostać pierwszym
parachain`em na polkadot z Acala
więc z tym jako tłem
tak jak wspomnieliśmy, zamierzamy
rozmawiaj dziś o Karurze, która
jest tym, co rzeczywiście widzimy
staje się rodzajem centrum DeFi
w ekosystemie Kusama, jak również|
dostarcza wiele różnych produktów
finansowych do
wszystkich innych parachain`ów i
aplikacje, które zostaną uruchomione
w ekosystemie Kusama
in my opinion there's no better way to
startu dla ekosystemu Kusama, niż
uruchomienie Karura
najpierw z powodów, które chcemy Tobie
wyjaśnić, i to nie są tylko
produkty, które Acala i Kurura będą
mogły używać, w rzeczywistości to jest to
co nazywamy prymitywami, to jest
rodzaj nowej koncepcji, ale jest to wbudowane
do samego blockchain`a
co oznacza, że ​​inne zespoły mogą
faktycznie przyjść do ekosystemu i
wykorzystać to, co zbudował nasz zespół
na przykład dolar Karury jest
stablecoin`em, który będzie nie tylko używany
w naszych aplikacjach, ale może być używany
przez każdego
w ekosystemie Kusama, więc nie ma lepszego sposobu
aby uruchomić ten ekosystem
niż zbudować tego rodzaju
Najpierw ważny fundament
z Karuą, a następnie zezwolić
innym zespołom na tworzenie z wykorzystaniem tego
dostarczamy do
ekosystemu, to co tu widzisz na
ekranie jest
to interfejs użytkownika, właściwie jest to rodzaj
warstwy aplikacji, którą nasz zespół
zbudował
więc mamy te produkty, które są
wbudowane w sam blockchain, ale nasz
zespół również zbudował na własnej sieci
cały szereg aplikacji
które widzisz tutaj i to jest to
Ruitao dziś zademonstruje
aby dokładniej wyjaśnić, o czym wspomniałem
że Acala jest platformą
dla aplikacji, a następnie również
warstwą aplikacji
jeśli widzisz ten schemat tutaj
to jest rodzaj działania z
warstwy podstawowej Kusamy
To, co jest pokazane to Kusama, to jest
oczywiście ta wielołańcuchowa platforma, którą
pokazałem i dla której staramy się uzyskać
slot w Kusamie
i to pozwala nam podłączyć się
do tego
jakby pomarańczowego pudełka, którym jest Karura
i to jest nasz blockchain to jest
warstwa pierwsza blockchain, równoważna z
czymś takim jak ethereum dzisiaj
W Karurze jest wiele
podstaw lub zbudowanych produktów finansowych
z których możemy korzystać
w aplikacjach na tym, tak więc
możesz zobaczyć stablecoin, o którym wspomniałem
staking płynnego KSM, który pozwalaja ci
stakować KSM i właściwie uzyskać możliwość
wykorzystania w DeFi
zamiast tylko stakować swój KSM, i
być w pewnym rodzaju zablokowanym i
nie
użytecznym. Kolejnym rodzajem są nasze DEX`y
które Ruitao zademonstruje tutaj wkrótce i
następnie
niektórzy z Was, zawsze rozmawiają o tym
jak blockchain można dostosować z
Substrate i budować
dla konkretnych zastosowań i oto co
rozumiemy przez sformuowanie
przynieś swój własny gaz, to jest to funkcja, którą
dziś również zademonstruujemy
Jest to funkcja, którą
dostosowaliśmy specjalnie dla Naszych sieci
Karura i Acala, ponieważ próbujemy
wyspecjalizować je w DeFi
i co Ci pozwoli, jeśli kiedykolwiek
korzystałeś z DeFi i ethereum
wiesz, że nie możesz zrobić żadnej
transakcje bez posiadania
eth i jeśli jesteś nowym użytkownikiem ethereum
najpierw musisz się nauczyć, czym jest eth
musisz je zdobyć
to trudny proces, jednak z funkcją przynieś
swój własny gaz z Karura i Acala to
pozwoli ludziom wziąć
każdy token i natychmiast zapłać
wstępną opłatę transakcyjną tym tokenem
więc na przykład ktoś wnosi bitcoin`y
do
Karura i ma możliwość wziąć
bitcoin poprzez
po prostu zrobić wrap i używać go na Kusama
w Karurze, a następne
być w stanie zapłacić ich transakcję, może to być
zamiana, czy przesłanie tokenów, ale opłata
za to fee
w BTC zamiast wychodzić
i szukać
tokenów KAR, który jest rodzajem tokena
użyteczności w Karurze
i na koniec Acala EVM jest czymś w rodzaju
następnego wyspecjalizowanego
środowiska ethereum, które zbudowaliśmy
konkretnie dla Karury
i Acali, więc można stwierdzić, że to jest
warstwa pierwsza. Tutaj w środku to jest
blockchain
sam w sobie, i na tym nasz zespół
już zbudował całą
aplikację która wykorzystuje te wszystkie
rzeczy, o których właśnie wspomniałem, więc
Ruitao, to o czym on dziś będzie mówił
jest naszym całym pakietem
aplikacji, które zbudowano na
naszym blockchain`ie, miejcie to na
uwadze, że tam jest także
jest to otwarta platforma, oczywiście, więc
to nie będzie tylko Karura
tworzyła aplikacje, to będą również
inne zespoły przychodzące i budujące w tym
otwartym środowisku, które
stworzyliśmy
Nie muszę tego omawiać, ponieważ
po prostu omówiłem to wszystko
i tutaj jest tylko spojrzenie
ogólne na Karurę, tak więc
to są
wszystkie produkty, które zbudowaliśmy
jest tam zbudowanych kilka mostów
w ekosystemie właśnie teraz, w szczególności
dla lub przede wszystkim, dla
bitcoin`a i ethereum, więc już niedługo
po uruchomieniu zobaczymy walor
ethereum
którymi będzie można handlować i będące w pewnym sensie użyteczne
w naszych DEX`ach i w
innych produktach
tak więc, jak jest w zasadzie Karura w
w skrócie. Bardzo podobna do Acala
ale po prostu pozostaniemy przy Karurze
today's
prezentacji.
Myślę, że jest to ostatni slajd
wiele ludzi pyta
dlaczego zdecydowaliśmy się zbudować
Karura na Kusamie poza Acalą na
polkadot
a odpowiedź na to pytanie brzmi następująco
my to robimy
w oparciu o zapotrzebowanie użytkowników, aby środowisko
Kusamy i Polkadot
chociaż w pewnym stopniu się pokrywają
bardzo wyraźnie różnie się też od siebie różnią
Te sieci mają
dwie różne społeczności posiadaczy
tokenów z różnymi potrzebami DeFi
więc budujemy Karurę, aby to zaspokoić
potrzeby DeFi Kusamy, jak również będziemy
budowali Acalę, aby zaspokoić potrzeby na DeFi
Polkadot
Jednak Kusama, jeśli znasz podstawy
projektu Kusama, w znaczeniu, że to być miejsce
do zabawy, eksperymentowania i poniekąd
uruchomienia
produktów przed przeniesieniem do Polkadot, jednak
już po intensywnych testach w sieci testowej
więc kusama jest
absolutnie nie nie jest to sieć testowa
.
sieć testowa nazywa się rokoko i westend
rzeczy są testowane na testnecie, a następnie są przenoszone
do Kusama, a potem do Polkadot
to, co budujemy, jest w pewnym rodzaju
będzie podążać podobną ścieżką
nasza sieć testowa nazywa się Mandala, więc
sieć testowa jest tam gdzie
nowe produkty będą budowane i
testowane i dopracowane, i
miejmy nadzieję, że dopracowane do perfekcji, zanim
zostaną przeniesione do Karury
wtedy Karura jest miejscem, gdzie możemy naprawdę
eksperymentować w uruchomionym rzeczywistym środowisku
z realną wartością w rzeczywistej
prosperującej sieci
a następnie, jeśli zdecydujemy, że dany produkt
który społeczność Kusama
polubiła, otrzymaliśmy dobre opinie będziemy mogli
ulepszyć produkt, a następnie przenieść go
później
do Acala
a na koniec luźne
spójrzenie na liczby, nie muszę dokładnie
omawiać tego wszystkiego
właśnie wczoraj dodaliśmy wielkość naszej
społeczności, i właśnie
przekroczyliśmy 200 000. Jesteśmy w okolicach 205 000
w kanałach Acala i Karura
rozrastamy się
całkiem szalonej prędkości, teraz, i
jesteśmy bardzo blisko
przeprowadzenia procesu pożyczek publicznych 'crodloan' oraz
aukcji na parachain`y, o którym
mówiliśmy wcześniej i jest jeszcze
kilka filmów na naszym kanale
YouTube
Nie krępuj się sprawdzać, bo dzisiaj nie będziemy wchodzić
w szczegóły dotyczące tego procesu
więc z mojej strony to wszystko, a teraz
przejdziemy do
demonstracji i tego co będziemy robić w
sensie
tego w jaki sposób Ruitao
omówi
jeden z produktów, a następnie zrobimy
krótką pauzę i pozwólimy Wam zadawać pytania i będziemy
Proszę o konkretne pytania
na temat
demonstracji, która właśnie się odbyła
Na przykład jeżeli będzie to o
pożyczaniu aUSD, po prostu zachowaj
to pytani do tego momentu
odpowiemy na kilka pytań, a następnie On
przejdzie do następnej demonstracji, znowu zrobimy
krótkie Q&A
a następnie zrobimy ostatnią demonstrację i zrobimy kolejne
Q&A i w zakończymy
pewnego rodzaju otwartą sesją pytań
Wiem, że macie dużo
pytań, więc
śmiało, zadawajcie pytania
tutaj
Wspaniale. Dziękuje Dan za niesamowite
wprowadzenie, więc zacznę udostępniać ekran
aby upewnić się, że możesz zobaczyć
mój ekran. Każdy może zobaczyć mój ekran
Tak, mamy to, wspaniale, więc to jest
widok strony front-end dla Karura, czy do
mandala, która jest siecią testową, ale
to będzie widok strony
Karura
to jest tak, jak mówi zespół
jest to wyspecjalizowany blockchain
z zestawem wbudowanych funkcji i tym
oto widokiem strony do interakcji
jako konsument, jako trader do interakcji
z tą
wyspecjalizowaną siecią i oczywiście
najważniejszą funkcją jest
tryb ciemny, który
pasuje do ustalonego przez zepół Acala
schematu kolorów. Wygląda to niesamowicie
tak to będzie wyglądać
jako skórka domyślna
kiedy
uruchamiamy
sieć Karura i na pierwszej stronie
którą mam zamiar pokazać
jest strona portfela, to jest miejsce, w którym Ty
zarządzaj wszystkimi swoimi aktywami
w ramach parachain`a Karura oraz możesz
zobaczyć
że to
się zmieni na KAR token
masz swój token KSM i masz swoje
tokeny kUSD
możesz je swobodnie przesłać do innych
portfeli przez interakcję z tym
widokiem strony aplikacji
możesz zarządzać swoimi aktywami, jak
jeden ze
zgromadzonych Twoich aktywów, masz dostęp
aby przesłać wartość
albo uzyskać dostęp do takich rzeczy jak minting btc
minting polkaBTC, albo przesłać środki do
innego parachain`a. Na przykład jeżeli chcesz
przesłać
aktywa z Acala do na przykład
hydra Dex
mogę tutaj wybrać i zrobić wymianę
przelew, więc to
wygląda prawie tak, jak bardzo przyjazny
użytkownikowi portfel
w mojej opinii masz lepszy dostęp
niż
używanie polkadot.js, aby
mieć interakcje z
blockchain`em, więc to jest to, o co
chciałem zapytać
zanim przez to przejdziemy, po prostu zamierzam
zadawać pytania, o których myślę
że odbiorcy mogą się
zastanawiać, więc to co tutaj pokazujez
jest to
portfel, który może być używany podobnie jak
ludzie teraz korzystają z polkadot.js, czy nawet
niektóre z portfeli mobilnych, jednak
kiedy ludzie połączą się, to, to aby
zobaczyli te numery, tutaj
poprawnie, powinni iść do
rozszerzenia przeglądarki polkadot.js
i połączyć swoje konta
polkadot.js z tym portfelem i
pokazałyby się
ich salda w czasie rzeczywistym w tym portfelu
jest to
zdecydowanie i rozszerzenie polkadot.js
jest bardzo podobne do
metamaska, taki odpowiednik metamask`a na polkadot
możesz zarządzać wieloma kontami w
sekcji portfela, więc mogę zmienić
na inne konto demo tutaj
możesz tutaj zobaczyć wszystkie rzeczy, odświeżam
na bieżąco, i mogę zmienić z powrotem na moje oryginalne
konto demo
możesz również zobaczyć historię swoich
transakcji
więc jest to bardzo przyjazny dla użytkownika, bardzo
skoncentrowany na konsumencie
to twój pojedynczy przystanek do
dostępu do Twoich zasobów
na Karura
Tak, więc, Dan czy
są jakieś pytania, które chciałbyś zadać?
hmm
w sprawie tego interfejsu portfela
czy powinniśmy kontynuować pracę i
przejść do
następnej sekcji, którą jest branie pożyczki
pożyczanie
stablecoin`ów
zobaczmy
może być trudne aby posortować
przez to
pudełko. W porządku, więc jeśli macie jakieś
specyficzne pytania do którejś z tych
demonstracji. Będe obserwował
czat, więc
ktoś pyta, który portfel
został do tego wybrany
portfel KSM
cóż, jest to tak jak
Jeżeli używasz rozszerzenia polkadot.js
to jest
zasadniczo twój dostęp do obu sieci: Kusama
i Polkadot
do Karura i Acala, każdy
tematyczny blockchain, będzie
obsługiwany przez polkadot.js
Więc pomyśl o tym, jak
wielofunkcyjna wersja metamask`a
Łączysz sie z Karura i masz dostęp do swoich
zasobów na Karura, używając tego samego
rozszerzenia polkadot.js
tak, więc w zasadzie łączysz jedno
konto z polkadot.js, a następnie
to pokazuje każdy portfel, który jest
połączony z tym
kontem, tak, tak
i oczywiście w polkadot.js masz
możliwość zarządzania, tak jak
chciałbyś tego użyć na Acala
Chciałbym użyć tego
konkretnego adresu portfela
może tylko na Relay Chain na Kusama. Albo
możesz powiedzieć, że chcesz użyć
ten
portfel we wszystkich dostępnych parachain`ach
i na Relay Chain`ach, więc
to zależy od użytkownika
który wybiera, gdzie dany
portfel będzie dostępny
Jeżeli zrobisz go dostępnym
dla Karura, to pojawi się tutaj i masz
możliwość zarządzania
Widzę, że ta osoba
nazywająca się Pi, właśnie zapytała
o
pojawiającą się tu nazwę, kiedy Acala zostanie
uruchomiona
będzie tam tylko Acala i będzie mieć
logo Acala
kiedy Karura zostanie uruchomiona, to będzie miało
logo Karura na górze po lewej stronie
w ten sposób zawsze to będzie pokazywać
że to jest tylko sieć testowa, więc Mandala jest siecią testową
dla Acala
Więc będzie to
tylko nazwa
sieci, jak będą uruchomione
również chciałbym podać tutaj trochę wskazówek
więc
Karura jest siecią siostrzaną Acali
więc kiedy one
powstają, są prawie
identyczne, jednak gdy zostaną uruchomione
kiedy nastąpi geneza, obie
sieci obiorą różne ścieżki, tak więc
możesz zobaczyć aktywa, które
będą dostępne tylko na Karura, ponieważ
będą one
tylko dostępne w sieci Kusama, albo możesz
znaleźć funkcje, które będą dostępne tylko na
Karura
ponieważ będzie to taki dziki kuzyn
polkadot i będziesz widział podobne
rzeczy dziejące się głównie na Karura
czy głównie na Acala, więc można
generalizować, że są one tym samym
ale mogą przekształcić się we własny
odmienny
zestaw funkcji
Przejdźmy do następnej
demonstracji
Mamy Kate
ktoś jeszcze, oboje byli
zainteresowani
w zaciąganiu pożyczek na platformie, więc
przejdźmy do tego
Tak, nie ma problemu. To jest jeden z
powodów dlaczego myślimy, że Karura jest tak
użyteczna
kiedy zostanie parachain`em, możesz
odblokować użyteczność
Twoich tokenów KSM i zacząć
brać pożyczki w zastaw za Twoje
tokeny KSM, więc to jest
Interfejs zaciągania kredytów, który możesz zobaczyć
przegląd Twoich aktualnych pozycji
Możesz zobaczyć
że posiadam już pożyczkę
pozycję na renBTC
Pożyczyłem około 3 tysiące dolarów
w zastaw za 0.1 renBTC
jest to trochę ryzykowne
To jest to, na co pozwala system
Możesz właściwie utwożyć pożyczkę używając
dowolnego rodzaju aktywa, które będą
dostępne i w procesie zarządzania
dozwolone do użycia
w tym konkretnym interfejsie, tutaj, ja
mam DOT
LDOT, który będzie zastawem
Będzie to z pewnością takie jak
KSM
LKSM i bitcoins, więc to co
zamierzam
tutaj zademonstrować, jest pożyczenie
więcej
w zastaw za moje 0.1 ramBTC
więc możesz zobaczyć, że bieżąca dla Bitcoina
wycena jest
mniej więcej tą wartością. Wciąż jestem dość bezpieczny
pożyczam trochę więcej
w zastaw za to 0.1 ramBTC, więc
klikam wygeneruj więcej
Zamierzam nacisnąć tutaj
10 dolarów więcej
potwierdź
i to właśnie tu pojawia się podpis
wpiszę moje
hasło i podpiszę transakcję
BOOM. Mam 10 dolarów więcej, które mogę
wydać i to jest przykład jak szybko to działa
i jak wygląda sieć projektu
wszystko się dzieje na bieżąco
właściwie możesz to zobaczyć na
skanerze bloków
dostarczonego przez SUBSCAN
więc jest to niesamowite. Prawda? to jest
o wiele bardziej
responsywne i o wiele bardziej przyjazne
użytkownikowi
mogę to również powtórzyć i zwrócić
pozycję, którą ustawiłem, jeżeli myślę, że
zmniejszę trochę ryzyko
tutaj mogę zapłacić około 100 aUSD
to tak jak zmniejszenie obliczeń mojej
proporcji
i wszelkie aktywa, które będą dostępne
w procesie zarządzania, mogą być
użyte jako zastaw
różne aktywa będą miały różne
parametry ryzyka, więc na przykładzie bitcoina
różne parametry ryzyka mogą być dla
średniej wartości minimalnego zabezpieczenia, wskaźnika kredytu,
wskaźnika likwidacji, opłaty likwidacyjnej
DOT, LDOT, KSM, LKSM, one wszystkie mogą mieć
różne
wskaźniki, one będą zarządzane w
przez proces zarządzania
tak, tak to zasadniczo wygląda, jak bierzesz kredyt
w zastaw
za krypto w Karura
być może możemy zrobić jedną rzecz, ta
koncepcja
zabezpieczeń i zaciągania pożyczek jest
prawdopodobnie nowa dla wielu ludzi, których znam
to było nowe dla mnie
w jednym momencie i właściwie chciałbym
uczynić to w miarę możliwości najprostszym
Myślę, że wielu z nas jest świadomych
że, tak jak pożyczki na dom
działają, gdzie zazwyczaj musisz wpłacić
jakieś 10 czy 20 procent
tej gotówki, którą pożyczasz
dokonujesz wkładu własnego
aby uzyskać pełną
pożyczkę na cokolwiek na co pożyczasz, czy na
dom
ale w sposób w jaki to działa w kryptowalutach
My właściwie, Ty właściwie więcej
zabezpieczasz, niż
pożyczasz. Więc, to jest powód dlaczego te wskaźniki
zabezpieczenia przekraczają
100 procent. To co robisz, to jest
to co tak naprawdę oznacza zabezpieczenie
to jest tak,  że faktycznie bierzesz bitcoiny
coś takiego jak bitcoiny
nie musisz tego sprzedawać, ale możesz
wyjąć
aUSD, "stablecoin" za pomocą Twojego Bitcoina
nadal nie jest sprzedana, a potem możesz
wziąć aUSD
i albo możesz to wysłać do ludzi
możesz dokonać płatności
moższ zapewnić płynność w obrębie naszego
DEX`a, ale
to jest zasadniczo to, co ten wskaźnik zabezpieczenia
znaczy. Nie wiem Ruitao, czy Ty
masz coś więcej do
dodania. Tak, zasadniczo to daje Ci
większą użyteczność aktywów które możesz
trzymać
których możesz nie chcieć sprzedać, albo
w najbliższym czasie
dla przykładu, KSM, czy
LKSM są dla Ciebie doskonałą możliwością
dającą większą użyteczność
dla posiadanych przez Ciebie KSM, możesz
iść long, albo short
oznacza to, że opcja jest w twoich
rękach aby zadecydować, jak zamierzasz użyć
ten kolektor
do handlu i poruszać się z rynkiem
i Broderick zapytał o
odsetki są płacone w momencie
kiedy wychodzisz z
tych pożyczek i w taki sposób to właściwie działa
więc, główne oprocentowanie jest tym co
nazywamy opłatą stabilizującą "stabilization fee"
Jeżeli bieżesz pożyczkę na dłuższy czas
z pewnością pojawią się jakieś odsetki
i to są również odsetki używane podczas
zarządzaniem podażą i popytem
dla stablecoin`ów, jak również
sposób utrzymania tej stablecoiny
będzie
zapakowane do dolara pod względem wartości oraz
wzrost
wszystkich opłat stabilizacyjnych będzie
zarządzany w ramach procesu zarządzania
naprawdę zależy od podaży i popytu
i znasz swoją stopę procentową
przed zaciągnięciem pożyczki
Oczywiście z całą pewnością powiedzmy, że:
chcemy utworzyć pożyczkę
chcemy utworzyć jakieś LKSM i aUSD
zamierzam włożyć w to może jakieś 5 LKSM
tutaj i teraz zamierzam wziąć, jakieś 2
dolary pożyczki
już możesz zobaczyć
kwotę pieniędzy, którą możesz pożyczyć
oprocentowanie tutaj
karę za likwidację
Jeżeli sprawy idą źle, to tutaj
możesz ale
jest szansa, że jeśli przekroczysz kapitalizację
i pozycja staje się ryzykowna
możesz zostać zlikwidowany, więc jest to
hmm
obraz, który możesz zobaczyć
zanim
weźmiesz pożyczkę i ją finalnie zatwierdzisz
etap, na którym będziesz
jeszcze raz przejdź dalej i potwierdź wszystkie
liczby i naciśnij potwierdź i to
W taki sposób możesz
utworzyć długą pozycję, więc właśnie wziąłem
pożyczkę
używając mojego LKSM i otrzymałem jakieś dwa
dolary, jeżeli teraz wrócę
do interfejsu
mam dwie pozycje otwarte, jedną z
bitcoin`em i jedną z LKSM
tak to wygląda. Całkowicie mam
pożyczone jakieś parę tysięcy
dolarów w zamian za
LKSM i ramBTC
jest to sensowne i ktoś zapytał gdzie
odsetki faktycznie trafiają
więc, odsetki trafiają do
skarbca
i są zarządzane przez sieć
jest to właściwie
kontrolowane przez sieć dla długotrwałego
funkcjonowania sieci
oprocentowanie ostatecznie byłoby
nadwyżką w ramach tego systemu oraz
jeśli przeczytałeś nasz whitepaper o
zdecentralizowanym niezależnym funduszu
który ostatecznie trzyma odsetki i jest zarządzany
przez posiadaczy tokenów
okay. jeszcze jedno pytanie, które jest
istotne. koncepcja
likwidacji jest nowa dla większości
osób i
Zasadniczo o co on zapytał jest
co się stanie, jeżeli
token który jest zasadniczo zabezpieczony
jego wartość spadnie, więc
likwidacja w tym znaczeniu nie oznacza
tego, że stracisz
wszystko co włożyłeś, dlatego
tam jest odsetek likwidacyjny
więc
Na tym przykładzie Ruitao pokazał to, że
co to oznacza, jeżeli cena
bazowa
aktywa zabezpieczającego, które umieściłeś
powiedzmy, że jest to bitcoin. Jeżeli cena
spadnie
do punktu, w którym stanie się ryzykowna
w zależności od tego, co
system pokazuje tutaj, potem twoja
pozycja zostałaby zasadniczo sprzedana na
na poziomie
stawki 20. rodzaj opłaty fee
za tą likwidację
się odbywa
Tak, myślę, że lepiej jest myśleć
o likwidacji, bardziej jako
Jeżeli bierzesz pożyczkę i zabezpieczasz
ją bitcoinem, następnie ustawiasz zlecenie
dla określonej ceny
część Twojego zabezpieczenia zostanie
sprzedane i zobaczysz, że to wygląda
tak jakbyś sprzedał to zabezpieczenie
po tej cenie. Nadal będziesz posiadał
pieniądze, które pożyczyłeś
tak jakbyś
sprzedał to zabezpieczenie z
karą
Fajnie, przejdźmy do następnego
punktu
W następnej część będzie
o
DEX`ach, gdzie możesz handlować
walorami
będą dostępne w Karura i walory
będą
dostępne w szerszym ekosystemie Kusamy
tutaj możesz handlować, więc możesz
zobaczyć, że pożyczyłem jakieś aUSD, czy kUSD
stablecoin. Mogę już zacząć
handlować. Na przykład kupić
za 100 kUSD może jakieś
polkaBTC i mogę powiedzieć, że to
co zamierzam handlować jest bardzo podobne
do uniswap
giełda typu AMM klikam jeden
przycisk
i boom będę handlować i
kupiłem trochę polkaBTC
Innym sposobem w jaki również mogę handlować
poprzez sprzedaż, na przykład
polkaBTC i uzyskać jakieś walory
DOT albo coś innego, dopóki
tam jest płynność, którą możesz handlować
na tych DEX`ach, ten DEX jest bardzo
użyteczny, kiedy
sieć zostanie uruchomiona, to będzie
jednym z pierwszych DEX`ów, które
będą dostępne
na Kusamie, która pozwala na handel
w sposób nie wymagający zaufania
i dlatego, że jest to typu AMM
giełda, możesz również
dostarczać płynności, więc możesz dostarczyć
płynności podobnie jak
dostarczanie zestawu par do póli
na przykład aUSD
wraz z DOT i możesz je dostarczyć, to będzie
wymagać ilość x aUSD oraz ilość x
DOT
dostarczając płynność do tego DEX`a, jesteś
właściwie animatorem rynku
i jako bierny animator rynku będziesz
zarabiać
płynność, opłaty transakcyjne będziesz
wszystkie nagrody, kiedy jesteś
dostawcą płynności
więc za każdym razem, gdy ludzie handlują, Ty
zasadniczo pomagasz im w handlu i
robąc to, na końcu będziesz mieć
niezły udział
w opłatach transakcyjnych przez dostarczanie tej
płynności, ta giełda sama w sobie
jest już całkiem użyteczna dla konsumenta
ale ma też jakąś
rzeczywista funkcjonalność jest tak naprawdę
szkielet jednolitego źródła płynności
suma dla całej sieci, o której
omówię później
kiedy pokażemy funkcję płatności za gaz
jednak na razie
możemy zobaczyć, że to jest bardzo
przyjazne użytkownikowi
przyjazny dla konsumenta, przyjazny sposób abyś mógł
handlować nie wymagając zaufania na Kusamie
i Karurze
i aby jeszcze raz wspomnieć co
Ruitao wspomniał wcześniej
to jest nasz sieć testowa, więc kiedy
Karura zostanie uruchomiona
będzie skoncentrowana wokół KSM, więc to co tutaj widzisz
jest to aUSD
i ACA, kiedy Karura zostanie uruchomiona
zobaczysz
kUSD, będący dolarem Karura i
tutaj zobaczysz
KAR zamiast ACA, która jest
tokenem użyteczności Karura
Kolejną sprawą, o którą pyta Ben jest
coś takiego jak jaki jest udział w zarobkach
za dostarcznie płynności
więc jedną rzeczą, o której musimy wspomnieć jest to, że mamy
odłożone
um it's six percent uh right rutau of
our of the
kar the karua supply for the initial
liquidity provider
program so this is this is a bit of an
alpha leak i think on this on this call
but definitely uh
something that will reward early
liquidity providers who
who bring in whatever it might be if
it's ksm
or what have you um there will be there
will be an opportunity to provide
liquidity for
for any of these pairs on the career
decks from day one when we launched
yes yes i think this is another reason
that why um
we think kuru is going to be so amazing
for kusama token holders because you can
actually put the kusama token into work
for you right you can simply provide
liquidity
uh in the cruel network and start to
enjoy return
um for participating in this network and
for the uh
for the for the rewards when providing
liquidity they actually double reward
in the very first year that we as then
mentioned so you will be earning the
typical
liquidity provider fee that's like uh
pretty much industry standard if you
check out like sushi swap you can check
out that uni swap
um they already pretty much like to eat
the standard liquid liquidity provider
fee
but in additional you will be earning uh
some liquidity reward for the for early
contribution
for kurura and as then said we set aside
a set of
kura token to be used for that
particular
incentive as well a couple people are
asking about
um impermanent loss when providing
liquidity
yeah definitely like if um obviously in
the
in in short run or in short term if you
check
uni swap there's like this problem of
impediment loss
um when you're providing um liquidity
pair to let's say two very volatile
assets uh it's in the in the very
beginning it's almost the same for
providing liquidity
uh in um in kura as well so you will
experience some of the implement loss in
short term
but in long term um if you actually
check the historic data
in long term that pretty much all turns
out to be great um the additional
incentive that we have in place
for kr tokens um as liquidity rewards
for providing
early liquidity will even offstat that
if there's any
even further and we have some exciting
stuff that we may come up later when we
start to roll up
stuff one by one as i said uh or as dan
described
um kuru and alkala a specialized network
right it's like
a network specialized for finance um so
when when we go live it's not going to
stay in this straight we're going to
continue
to improve and continue to grow up new
feature on top of that
that's the hints i can give up today
cool yeah i guess we can move on to the
next
section someone was asking like when you
can do this when you can provide
liquidity when you can use
um the decks and the answer is the
moment we launch
so karua we just need to win the pair
chain slot
auction and the moment we win that um
all these
as you can see right now this is all
built we've been actually waiting
to launch this so the moment we can get
our
our slots in the kusama network we'll go
live and this stuff will all be usable
um from the moment we we get started
yeah so the next section is about liquid
staking and this is super amazing i
i just can't wait to use this feature so
the liquid staking in essentially in a
nutshell is like
it's a meta a trustless staking pool
that you can free
your stake asset so think about as like
if you're holding kusama today
and if you stick with validators which
you should
every time that you want to spend or you
want to move your kusama you have this
typical
seven day uploading period for the
security of the network
and on polkadot it's even longer it's 28
days for unbounding your stack assets
so what we created as what we call
liquid staking essentially
a trustless staking pool that you can
stack using
a kura and every time that you stake you
will be getting a receipt
of your stake assets uh because it's
trustless the receipt of your state
asset
is what we call lksm so lksm is
you bailing as long as you hold on to
lksm
you will be earning the staking reward
it's also safe because it's trustless
it's always guaranteed that you can
redeem for more
uh ksm when you want to redeem the the
ksm back
so um this is something that's extremely
extremely
user-friendly i think everyone should be
using this if you hold a hokusama
um and i'm gonna demonstrate here right
so um for me to stay in this
techniques trusting uh in this trustless
staking pool
it's as simple as i just swap some some
dots or some ksm into lksm
we make the user interface looks like
swapping but inside instead this is not
this is staking
so i'm going to say that i'm going to
stick and this is um
essentially it's taking one ksm and
exchange i get z
i get 10 lks and bad the the this ratio
is determined by the system uh we're
going to improve this
user interface later so it's always say
that uh one
ksm will be equal to one lksm and then
one lksm will be equal to more and more
ksm when you redeem later
that's like if you hold on to lksm you
will be growing very similar to how you
save money in compound your money will
be growing that's like you are earning
interest
but in this particular in the in your
liquid staking you are earning the
staking reward
the lksm go ahead again let me just
explain that so in this case you can see
dot and l dot so
that might be easier so what you're
doing here is you're staking dot
and say you're staking 10 dot you would
get 10
l dot in return and those liquid dots
can be used within
akala if it's dot um but what what
ruitan mentioned is
how this l dot is a receipt for your for
your staked dot
so if you can imagine like on the on the
wallet screen that rue tau showed you
with all of your balances
your l dot balance will actually always
be going up
because it's it's showing you it's a
receipt for your staked dot
so as your staked dot starts earning
more and more staking rewards that'll be
reflected in your
ldot balance so when you go to redeem
your ldot
for like native dot at the end
whenever you want to unstake your l dot
will have gone up
since the moment you actually got your
original l dot if that makes sense
because it's just it's always reflecting
your staking rewards adding on to your
stack of ldap yeah think about
as if eldor is a share of the pool of
the staking pool
and the staking pool is growing size
because there's going to be staking
reward that's
praying to the pool but you can always
redeem um for the same share that you
put it in
so your your that up the the redeeming
number will be always growing so holding
lg holding lksm is as if you are
staking yeah
and it's slightly if you have l or you
have lksm
because we call it liquid right it's
actually transferable within the archive
shot and
within the wider pocket ecosystem you
can send ldap to someone else you can
send lksm to someone else
as he was just moving um as if he's just
moving some
of some some transferrable assets um the
the recipient who gets lg or google
gets klksm can choose to continue to
hold
on the the lks ml dot or they can
continue to
decide to redeem um and get the actual
valina dot back
so this is like the the reason we call
it liquid is that it's transferable it
could be used for other utility as well
and one big utility that you can use
with this l ksm is that
you can actually borrow against um your
lksm
in the demo that i showed earlier is
that you can borrow
against your stack asset so you don't
actually have to give up your
opportunity cost if you say that you
want to borrow against thoughts
you have to choose that hey do i want to
select these thoughts or do i want to
borrow against my dog
but with ldl always lksm this is the
best of both
you could be earning the staking reward
while you're borrowing against a
position
and yeah um dan any any question
yeah one question um from
jack here in the chat is it's basically
like
what he said what happens if you trade
or sell your ldot so you have like the
stake dot you get this l dot
let's say you sell it all and you have
so what happens then to your original
dot like how do you actually
either pay for that or get get the dot
so think about the outdoor it's like an
a receipt or redeems the receipt for
your stakedown right so if you sell your
l dot you actually sell the right
to redeem those stocks so it's as if you
sell the dollar someone else so in the
demo that i just showed
uh earlier if i transfer some ldl to
somewhere else
i was transferring the the redeem right
of the underlying dot
to someone else so it's as if i was
sending dots so if you sew them then you
just slice
your solder dots it's um it's no longer
yours and
yeah the redeem right for that length is
also no longer yours
okay so the the l dot isn't connected
directly to
like a specific dot it's kind of that
pool so if i so if jack here who asked a
question
sent me his l dot i could type that l
dot and redeem it for dot
in the akala pool yes yeah okay
yeah the moment that you the moment that
you stick with the the
liquid sticking pool um the dog enter
the pool
and you essentially get is that what you
essentially get back is the right to
redeem
for the dog and because dog itself is
not functional it's fungible like every
single dog is the same
you can't say that okay that dog is my
dog and that dog is your dog they are
all dogs
yes this guy this sage law said so the
ldad is like the title to a car
so if you sell the title someone else
kind of owns the car
yes since um another good question is
basically could you explain how the the
interest
or the staking interest works since
you're staking
with a kala versus i guess in the in
this case with karua so if you're
staking your ksm with karua it's not
staking like
directly into the kusama chain there's
this there's this kind of application
layer so
they're asking who is paying that
percent interest for
um in the carrera case lksm staking
how does that work well well awesome
like this is a good question right so
the
um think about the um the liquid staking
pool as a trustless staking pool
the dot other the ksm that you deposit
into the pool will be managed by the
network and the
network will then nominate those dots
into the
um validator within the kusama network
and if this dot is
these pool sizes grow in size it will be
managed it will be nominated across
multiple validators in the in the kusama
network
so ultimately the staking reward of the
of um staking by minting the lksm would
be
equivalent to the average eu of the
network it will be safer because like d2
is spread across
multiple validators so even a slash
happens
the risk of like the pool is sort of
like meditated
because only slash a portion a tiny
portion of that but the same
um the sticking reward is also the
average eu
it's like a safe average view of the
expected return
of the network and one key other
fact we need to understand is also the
lksm holders actually can vote for
validators so this is what we are
working progress so
when you meet lksm you guys you have the
the right to say that i
prefer the pool to validate and delegate
the ksm into this set of validators and
ultimately
the pool would check all the input from
the lksm holders
and nominate those um those um kusama
for across all the validators um as
proportion as a portion
okay so yeah so if i'm understanding
correctly just to
to reiterate this for um i forget who
who asked that question but
with kusama now if you're staking
through polka dot js it's you as a user
staking directly to
a validator or a set of validators in
this case
in this case there's kirura in the
middle so you
stake with karua karua distributes the
stake of
everyone on karua to an evenly
distributed set of validators across
kusama and then all the returns coming
in from
those validators are pooled and then
evenly distributed at the average
across all the validators that career is
staking with
yes and if this is like a centralized
staking service then you have the risk
of the
centralized entity being default you
have this chart you have to trust the
centralized entity
um to do the right thing but since um
the the liquid staking protocol that we
currently have
is trustless everything is managed on
chen
uh you can think of like it's like an
advanced version of smart contract
um everyone is staking in a trustless
way and there's no risk of
um of being um managed by one single
centralized entity
so this is the i think this is awesome
this is the way to go um for
um in a sense yokusama even you stick
through the liquid staking
yokusama never leave your custody
yep we have some just really good
questions here so um
kalyan asked um
okay so by staking or by making dot
liquid are we compromising the safety of
the polka dot
chain the dot can be slash still be
slashed right
um what happens then the
so basically he's asking what happens
with like network security and slashing
okay i think this is an awesome question
right so um if the
polka dots network security can be
compromised
by saying that you simply pull up the um
the dot together
and make it transferable and make it
liquid
then i think um it's gonna happen anyway
like there's always a lot of centralized
entities so if you stick with
finance today you can already transfer
your stack asset you can trade it in the
market or things like that
so the thing is that i we don't think
this is going to affect the
um the pokers network security at all
because ultimately
if by simply reprogram or by gaming by
by
building something on top of the network
and you can affect security
then there's actually a security problem
of the underlying layer in this in our
case we don't think that's
gonna have any problem um the other key
stuff to think about if you stick
through this particular
liquid staking pool you actually do not
have the
like the risk-free way to say that you
are no longer getting chance of getting
slashed
so if the liquid staking pool was
delegating or nominating
let's say across 50 validators and one
of those getting slashed
the pool actually will get a hit of
getting this slashed but
the the result of like spreading this
pool
across 50 validator is that even though
you you're getting slash in one
validator
the overall damage for the whole pool is
particularly low and that's why i say
it's a
safe way to stake uh it's getting the
average view of the network
it's not trying to seek for the maximum
return
but it's also a very very user-friendly
way that you can always expect to earn
the expected return of the network
um if you were stating by yourself and
if you're nominating your dot to one
particular
validator and then if that validator was
misbehaving it slashed
then you will get a you will take a
touch by normally getting that validator
if you stick through this pool
there's still chances that value gets
latched but the overall cost
for the pool holders will be even out
and will be
reduced
cool so hopefully that helps kalyan
[Music]
oh another thing to maybe mention or
pokazać
is um one of the current issues on
polka dot and kusama right now is are
the there are two things the staking
minimums
are becoming super high on polka dot and
also on kusama
um so what this allows is
for people to come in and stake dot with
like virtually no minimum right like
what would the yes
what would the actual minimum be so this
is like um
i have friends that has like 40 dots
right and my friend really wants to
steak but you can't because the mini
mistaking amount on product
currently i think it's over 200 which is
um a lot
but in this if you stick through um kura
or if you stick through alcohol
you actually can get you can actually
bypass this limitation
because like the pool itself like this
particular gs uh
controlled by the protocol uh will
actually definitely have more than 200
dots
to nominate so no matter how much how
how small amount you have you can still
deposit into this pool
and the pool by itself can nominate um
the total amount of install to all the
validators so yes
we can definitely bypass that and then
the other thing is um
people who are staking through polka dot
js or
um any of the other kind of more native
staking like not
uh exchanges and centralized stuff with
polka dot js right now
you stake ksm and you have to do this
seven day unbonding period
and then with polka dot it's even longer
it's 28 days so it just takes forever to
unlock
with uh with karua and with akala you
can
in talking maybe you can show this but
um basically you can un-stake
early for a small fee
um and that fee is shown i think as
you're kind of um
not checking out but as you're kind of
going through this process
yeah so fee so in this case you're
you're basically unstaking instantly
right and then you're paying a fee of
.02 dot
yes so the design of the liquid sticking
pool is that if i go to the advanced
tab you will see that we always have
some maintenance some free
dots or some free kusama available for
redeem immediately
so let's say that if an user we really
want to redeem
um the l dot back to dots immediately
you can do so because there's always
a portion to set aside um for free um to
redeem
but if you want to redeem immediately
you need to pay a fee to cover the
otherwise lost return of those free
portion of the
um and also like this is not option this
is not compulsory so if you want to
redeem
there's actually three way for you to
redeem you can say that i want to redeem
now then i will
i will have to pay some fee all you say
that i was gonna redeem
the typical way um that's like waiting
for the standard unbounding period
you can free to do so or you can also
redeem to say that i want to redeem and
there's
a queue of unbounding um dots on the
on the on the on the on the staking pool
because like will be always
rebalanced between the stick dots and
the an unstacked dot so you can choose
that which may be like
five player later you need the dots that
will be at that particular price
so it's actually a lot of like advanced
feature hidden in here that you can
redeem
in multiple way um you can redeem at no
cost or you can redeem immediately
so in that in the middle one that you
just showed um
basically the main difference would be
every
every day closer to the current date
you're just
paying a little bit higher of a fee is
that right yes yes
so thinking about that you want to um
with your money from a fixed term
deposit account
right so you have to pay some fee or you
have to lose some interest if you want
to withdraw money from a fixed um
from a fixed um deposit account and how
much you want to
how urgently you need the money um
depend and you will forfeit
how much interest you will be giving
back
awesome so i think that's um the the
show off
of the uh of the liquid staking protocol
and um all these three particles like
they work with each other
um the liquid staking dots on the lksm
can be used um to borrow um can be used
as character
can betray in the decks as well um and
because we call ourselves like as a as a
specialized network
i would like to really show off
something that's like why we call
ourselves as a specialized network is
because like we can
customize stuff that's outside um the
um outside application layer we can
customize a logic has
in the blockchain layer that can create
something that's like amazing
to boost the user experience much much
friendlier so what i'm going to do here
is i'm going to switch to a brand new
account right
i have this brand new account and i have
nothing else but 500
usd or kusd in this case i have no other
assets
we have this like pay as a goal or like
fix the fee or bring your own gas
i can start to trade immediately as i as
long as i have some assets
in the guru network so i'm going to send
a hundred dollars to
an another address i will just press
confirm i'm going to type in my password
and i can send it and the network is
happily taking
a fetch uh uh the iusd that i sent it
was it will charge
like a half of a dollar of the usd as
the network fee
so this is already a huge um user
experience
boost compared to other blockchains this
is like making the
transaction in akala or in kura much
much
friendlier and another very common
scenario
um that you experience is that uh if you
arrive on
kuru or you arrive on kala kala you have
only dots right you have nothing else
but dogs
um and in this particular cases you
still want to transact
within uh we sing within kurura you can
do so so
i'm gonna borrow against my 1.5
kusama let's pretend it in these cases
i'm going to borrow against that
i have no other assets i have only dots
i can still change that
i can change that and the network is
happy to take a friction off my god
or my kusama as the network fee to allow
me to transact
so this is like what we call uh bring
your own gas flexi
flexi fee and this is like you are not
forced you are not
uh you are not forced to buy some native
tokens just to in order to
to pay for the guest fee we think a
specialized financial network
should be as smooth as possible should
be encouraging
um the user to trader to trade other
than tight you should really get some
token before you can trade
uh so this is the one the special
functionality um that you can see that
the power um
if you can customize the network into
the core level
yeah um this person jack asked a really
good question
um and it's it's exactly right so he's
so um
is there any question regarding like how
we um how we show this um
this fixed flexible fee payment on gas
yeah can you can you hear me
oh can you hear me i think we lost dan
um but don't worry
i can continue to
i'm
rita i'm here can you can you guys hear
me
um i can't hear you dan um
can you hear me then okay oh well
i think for some reason i can see dan
the spinning the spinning okay that's
great
um maybe then i will i will try to
rejoin
or you can you can you can carry in the
conversation i will try to rejoin and
see if you can uh
if i can hear you let me let me try to
rejoin okay
cool
okay well i'm glad it wasn't just me
um so let's see what was i gonna say oh
yeah there was a question about
um from
from who was it jack oh about how the
pay your own gas or what's it
basically the gas fee um bring your own
gas so
as i try to invite roytel back
uh basically you were is it is he right
there you hear me now
yeah i can hear you right now i think
it's awesome like we're building we're
building web
we're building web 3.0 but now the web
2.0
streaming service failed on us okay
i was i was trying to answer the
question so
jack you are exactly right the way that
the gas fee
actually works um on the surface on the
ui
to the user it looks like you're paying
in bitcoin or
link or eth or whatever it might be but
on the back end you're exactly right
it's actually being sent to the akala
dex on the back end and transferred for
the aca which is actually the fee that
has to be paid for that transaction
so you were right there
so yeah ruta do you have anything else
in terms of demo
we've got 51 questions
yeah i would just maybe um in my screen
show off um
what one additional reason that you i
mean all the kusama holders should
support
kura it's like when we launched guru
um dan already hinted there's going to
be a liquidity mining um
reward incentive program so
it'll be super awesome like if you
launch if kura launched
you can not only you can start to trade
your kusama token
you can also earn some return by
providing liquidity
by maintaining stablecoin there's a lot
of fun stuff you can do
by participating in this network as an
early computer so i think this is
a really amazing chance to push straight
no better way to push up kusama with a
set of
useful consumer um protocol along with a
way to participate the network and get
return
get rewards yeah i know we actually had
a question about
that six percent someone kept
someone asking a few times um is
so i guess um bit i need to find
bayes bayes was asking and i just like
there's so many questions
uh well hey
i guess baze will find that question and
come back to it
someone also asked about the crowd loan
i
how they lock and contribute to all that
let's keep the conversation um kind of
focused more on the product today
there's going to be
we've done crowd loan presentations in
the past and we're going to be doing
at least one probably more before that
starts
so trust us we're going to be giving you
probably more education than you even
need on how that whole process works and
we'll
we'll be doing that um when the time
comes we're
we're waiting just like you guys and we
don't know dates or anything like that
but it's it's going to be soon it's it's
looking like
um the question about the liquidity was
six percent of kr will be allocated to
early
liquidity providers how many early
providers will that
apply to and is there like a fixed
amount or how does that
work no because like this is a brand new
area right so
um we think six percent is going to be
distributed across
the very first 12 months is upon network
genesis
and that's the total the minimum total
that we the network is willing to
incentivize um
early adopters and because like this is
a brand new area
we will be reviewing um all the
governance process of the network we're
reviewing
uh where incentive incentive is needed
at most for example if more stable coin
is needed um
every two week the governance process
will review there should be more
incentive deploying
into the stable stable coin meeting if
more tax volume or the more tax
liquidity is needed
um every two weeks the government's
process will say that okay there will be
slightly more incentive in the in the in
the decks at that particular pair
so you'll be constantly updating but the
goal for the network is to give out
um six percent at minimum with for the
various 12 months
for everyone that contributing that's
trading that's providing liquidity
that's meaning stablecoin
um or maintain the lksm token in the
network
so yeah there's so many ways to
participate
and that so i guess there's a little bit
more to his question like
or his or her i don't know um the first
he's saying or he or she is saying like
the first is it is it a cap on
like time how do you how does the six
percent get distributed across that
12 months if there's all these different
ways of
allocating that yeah i think that's like
the
in the very early we because the network
was freshly generous
genocide so we don't know um and what it
really depends on
every constant review of every two weeks
but um
the goal is to to dispute this i think
the very early there will be more
uh incentive as well currency to end
will be slightly less
um because that by then the level should
be already bootstrapped so
i think the best way um to get more the
maximum amount of reward that you're
able to get is to get in early
and constantly checking the governance
process of like where the most incentive
will be located there
and supply um to those um protocols
cool okay well we're hitting an hour
so for those of you who need to go um
feel free we're finished with the
presentation um
we've got a lot of questions so i think
we can spend
maybe 10 minutes working through these
as quickly as we can
and what what we can do and
this is going to take some work but i
think we can we can commit to this is
we'll go through the questions
afterwards that we didn't answer and if
there's any
questions that are like particularly
good questions we'll get some q
a written up and send that as a
follow-up to everybody who is on this
on this call so apologies if we can't
get to your question but we'll
answer as many as we can now and then
respond with the others
so the first
question is um
the most upvoted so they're asking
um i i think one of the most asked
questions is unanswered
was yesterday's build a call email
official
well there's um how do i say that
there's a
community reward event so if you do have
a code
and if you do check the website's
official
icloud.network then it is the official
channel and if you received any emails
from
akala foundation just make sure you're
checking the domain
if it's at akala.network then that's
coming from
the akala foundation
second question is um
okay is there a date for kurora's
auction process i already answered that
no soon
um okay let's see
they're asking if the if u.s citizens
will be eligible for
the crowd loans and parachain auctions
um we are working with regulators
and legals and i don't have a
definitive answer at this stage it's
likely
maybe but we will know that um
it's not a no but it's also not a yes
but we'll know that once um the auction
process opens cool
okay
this okay this question i answered about
l dot and dot
the kind of receipt and how your l dot
balance is going to be constantly going
up in relation to reflect what your dot
balance is doing behind the scenes with
the staking
that's a good question
um so in the intensity stable coin dusty
swings
will be made
so
so the next question i see is um
carrera is intended to be the defy hub
of kusama and akala
will be the defy hub of polka dot um
will this be the only defy hubs or will
there also be other
d5 platforms well we see
the um the poke gonna have like a 100
power chance
so there's going to be always open and
trustless way for people to build right
but what i can say is that currently
karura is going to be the product and we
want the permanent project
in in kusama we had a very well the top
developed project
um in terms of like project completeness
so we have the code set
uh the whole code ready to go being
audited three times
um so i mean as things evolve there will
be more specialized network but i think
at this stage we will say that we
are the most ready the top pronoun
project
to go in this in this direction and
obviously the question regarding like
what the the kusama
the crew are serving kusama and the
akala serving polka dots
the the idea behind is that guru is
always going to serve the kusama
community and the kusama community's
culture
is very different from the polkadot
community sculpture
so i'm always using this example that
for kusama it's like
wilder it's like i don't want to say dgm
but it's more of like
risk-taking aggressiveness um and
vibrance
um polkadot is more of like um serious
um
security uh bankrupt security or things
like that so
upon launch this two network is the same
but they will evolve in their own very
distinctive style i would say
okay i'm gonna keep skip there's a lot
of build-a-collar questions we've
already answered that
um
so this so why i have a kala in kura i
already answered that
too it's basically to serve the d5
demand of of the kusama and polka dot
yeah and then i think there's a lot of
questions in the chat regarding that can
a u.s citizen participate in the crowd
na
i i mentioned earlier that i didn't say
no
but i mean we are working with with
legals and regulators
i don't have a definitive answer today
but we'll find out right
yep um
how many they're asking how many kar
they could
potentially receive as part of the crowd
loan for kusama
um yeah i think i'm very already shared
the numbers right so for the
one year lease the minimum amount of kr
that you are receiving
per kusama contributed is 12. you might
get more but that's the minimum amount
it's guaranteed
and with with that being said we know
that polka dot
has the maximum lease pair chain slot
lease of two years
we don't actually know yet the kusama
team hasn't revealed the the maximum
so when rurita is saying one to 12
plus this is for assuming we have a one
year slot
there's a chance that it could be less
than that or more than that we this is
one of the key things we're waiting on
from
gavin and the team at kusama yeah that's
the culture of kusama like expect health
you don't know until it's live
like a day before yeah
um exchanges
let's we'll skip that and you'll just
find out later
um okay um
they're asking this is a good question
and kind of more recent so
why did akala decide to re-denominate to
1 billion and kr at 100 million
well i think it's mostly due to the
reason that
polkadot itself has a redenomination
it will give out a much nicer ratio like
for example if you
um take kusama you get some kr token you
will see
you will see the similar nice ratio when
you stick dot to get some
aca token as well it's purely for that
reason um
yep um hope to answer that
yeah and the other aspect of it is the
the underlying like
the decimal point problem there was
quite a bit of issues with
um i think polkadot in the beginning
keeping the original token supply
added a lot of complexity with like too
long of decimal places
so that was the other that was the other
reason for
the akala one
i call
okay um
let's see take a couple more
oh someone's asking about the
collectibles tab
uh nfts and maybe i can just add to this
like what is zakala's
kind of i guess thoughts around or
strategy around nfts
i think there's already you can see
there's a collectible tab there's
already
some collectible being given in the test
nets um
because we've been building this test
net for a long time so i think that
hasn't been up and running for over half
a year
it's a way to reward the early uh
participants
in the test net there's already some
entity being minted in the testnet and i
think they would also be carrier
uh to mainnet as well um and
then maybe you can share a little bit
like um about the collectible that maybe
we have some
surprise when we're going to go launch
on the on the crowd on stage i'm not
sure how much you want to share but
maybe
take the stage dan um
yeah i don't think there's too much to
share on that like quite yet so we
we're just thinking around other ways to
kind of think and incentivize
um people who are early contributors and
crowd loan supporters so
um there could be some kind of surprises
that pop up in that
collectibles tab come come time for the
crowd loans yeah i would just say that
we think uh we are we are making history
right so i mean
if you guys uh put supporting along with
this right uh maybe there's a piece of
um
unique collectible that may be earned
through this process
here's a question that i saw pop up a
few times today
um who is this that's a good question
brian
so as traffic picks up within the
network how does this affect
gas and this is a question that
relates to kusama and polka dot um so
maybe you can
answer that one yeah okay awesome
question i think the um
my point of view on gas fee is that we
want to keep the gas as low
as possible it's um the gas fee is not a
way um to boost the network values
in fact the gas fee should be kept as
low to
as possible to encourage transaction
activity happen on the network and
there's that those are the stuff that
bring the network values
um in our rough test as a project and i
think we
see tps scale at a thousand or above
że
so um the way that we calculate gas is
weight based rather than the
the mechanism you most of people
familiar with the ethereum which is like
building
for the photogas fee because
the power chain has much higher capacity
in processing transactions
we think um we're able to maintain a
very low gas fee
um for for for as extend extend
i would say for the for the near short
term to medium term futures um i don't
think that's going to be a problem
and if we are hitting even hitting that
bottleneck of like two thousand
or a thousand transaction per second uh
the ultimate solution um
it's just like in the imagination um
stage at this stage is always
what scavenges polkadot within pogba
does there's a little bit long term but
i don't
want to get kept to carry too much on
that i would say there's always scalable
solution
when building a polka dot and we always
have a way to maintain low gas fee
yeah i want to pulse i showed something
last time that
that people i think liked and i'll just
share just to add on to what you're
saying about polka dot within polka dot
um if i can find it real quick oh yeah
here it is
so it's it's
definitely something that's in the
future but it's it's pretty interesting
do
to kind of think about so i'll just
share this real quick
and i will i will say that this is this
is nothing official
this is a this is something that i built
myself when i heard about polka dot 2.0
and what it could potentially be
and what he what retal is referring to
is like relay chains within relay chains
so what you could have is a kala
starting as a para chain here
but then this eventually deciding to
branch out and build our own relay chain
which then connects into the original
polka dot so you've got polka dot within
polka dot within
polka dot in this diagram and this is
potentially
where we could be heading in the future
kind of fun to think about
we'll see if it comes true
um okay it's let's take like one more
question
carrera tokenomics i pasted the link in
the chat
so akala dot network slash karua slash
token
is a good place to go for that
and yeah let's let's call it a day we've
been here for an hour and 15. like i
said i'll go through the questions and
anything that we didn't answer i'll
try to create a response if it's if it's
a good question
and that's that's about it hopefully you
guys learned something new about
i i know i i learned something new and
had fun looking at the product demos
this will be this is being recorded and
this is going to be live
on our youtube so definitely um
watch out for our twitter we'll post the
link on our twitter and then feel free
to share it with your friends if you
learned something and want to kind of
help spread the word so
um thanks everybody for taking the time
to join us
and we will definitely see you soon yeah
thank you super excited and can't wait
for the product to go live please
support us
bye guys bye guys