[Music]
最初にお見せするのは、
まずは
ウォレットページです。
ここではKaruraプロジェクト内の
すべての資産を
管理することができます。
ご覧のようにKARトークン、
KSMトークン、
aUSDトークンを持っており、
you can freely transfer um to other
voltages
by just interacting with this front-end
dap you can manage your assets as
if like one of the aggregation of your
assets um get access to
value transfer or get access to things
like
minting btc mint in poca btc
or do inter production transfer for
example if i want to transfer
um alcohol asset from my collar to for
example hydradex
i can select here and do a interchange
transfer so this is
almost looks like an uh a user very
friendly wallet they can
you can access like um in my opinion way
better than than just um
than just using polkadot.js to to to
interact with the the blockchain
what you're showing here is a wallet
that can be used similar to people have
on polka dot js now or even some of
their mobile wallets but
when they connect what they would do to
actually see these numbers here is it
correct that they would go up to the
polka dot
js extension and connect their polka dot
js account to this wallet and it would
show
their live balances within this wallet
is that
yes yes yes definitely and the poke.js
is very similar to the
metamask equivalent on polka dots um you
can manage multiple accounts
in this wallet section as well so i can
change to another demo account here
you can see all the stuff i refresh on
the fly i can change back to my original
demo account
and you can also see a history of your
past transaction
so very very user-friendly very very
consumer-focused
this is your your one-stop to access
your your assets
on cora yeah so you basically connect
one
account from your polka dot js and then
it shows you every wallet that's kind of
connected to that
account yes yes
and obviously in in pogo.js you have the
right um you're the way to manage like i
would like to use this on alkala
i only wanted to use this um this
particular watch address
maybe only on relay chain on kusama all
you can say that i would like to use
this
wallet in all the available power chains
and relations
so you can get it's the your the user's
um
um ability to choose like where this
wallet is going to be made available and
if you make it available
for garura it will appear here and you
can manage that so when the caller
is launched um it's going to only say
akala and have the akal logo when
carrera launches it'll have the kura
logo in the upper left
and then this is always going to say
this for the test net so akala mandala
is the test net
so yeah that will be that will be only
the the name of the
the network when they're live yeah and i
also want to give a little bit hint here
so
kura is the sister network of akala
right so when they
when they're born they are almost
identical but when they go
live and when the genesis happens um the
two networks might take different paths
like you might see assets that will be
only available
on guru ra because like they will be
only available on kusama or you might
see feature they'll be only available on
karua
because like it's the wild cousin of
polka dots and you will see the similar
stuff happened on kura as the main
alcohol is the main as well so when they
generalize this
it's the same but they might evolve into
its own distinctive
set of features