สวัสดีทุกคน ฉัน Dan Reecer จาก
Acala ตอนนี้ฉันเป็น VP of growth ที่นี่
ฉันอยู่ทีม Acala มาซัก
2-3 เดือน แต่ก่อนฉันใช้เวลาอยู่กับ
Web3 Foundation
ที่ฉันช่วยเปิดตัว polkadot และ
Kusama วันนี้ฉันจะทำ
อย่างรวดเร็ว ฉันอาจจะพูดเร็วเพราะฉัน
พยายามจะให้อยู่ใน
หวังว่าซัก 5-7 นาที
ฉันจะพูดเกี่ยวกับ
การประมูล Polkadot และ Kusama parachain
และ crowd loan ซึ่งเป็นขบวนการ
ของการเปิดตัว
บล็อกเชนซึ่งเป็นหนึ่งในเครือข่ายของ
Polkadot และ Kusama อย่างที่คุณรู้ว่า
ระบบนิเวศ multi-chain นี้
กำลังพยายามเพื่อ
เป็นเครือข่าย blockchain ซึ่งถูกเรียกว่า
parachain
ในอนาคตจะขยายเพิ่ม
เป็น 100 parachain บน Polkadot และ
หนึ่งร้อย
ขึ้นไปบน Kusama แต่ว่าตอนนี้ยังไม่มี
parachain บนแต่ละอัน
ดังนั้นวันนี้ฉันจะพูดเกี่ยวกับ
วิธีการรับ slot
เหมือนกับหนึ่งในกรอบสี่เหลี่ยมตรงนี้ใน
ไดอะแกรม วิธีการเป็น
คนแรก
ที่ได้รับ parachain บน kusama หรือคนแรกที่ได้รับ parachain
บน Polkadot
และขบวนการของ crowdloan และ
กระประมูล parachain ดังนั้น
นี่คือไทม์ไลน์ คุณสามารถเห็น
crowdloan นั่น
มาก่อน ซึ่งเราจะเข้าไปใน ส่วนหลัก
ของอีเวนท์การประมูล parachain ตรงนี้ใน
กรอบสีขาว
นี่คือทีม parachain หลายรายการ
เป็นหลักการ bid ราคาแข่งกันระหว่างแต่ละอัน
เพื่อที่จะชนะประมูล
และผู้ชนะการประมูลจะได้ไปต่อ
และได้รับ slot
ตรงสีเขียวนี้ เมื่อคุณได้รับ slot แล้ว
คุณจะอยู่บน
Kusama หรือ Polkadot parachain อย่างเป็นทางการ
team and you can begin
launching your applications, applications
can build on you
and so on. This is ultimately the
vision of Polkadot and Kusama
and then the last part here you can see
there's an actual end time of this slot
that the team
earns so after the team earns that slot
then there's things that happen
including crowdloan funds being
returned
to the contributors and so on. And
I'll cover all that in the next few
slides.
So parachain auctions, I'm going to start
with, because you need to understand this
before we go into Crowdloans. So
a parachain slot auction is essentially
like I said
teams bidding against each other to try
to win one of these slots
each auction is ultimately going for
one slot it can be divided into smaller
chunks but ultimately
on Polkadot it can be up to 24 months
but some teams may decide to bid for
shorter but to keep this simple let's
just assume the maximum.
Teams that are going into this
auction have two options for how to
actually
bid and what funds to use for their bid
so
first is if you have a single account
say for Kusama, you have a
stack of KSM that you want to use for
this auction
and you don't need to involve your
community then that could be one option.
The more frequent and more
likely scenario
will be number two here, which is using
the crowdloan module
so in this case you're actually
crowdsourcing KSM in the case of Kusama
or crowdsourcing DOT
from your community and you're
basically crowdsourcing this so that you
can use that
in the parachain slot auction.
How often will this happen? So
Parachain auctions will be done
one at a time but it's looking like
these will be about every two weeks so
in the Polkadot and Kusama ecosystem
these things will be happening on an
ongoing basis for the foreseeable future
so crowdloans first of all
like i said are used
for the opening bid in an auction so
teams will
crowdsource these tokens and then use
them in that parachain auction at the
next step.
If you're a user and you contribute KSM
to a Kusama parachain or if you
contribute DOT to a Polkadot parachain
you're essentially agreeing to locking
those tokens for the duration of that
parachain slot.
In the example that I used earlier
let's assume 24 months
then after 24 months your original
principle is returned back to you so
it's essentially no loss and a much more
ethical model
than we've seen in the past with things
like ICOs because in this case
you really hold the team accountable for
actually delivering on their
vision in their white paper because they
need to add value to their network
because they're actually not raising
any funds directly from you as the
community member.
Last, I kind of hinted at this
just now but
the funds that are contributed in
KSM or in DOT
are never touched by the team so there's
no worries about
teams raising money and running away
with it not delivering on what they
promised. All
the interests are really aligned here
and the team is really held accountable.
In the crowdloan,
this is kind of what it looks like.
You've got multiple teams
crowdsourcing KSM or DOT from their
communities
and that leads into the paratrain slot
auction.
Everything that was raised in that
crowdloan stage is
is not accessible to the team but
they can actually use that
in their parachain slot auction. So you
can think of it like a poker table
at the beginning of the auction all
these teams will basically go all in
with the funds that they raised in
their crowdloan.
Then how do we determine the winner?
When the auction starts we will know the
open time
here in the green, and we will know the
close time in the orange over here
and the most exciting point will be when
we hit this close time
the Kusama or Polkadot relay chain
itself will randomly select a time
that determines the end time, this red
bar here. So in this
example you've got Parachain B bidding,
Parachain C bidding,
Parachain A bidding.... E and F
beat A in terms of number of KSM but the
winner was determined at this red line
so
the highest bidder was Parachain A.
This is called an unpermissioned candle auction
and it incentivizes teams to bid
as high as they can as early as they can
instead of waiting until the end like
you might have seen on ebay
where people try to
snipe at the end and get the highest bid.
This is a full walkthrough of this
whole process. You've got
users over here contributing KSM they
contribute in this example to Karura
500,000 KSM. Then Karua
wins the first slot on Kusama and then
begins its launch process so
all of the KSM that was crowdsourced in
this original
crowdloan period is then locked in the
core
Kusama relay chain and then KAR
is then distributed, the native token of
Karura (KAR) is distributed to the
crowdloan contributors
and then at the same time
Karura is also launching so
the Karura stablecoin, the liquid KSM staking,
as well as
the Karura AMM-DEX, the Karura DEX
all go live on top of Karura
when this happens. At the end of
the parachain slot all of the KSM is
returned to the
supporters. Now the
last question that people sometimes
have is: 'What happens at the end of that
slot?' In this example, let's say
that it was a one-year parachain slot
the KSM is returned to the original
crowdloan supporters and then there's
three options for
any team to kind of maintain their
access to the relay chain.
First is to host another crowdloan and
do another parachain auction,
second is to self fund. Karura and
Acala will both have a decentralized
sovereign wealth fund
and over time that will
continue to build and build
so that we can become sovereign and
self-sustainable and actually
bid with our own treasury our own
sovereign wealth fund
for future slots, and then the third
option
there's probably several wiki articles
and videos that you could watch
about this but, the other option is
to become a parathread, which
just means that you have a little
bit less access..
less frequent access to the relay
chain itself.
So that's it in about eight minutes.
Hopefully you learned something. Let me
know if you have any questions.
Thank you, bye.