สวัสดีทุกคน ฉัน brett glodney
dev ของ Acala และวันนี้ฉัน
จะโชว์วิธีการเซ็ตอัพ Kusama และ
or polka dot address using the polka dot
js extension
so i'm going to head down here and open
up chrome
and we're going to head over to the
polkadot.js.org
and click on the extension link so i'm
going to be downloading it for chrome if
you're down if you have firefox download
it for firefox and if you have brave you
can use the chrome download as well
so i already have it so i'm gonna head
over to this um
puzzle piece in the top right corner
click pin
and i'm gonna open it up i understand
and now we're gonna see this screen so
to add an account for the first time
we're going to want to click the plus
sign in the middle of this circle
and we're going to see this 12 word
mnemonic seed the mnemonic seed can be
used to recover your account in case you
ever lose your device or
your computer but it can also be used by
anybody
to get full access to your account so
we're going to want to write it down and
save it in a safe place
and now i'm going to click i have saved
my mnemonic seed safely and click next
steps
so now we have this screen uh we see
this drop down that says
allow use on any chain if we click it
we'll see a bunch of different
chains here if you're creating a polka
dot address you'd want to click polka
dot relay chain
and you'll see that the address in the
top just changed to the polka dot format
and if you're making kusama account you
want to click kusama relay chain
and you'll see that the address changes
again to the kusama format
today i'm going to make a polka dot
account now we're going to want to give
the account a descriptive name and call
it
my account now we want to give this
account a password
the password is what you're going to
need to input every single time you want
to use this account to make a
transaction
so you're going to want to make it
something that's secure but something
you're going to remember
so i'm going to put a password in right
now
and click add this account with the
generated seed
so now we see the account in our
extension with the polka dot flag up
here telling us that this is a polka dot
account
and the polka dot address so let's head
back over to polkadot.js.org
and click the apps wallet link
you'll notice that we got this
authorized page this will show up the
first time you ever go to a site that's
trying to request
access to your extension it gives you
information about what the site is what
the
url is and just giving you a fair
warning that you should
only approve applications that you are
familiar with and that you understand
it's a good idea to check the url that
it's showing you that the request is
from
to make sure it's actually the url that
you're expecting so
everything here looks good so we're
gonna click yes allow this application
access
and now we see the polka dot wallet
so if i head over to accounts we'll see
that my extension is in
the wallet i can see my balance and i
can send transactions from here
uh so that yup that's it that's all you
need to do to set up a polka dot account
and now you can use your extension on
all the different uh dapps out there
that have polka dot compatibility thanks
for watching