[เพลง]
ต่อไปเป็นเรื่องเกี่ยวกับการ staking
สภาพคล่อง และมันน่าที่งมาก
ฉันรอไม่ไหวที่จะใช้ฟีเจอร์นี้
การ staking สภาพคล่องสรุปโดย
พื้นฐานแล้ว
มันเป็นเรื่องของการ staking pool ที่ไม่จำเป็นต้องมีการเชื่อใจ
โดยคุณสามารถ
stack ทรัพสินย์ของคุณอย่างอิสระ
โดยถ้าคุณกำลังถือ Kusama วันนี้
และถ้าคุณเป็น validator (ผู้ตรวจสอบ) ซึ่ง
คุณควรจะ
ทุกๆครั้งที่คุณต้องการใช้จ่ายหรือคุณ
ต้องการย้าย Kusama ของคุณ โดย
ทั่วไป
จะมีระยะเวลาประมาณ 7 วัน
เพื่อความปลอดภัยของเครือข่าย
และบน Polkadot จะนานกว่า มัน
ใช้เวลา 28 วันสำหรับการเอาทรัพย์สินที่ stack ของคุณออก
โดยสิ่งที่เราสร้าง เราเรียกว่า
การ staking สภาพคล่องโดย
เป็น pool ที่ไม่จำเป็นต้องเชื่อใจกัน โดยคุณสามารถ
stake โดยใช้
karura และทุกๆครั้งที่คุณ stake คุณ
จะได้รับใบเสร็จ
ของทรัพย์สินที่คุณ stake เพราะว่ามัน
เป็นใบเสร็จแบบ
trustless ของสถานะทรัพสินย์ที่
พวกเราเรียก LKSM
โดย LKSM คือตัวประกันตราบเท่าที่คุณ
ถือ LKSM
คุณจะได้รับรางวัลของการ staking
มันปลอดภัยด้วย เพราะว่ามัน trustless
ซึ่งมันการันตีว่าคุณสามารถ
ถอน ksm
ได้มากขึ้น เมื่อคุณต้องการถอน ksm
กลับมา
ดังนั้น นี่คือบางอย่างที่
ที่แบบ
ใช้ง่ายสุดๆ ฉันคิดว่าทุกคนควรจะ
ใช้มันถ้าคุณถือ
Kusama ฉันจะสาธิต
ให้ดู
สำหรับฉันที่มีลิสต์การ stake
เชื่อใจใน
trestles staking pool มันธรรมดา
ที่จะ swap
เหรียญ DOT หรือ KSM ไปเป็น LKSM พวกเราสร้าง
UI ดูเหมือนการ swapping
แต่ข้างในจริงๆแล้วไม่ใช่แต่เป็น
การ staking
ดังนั้นฉันจะพูดถึงมัน
และนี้
ฉันจะนำ หนึ่ง KSM ไป
แลกเปลี่ยน ฉันจะ
ฉันจะได้รับ 10 LKSM โอ้ไม่ดีเลย เรทนี้
ถูกกำหนดโดยระบบ
เรากำลังพัฒนา user
interface ทีหลังให้เป็น
หนึ่ง KSM จะเท่ากับ หนึ่ง LKSM
และ
หนึ่ง LKSM จะกลายเป็น มากกว่า
Ksm เมื่อคุณถอนในภายหลัง
มันเหมือนกับว่าถ้าคุณถือ LKSM
มันจะโตขึ้นคล้ายๆกับวิธีที่คุณ
เก็บเงินและดอกเบี้ยจะทบต้นเงินคุณ
มันจะโตขึ้นแบบนั้นเหมือนกับคุณได้
ดอกเบี้ย
แต่ในนี้ โดยเฉพาะในการ staking
สภาพคล่อง คุณจะได้รับรางวัล
การ staking
LKSM มาที่นี่อีกครั้ง ให้ฉัน
อธิบายในกรณีนี้คุณสามารถดูที่
Dot และ Dot นี้
มันอาจจะง่ายกว่า สิ่งที่คุณ
กำลังทำอยู่ที่นี่ เมื่อคุณ staking Dot
โดย staking 10 dot คุณจะ
ได้รับ 10
และเปลี่ยนมันกลับไปเป็นสภาพคล่อง
dot สามารถใช้ใน
Acala แต่สิ่งที่ Ruitan พูดถึง
คือ
สิ่งนี้เป็นใบเสร็จรับเงินของคุณอย่างไร
your staked dot
ดังนั้นถ้าสิ่งที่คุณกำลังจินตนาการถึง
ฉากบนกระเป๋าที่
แสดงทุกสิ่งทุกอย่างของ
balances your l dot
balance will actually always be going up
because it's it's showing you it's a
receipt for your staked dot
so as your staked dot starts earning
more and more staking rewards that'll be
reflected in your ldot balance so when
you go to redeem your l dot
for like native dot at the end
whenever you want to unstake your l dot
will have gone up
since the moment you actually got your
original l dot if that makes sense
because it's just it's always reflecting
your staking rewards adding on to your
stack of ldap yeah think about as if
eldor is a share of the pool
of the sticking pool and the staking
pool is growing in size because there's
going to be staking reward that's
praying to the pool but you can always
redeem um for the same share that you
put it in
so your your that up the the redeeming
number will be always growing so holding
lg holding lksm is as if you are
staking yeah and it's slightly if you
have ldl
or you have lksm because we call it
liquid right it's actually transferable
within the archive shot and within the
wider pocket ecosystem
you can send ldot to someone else you
can send lksm to someone else
as he was just moving um as if he's just
moving some
of some some transferable assets um the
the recipient who gets
elder or google gets klks can choose to
continue to hold on the the lksm or l
dot
or they can continue to decide to redeem
um and get the actual valence dot back
so this is like the reason we call it
liquid is that it's transferable it
could be used for other utility as well
and one big utility that you can use
with this lksm is that you can actually
borrow
against your lksm and the demo that i
showed earlier is that you can borrow
against your stack asset
so you don't actually have to give up
the opportunity cost if you say that you
want to borrow against stocks
you have to choose that hey do i want to
select these stocks or do i want to
borrow against my dollar but with ldl
always lksm this is the best of both
it could be earning the staking reward
while you're borrowing against a
position
one question um from jack here in the
chat is
it's basically like what he said what
happens if you trade or sell your ldot
so you have like the stake
dot you get this l dot let's say you
sell it all and you have so what happens
then to your original dot like how do
you actually
either pay for that or get get the dot
so think about the aldol it's like an a
receipt or redeems the receipt for your
stakedown right so if you sell your l
dot you actually sell the right
to redeem those dots so it's as if you
sell the dot to someone else so
in the demo that i just showed earlier
if i transfer some elder to somewhere
else
i was transferring the the redeem right
of the underlying dot
to someone else so it's as if i was
transcending dots so if you sew them
then you just like as you saw the dots
it's
um it's no longer yours and yeah the
redeem right for that
length is also no longer yours okay
so the the l dot isn't connected
directly to
like a specific dot it's kind of that
pool so if i
so if jack here who asked the question
sent me his l dot i could type that l
dot and redeem it for dot
in the akala pool yes yeah okay
yeah the moment that you the moment that
you stick with the the
um the liquid sticking pool um the dog
enter the pool
and you essentially get is that what you
essentially get back is the right to
redeem
for the dog and because thought itself
is not functional it's fungible like
every single dog is the same
you can't say that okay that dog is my
dog and that dog is your dog they are
all dots
yes this guy the sage law said so the
l-dot is like the title to a car
so if you sell the title someone else
kind of owns the car
yes since um another good question is
basically could you explain how the the
interest
or the staking interest works since
you're staking
with a kala versus i guess in the in
this case with kerra so if you're
staking your ksm with kura it's not
staking like
directly into the kusama chain there's
this there's this kind of application
layer so
they're asking who is paying that
percent interest for
um in the career case lksm staking like
how does that work
well awesome like this is a good
question right so the um
think about the um the liquid staking
pool as a trustless staking pool
the dot order the ksm that you deposit
into the pool will be managed by the
network and the
network will then nominate those dots
into the
um validator within the kusama network
and if this dot is
this full size is growing size it will
be managed it will be nominated across
multiple validators uh in the in the
kusama network
so ultimately the staking reward of the
of
staking by minting the lksm would be
equivalent to the average eu of the
network
it will be safer because like d2 is
spread across
multiple validators so even a slash
happens
the risk of like the pool is
sort of like meditated um because only
slash a proportion a tiny portion of
that
but the same um the sticking reward is
also the average yield
it's like a safe average view of the
expected return
of the network and one key other um
fact we need to understand is also the
l ksm holders actually uh can vote for
validators so this is what we are
working progress so
when you meet lksm you get you have the
the right to say that i
prefer the pool to validate and delegate
the ksm into this set of validators and
ultimately
the pool will check all the input from
the lksm holders
and nominate those um those kikusama
for across all the validators as
proportion as a portion
with kusama now if you're staking
through polka dot js it's you as a user
staking directly to
a validator or a set of validators in
this case
in this case there's kirura in the
middle so you
stake with karua karua distributes the
stake of
everyone on karua to an evenly
distributed set of validators across
kusama and then all the returns coming
in from
those validators are pooled and then
evenly distributed at the average
across all the validators that carrera
is staking with
yes and if this is like a centralized
staking service then you have the risk
of
the centralized entity being default you
have this chart you have to trust the
centralized entity
um to do the right thing but since um
the liquid staking protocol that we
currently have
is trustless everything is managed on
chen
uh you can think of like it's like an
advanced version of smart contract
um everyone is staking in a trustless
way and there's no risk of
um of being um managed by one single
centralized entity
so this is the i think this is awesome
this is the way to go um for
um in a sense yokusama even you stick
through the liquid staking
the yokusama never leave your custody
okay so by staking or by making dot
liquid are we compromising the safety of
the polka dot
chain the dot can be slash uh still be
slashed right
um what happens then the
so basically he's asking what happens
with like network security and slashing
okay i think this is an awesome question
right so um if the
polka dots network security can be
compromised
by saying that you simply pull up the um
the dot together
and make it transferable and making
liquids
then i think it's going to happen anyway
like there's always
a lot of centralized entities so if you
stick with finance today
you can already transfer your stack
asset you can trade it in the market or
things like that
so the thing is that i we don't think
this is going to affect the um the
pokedex network security at all because
ultimately
if by simply reprogram or by gaming
by by building something on top of the
network and you can affect
security then there's actually a
security problem of the underlying layer
in this in our case we don't think
that's going to have any problem
um the other key stuff to think about if
you step
through this particular liquid staking
pool you
actually do not have the like the
risk-free way to say that you are no
longer getting chance of getting slashed
so if the liquor staking pool was
delegating or nominating
let's say across um 50
validators and one of those getting
slashed the pool actually will get a hit
of getting this slashed
but the the the result of like spreading
this pool
um across 50 validator is that even
though you you're getting slash in one
validator
the overall damage for the whole pool is
uh particularly low and that's why i say
it's a
safe way to stake it's getting the
average view of the network
it's not trying to seek for the maximum
return um
but it's also a very very user-friendly
way that you can always expect to earn
the expected return of the network
if you were stating by yourself and if
you're nominating your dot to one
particular
um validator and then if that validator
was misbehaving is slashed
then you will get a you will take a
touch by normally getting that validator
if you stick through this pool there's
still chances that value
gets less but the overall cost for the
pool holders
will be even out and will be reduced
one of the current issues on polka dot
and kusama right now
is are the there are two things the
staking minimums are
becoming super high on polka dot and
also on kusama
um so what this allows is
for people to come in and stake dot with
like virtually no minimum right like
what would the yes
what would the actual minimum be so this
is like um
i have friends that has like 40 dots
right and my friend really want to stake
but you can't because the minimum
staking amount on product
currently i think it's over 200 which is
um a lot
but in this if you stick through um kura
or if you stick through alcala
you actually can get you can actually
bypass this limitation
because like the pool itself like this
particular address uh
controlled by the protocol uh will
actually definitely have more than 200
dots to nominate so no matter how much
how how small amount you have you can
still deposit into this pool
and the pool by itself can nominate um
the total amount of its dollar to other
validators so yes
we can definitely bypass that and then
the other thing is
um people who are staking through polka
dot js
or um any of the other kind of
more native staking like not exchanges
and centralized stuff
with polka dot js right now you stake
ksm and you have to do this seven day
unbonding period
and then with polka dot it's even longer
it's 28 days so it just takes forever to
unlock
with uh with karua and with akala you
can
and we're talking maybe you can show
this but um
basically you can unstake early for a
small
fee yes so the design of the liquid
sticking pool is that if i go to the
advanced
tab you will see that we always have
some maintenance some free
dots or some free kusama available for
redeem immediately
so let's say that if an user we really
want to redeem
the l back to dots immediately you can
do so because there's always
a portion to set aside um for free um to
redeem
but if you want to redeem immediately
you need to pay a fee to cover the
otherwise lost return of those free
portion of the pool
um and also like this is not option this
is not compulsory so if you want to
redeem
there's actually three way for you to
redeem you can say that i want to redeem
now then i will so i will have to pay
some fee
all you said i was gonna redeem the
typical way
um that's like waiting for the standard
unbounding period
you can free to do so or you can also
redeem to say that i want to redeem and
there's
a cue of unbounding um dots on the
on the on the on the on the staking pool
because like will be always
rebalanced between the stick dots and on
an unstacked dot
so you can choose that which maybe like
five days later you need the dots that
would be at that particular price
so it's actually a lot of like advanced
feature hidden in here that you can
redeem
in multiple way um you can redeem at no
cost or you can redeem immediately
so in that in the middle one that you
just showed um
basically the main difference would be
every
every day closer to the current date
you're just
paying a little bit higher of a fee is
that right yes yes
so thinking about that you want to
withdraw money from a fixed term deposit
account
right so you have to pay some fee or you
have to lose some interest if you want
to withdraw money from a fixed um
from a fixed um deposit account and how
much you want to
how urgently you need the money depend
and you'll forfeit
how much interest you'll be giving back