สวัสดีทุกคน
ผม Dan Reeser จะมาร่วมพูดคุย
ที่นี กับ  Ruitao
วันนี้เราจะมาเจาะลึก
ข้อมูลกันสักหน่อย
เกี่ยวกับเครือข่ายของเรา Karura ที่
พวกเราพัฒนาบน kusama คุณอาจจะ
รู้จัก
พวกเราในชื่อของ ทีม acala พวกเรายัง
กำลังเตรียมสำหรับ
การใช้งาน acala บน polkadot อีกด้วย แต่มันจะ
เกิดขึ้นหลังจากเราได้เริ่มใข้งาน  Karura แล้ว วันนี้
เราจะใช้เวลากันสักหน่อย
ในการพูดคุยเกี่ยวกับสิ่งนั้น ให้ฉันเริ่ม
แชร์หน้าจอของฉัน
ฉันจะอธิบายสั้นๆ เกี่ยวกับ
วาระของเรา
เรามาเริ่มกันได้เลย
เช่นนั้น
วันนี้ฉันจะมาพูดบาง
สิ่งเกี่ยวกับ
Karura โดยทั่วไปคืออะไร ฉันจะอธิบาย
ด้วยสไลด์บางส่วนและให้คุณเข้าใจ
ภาพรวมของ
ทุกสิ่ง และ รู้จักผลิตภัณฑ์ ที่เรา
พัฒนา และผมจะพาไปคุยกับ Ruitao
ที่จะมา
สาธิตเกี่ยวกับ ผลิตภัณฑ์แต่ละชิ้น
ที๋โดดเด่นที่สุด
Ruitao จะเริ่มต้นด้วย กระเป๋า Wallet จากนั้น
เราจะมาอธิบายเหรียญ kusd ที่เป็น  Karura
ดอลล่า Stable coin
หลังจากนั้น เราจะพูดเกี่ยวกับ Karura AMM Dex
และจากนั้น
สุดท้าย เราจะจบด้วย Liquid KSM staking
ดังนั้น มันจะเจ๋งมากๆ ถ้า
สามารถทำให้มันเป็นจริงได้ และ
พวกคุณที่ได้เข้ามาร่วมและเห็นจริง ๆ
การทำงานของผลิตภัณฑ์จริงๆ
และ สิ่งที่เรากำลังจะทำ Robin อยู่กับเราที่นี่ด้วย
พวกเราจะ
วาง ลิ้งค์ของพวกเราไว้ท้ายสุด ที่คุณสามารถ
ใช้งานแอพลิเคชันเหล่านี้ได้จริงๆ
บน Testnet ได้ตอนนี้เลย
และเตรียมพร้อมสำหรับสิ่งที่กำลังจะเกิดขึ้น
บน kusama เร็วๆนี้
ดังนั้น ขั้นแรกเราจะขอ
แนะนำตัวเองก่อน และ หลังจากนั้น
เรามาเริ่มกันเลย
ขอบคุณมาก Dan สวัสดีทุกคน
ผม คือ Ruitao ผู้ร่วมก่อตั้ง
acala และ karura เช่นกัน
ทำงานเกี่ยวกับ Karura
ผมทำงานทางด้านบล็อคเชนมา
มากกว่า 7ปี ผมจะบอกว่า
พวกเราเริ่มพัฒนาเครือข่าย acala
ย้อนกลับไปเมื่อสองปีที่แล้ว
พวกเรา คือ หนึ่งในกลุ่มแรกๆ
substrate builders ผมเป็น วิศวกร
จนถึงปัจจุบัน
จนถึงวันนี้ ผมรักการเขียนโค้ด และ
นั้นคือประวัติคร่าวๆ ของผมครับ
ฉันกำลังจะสร้าง
สิ่งล้ำสมัยและตื่นเต้นมากที่
หลังจากสร้างมาเกือบสองปี
เราใกล้จะเข้าสู่ช่วง Go live โปรเจ็คนี้แล้ว
บน kusama
เยี่ยมมาก ขอบคุณ Ruitao และผม Dan
Reeser
รองประธานฝ่ายการเติบโต acala
และ karura
ผมอยู่ในทีมมาสักพัก
2-3 เดือนก่อนหน้านี้แล้ว
เคยทำงาน
นอกเวลา กับ acalaประมาณ
หก เดือนก่อนที่จะเข้าร่วมทำงานแบบเต็มเวลา
ก่อนมาทำงานที่ acala ผมใช้เวลาอยู่ที่
web3 foundation
ทำงานบน Polkadot และ Kusama ดังนั้น
ดังนั้นมันจึงเป็นการความก้าวหน้าทางธรรมชาติ
จากชั้น Layer นี้ขึ้นไป
หนึ่งขั้นจนถึงขั้น Parachain และ
เตรียมตัวให้พร้อม
ความบ้าคลั่งทั้งหมดนี้และ
ความตื่นเต้นที่
กำลังจะตามมาทั้งหมดนี้
การเปิดตัวครั้งแรกที่
เรา
เรากำลังดำเนินการอยู่นั้นคือ karura
และ ผมคิดว่าก่อนที่เราเข้าสู่
รายละเอียดของ
karura และ acala
มันมีประโยชน์ ที่เริ่มสม่ำเสมอ
ที่ขั้นสูงที่สุด สิ่งที่เรากำลัง
สร้าง
เป็นหนึ่งใน parachains เหล่านี้
ขนาดเล็ก เหมือน
gray squares นี่คือแต่ละคู่
เชนหรือแต่ละบล็อกเชน
ที่ถูกปรับแต่งเพื่อวัตถุประสงค์เฉพาะ
และสิ่งที่กราฟิคนี้แสดงให้เห็น
คืออนาคต ที่ซึ่ง
เราจะมี 100 หรือมากกว่าคู่ ที่
เชื่อมต่อกับเชน เข้ากับ kusama
และ 100 หรือ มากกว่า parachains เชื่อมต่อเข้ากับ
polkadot
ทั้งหมดในระบบนิเวศที่เชื่อมโยงกันเป็นหนึ่งเดียว
เพราะที่เห็น
ตรงกลางนี้จะมีสะพานเชื่อม (Bridge)
ระหว่าง polkadot และ kusama แต่
ณ จุดนี้
เครือข่าย multi-chain สองประเภทนี้
จริงๆ แล้ว
ค่อนข้างว่างเปล่า ยังไม่มีคู่เชน
ที่เชื่อมต่อกับทั้งสองอย่างเลย
มันก็แค่จุดเริ่มต้น
และเป้าหมายของเราอยู่ที่ acala และ karura
จะเป็นparachainแรกใน
ในช่องสาธารณะบน kusama
กับ karura หลังจากนั้น จะเป็น
parachain แรกบน polkadot และ acala
ด้วยเบื้องหลังนี้
อย่างที่เราบอกไปว่าเราจะ
พูดถึง karura กันในวันนี้
เราเห็นกันจริงๆ
มันกลายเป็น defy hub นั่นเอง
ของระบบนิเวศ kusama
ตลอดจนการจัดหาผลิตภัณฑ์ ทางการเงินที่แตกต่างกัน
มากมายให้กับ
parachains ต่างๆ และ
application ที่เรากำลังจพเปิดตัว
ในระบบนิเวศของ kusama
ในความคิดของฉัน ไม่มีวิธีใด
ที่จะเริ่มต้นระบบนิเวศของ kusama ได้ดีไปกว่า
การเปิดตัวของ karura ก่อน
เพราะสิ่งที่เรากำลังจะ
อธิบายให้คุณฟัง และสิ่งเหล่านี้ไม่ใช่เพียง
ผลิตภัณฑ์ที่ akala และ kuru จะ
สามารถใช้สิ่งเหล่านี้ได้ จริงๆ
แล้วเรียกว่า primitives
เป็นแนวคิดใหม่ แต่มันถูกสร้างขึ้น
ในบล็อกเชนนั่นเอง
ซึ่งหมายความว่า ที่ทีมอื่นสามารถ
เข้ามาในระบบนิเวศได้จริงและ
ใช้ประโยชน์จากสิ่งที่ทีมของเราสร้างขึ้น
ตัวอย่างเช่น Dollart ของ Kusamaเป็น
stable coin ซึ่งไม่เพียงแต่จะใช้ใน
แอปพลิเคชันของเราเท่านั้น แต่
ยังใช้ได้กับทุกคน
บนระบบนิเวศของ kusamaอีกด้วย ดังนั้นจึงไม่มีวิธีใดที่จะดีไปกว่า
ที่จะเริ่มต้นระบบนิเวศนี้
มากกว่าที่จะสร้างแบบนี้
คุณรู้พื้นฐานที่สำคัญกับ karura ก่อน
แล้วจึงอนุญาต
ให้ทีมอื่นสร้างด้วย
สิ่งที่เรามอบให้กับ
ระบบนิเวศ สิ่งที่คุณเห็นตอนนี้
หน้าจอตอนนี้ คือ
User Interface ของจริง
บน Application Layer ที่่ทีมเรา
ได้สร้างขึ้น
ดังนั้นเราจึงมีผลิตภัณฑ์เหล่านี้
ที่สร้างขึ้นในบล็อกเชน แต่ทีมของเรา
ก็สร้างขึ้นบนเครือข่ายของเราเองด้วย
เลเยอร์แอปพลิเคชันทั้งหมด
ทื่คุณกำลังเห็น และนี้คือสิ่งที่
ruitao กำลังจะสาธิตในวันนี้
เพื่ออธิบายเพิ่มเติมในสิ่งที่ฉันพูดถึง
เกี่ยวกับ acala ว่าเป็นแพลตฟอร์ม
สำหรับแอปพลิเคชันแล้วยัง
เป็นชั้นแอปพลิเคชัน
ถ้าคุณเห็นไดอะแกรมนี้
นี่เป็นการทำงานจาก
ชั้น Base Layer ของ kusana ขึ้นไป ดังนั้น
สิ่งที่แสดงให้เห็น kusama นี้คือ
แพลตฟอร์ม multi-chain ที่
ฉันแสดงให้คุณเห็น และเรากำลังพยายาม
หาช่องใน kusama
และสิ่งที่ทำให้เราทำได้คือ plug-in
ภายในทั้งหมด
ของกล่องสีส้มนี้ ซึ่งก็คือ kurara
และนี่คือ บล็อคเชนของเรา นี่คือ
บล็อคเชน Layer 1 ที่เทียบเท่า
อีเธอเรียมในปัจจุบัน
และภายใน karura มีการ
สร้างผลิตภัณฑ์ทางการเงินดั้งเดิมหรือผลิตภัณฑ์ทางการเงินมากมาย
ที่เราสามารถใช้ได้
ในแอปพลิเคชันด้านบนนี้ ดังนั้นคุณ
สามารถที่จะเห็น Stable Coin ที่ฉันได้กล่าวถึง
liquid ksm staking ที่ช่วยให้คุณ
stake ksm และรับใบเสร็จรับเงินได้จริง
สำหรับสิ่งที่คุณสามารถใช้ได้ภายใน defi
แทนที่จะเพียงแค่ staking ksm ของคุณเท่านั้น และมัน
ถูกล็อคและติดอยู่ที่นั่นและ
ไม่สามารถ
ใช้งานได้อีกแง่มุมหนึ่งคือเด็คของเรา
ที่ ruitao จะสาธิต ที่นี่ เร็วๆ นี้ และ
จากนี้
พวกคุณบางคน เรามักจะพูดถึง
วิธีปรับแต่งบล็อคเชนด้วย
substrate และสร้างขึ้น
สำหรับกรณีการใช้งานเฉพาะ และนี่คือสิ่งที่
เราหมายความตามนั้น
นำค่า gas ของคุณมาเป็นคุณลักษณะที่
ruitao จะแสดงให้ดูในวันนี้
นี่คือคุณลักษณะที่เรา
ได้ปรับแต่งเฉพาะสำหรับเชนของเรา
สำหรับ karura และ acala เพราะ พวกเรากำลังพยายาม
เพื่อให้มันพิเศษสำหรับ D5
และสิ่งนี้ช่วยให้คุณทำอะไรได้หากคุณ
เคยใช้ d5 และ ethereum
คุณรู้ว่าคุณไม่สามารถ
ทำธุรกรรมใดๆ ได้โดยไม่ต้องมี
eth และ หากคุณเป็นผู้ใช้ใหม่ของ ethereum
ก่อนอื่นคุณต้องเรียนรู้ว่า eth คืออะไร
คุณต้องไปหามัน
เป็นกระบวนการที่ยาก แต่ด้วยการนำ
ค่า gas ของคุณเองด้วย kurara และ acala มันจะ
จะช่วยให้ผู้คนนำ
เหรียญต่าง ๆ มาและ
ชำระค่าธรรมเนียมการทำธุรกรรมเริ่มต้นด้วยโทเค็นนั้นทันที
ตัวอย่างเช่น มีคนนำ bitcoin
มาที่
karura ก็จะสามารถนำ
bitcoin มา
ห่อ (wrap)และออกบน kusama
ใน karura แล้ว
แล้วสามารถจ่ายเงินเริ่มต้นได้ บางทีอาจเป็น
การ swap อาจเป็นการโอน แต่การจ่าย
ค่าธรรมเนียมนั้น
ใน btc แทนที่จะต้องออก
ไปหา
KAR โทเค็นซึ่งเป็น
โทเค็นยูทิลิตี้ของ karura
และสุดท้าย acala evm ก็เป็น
อีกสภาพแวดล้อมหนึ่ง
ของ ethereum เฉพาะ ที่เราสร้างขึ้น
สำหรับ karura โดยเฉพาะ
และ acala อย่างที่บอกว่าเป็น
layer 1 ตรงกลางนี่คือ
บล็อกเชน
และจากนั้นทีมของเรา
ด้สร้างแอปพลิเคชันทั้งหมด
ใช้ประโยชน์จากสิ่งเหล่านี้
ที่ฉันเพิ่งพูดถึงคุณไป
ruitao สิ่งที่เขาจะพูดถึงในวันนี้
คือชุดแอปพลิเคชัน
ทั้งหมดของเราที่สร้างขึ้นบน
บล็อคเชนของเรา และจำไว้
ว่าแน่นอนว่านี่เป็น
แพลตฟอร์มแบบเปิด ดังนั้น
มันจะไม่เป็นแค่การ
สร้างแอปพลิเคชันบน karura มันจะเป็น
ทีมอื่นๆ ที่เข้ามาสร้างใน
สภาพแวดล้อมแบบเปิด
ที่เราสร้างขึ้น
ฉันไม่จำเป็นต้องพูดลงลึกเกี่ยวกับเรื่องนี้ เพราะ
เพราะฉันแค่พูดถึงสิ่งเหล่านี้ทั้งหมด
แล้วนี่เป็นเพียง ระดับสูงสุด
karura โดยทั่วไป
เหล่านี้คือ
ผลิตภัณฑ์ทั้งหมดที่เราสร้างขึ้น
มีการสร้างสะพานหลายแห่ง (Bridges)
ระบบนิเวศในขณะนี้โดยเฉพาะ
สำหรับสิ่งที่โดดเด่นที่สุดสำหรับ
bitcoin และ ethereum เร็วๆนี้
ในไม่ช้าหลังจากที่เราเปิดตัว เราจะเห็น
สินทรัพย์ ethereum
ซื้อขายได้และใช้งานได้จริง
ภายใน decks ของเราและอื่นๆ
ในผลิตภัณฑ์อื่น ๆ และ
และนี่คือพื้นฐานของ karura
โดยสังเขปและคล้ายกับ acalaมาก
แต่เราจะยึดติดกับ karura เพื่อ
สำหรับการนำเสนอ
ในวันนี้เท่านั้น
ดังนั้นสุดท้ายฉันคิดว่านี่เป็นสไลด์สุดท้าย แต่
คำถามหนึ่งที่หลายคนถามคือ
ทำไมเราถึงตัดสินใจสร้าง
karura บน kusama นอกเหนือจาก acala บน
polkadot
และคำตอบสำหรับคำถามนี้คือ
เรากำลังทำเช่นนี้
ตามความต้องการของผู้ใช้ ดังนั้น ระบบนิเวศ kusama
และระบบนิเวศ polkadot
แม้ว่าจะมีการทับซ้อนกันอยู่บ้าง
แต่ก็มีความแตกต่างกันอย่างชัดเจนในตอนนี้ และ
พวกเขามี
ชุมชนผู้ถือโทเค็นสองแห่ง
ที่มีความต้องการทาง defi
ดังนั้นเราจึงสร้าง karura เพื่อตอบสนอง
ความต้องการทางdefy ของ kusama และเราจะสร้าง
acala เพื่อตอบสนองความต้องการ d5 ของ
polkadot
แต่ kusama ถ้าคุณมีพื้นฐาน
บน kusamaมาก่อน มันควรจะเป็นสถานที่
เพื่อสนุกกับการทดลองและ
และเปิดตัว
ผลิตภัณฑ์ก่อนที่จะย้ายไปที่ polkadot แต่
หลังจากทดสอบอย่างหนักบน test net
ดังนั้น kusama จึง
จึงไม่ใช่ testnet เลย
มันคือ
ครือข่ายทดสอบที่เรียกว่า rococo และ westend
ได้รับการทดสอบบน testnet
จากนั้นย้ายไปที่ kusama แล้วย้ายไปที่ polka dot
สิ่งที่เรากำลังสร้างก็
เป็นไปตามเส้นทางที่คล้ายกัน
testnet ของเราเรียกว่า mandala
testnet จะมีการสร้าง
ละทดสอบและกลั่นกรองผลิตภัณฑ์ใหม่
ทดสอบ และ
หวังว่าจะเกือบจะสมบูรณ์แบบก่อน
ที่จะย้ายไปที่ karura
karura เป็นที่ที่เราสามารถทดลองได้จริง
ในสภาพแวดล้อมจริง
ด้วยคุณค่าที่แท้จริงบน
เครือข่ายที่อุดมสมบูรณ์
แล้วถ้าเราตัดสินใจว่านี่เป็นผลิตภัณฑ์
ที่ชุมชน kusama
เราก็ได้รับการตอบรับที่ดี เราสามารถ
ปรับปรุงผลิตภัณฑ์ได้ จากนั้นเราจะย้าย
ไปยัง
acala หลังจากนั้น
และสุดท้าย นี่เป็นแค่
การดูตัวเลขบางตัว ฉันไม่จําเป็นต้อง
เจาะลึกทั้งหมดนี้
เราเพิ่งรวมจำนวนชุมชนของเรา
เมื่อวานนี้ และเราเพิ่ง
ถึง 200,000 เราอยู่ที่ประมาณมากกว่า 205 000
ช่อง acala และ karura ดังนั้น
เรากำลังเติบโต
อย่างรวดเร็วมากขณะนี้ และ
และใกล้เคียงมากขึ้น
ขั้นตอนการทำ crowdloanและ
กระบวนการประมูล Parachain ที่
เราเคยพูดถึงมาก่อน และมี
วิดีโอบางส่วนในช่อง YouTube
ของเรา
สามรารถลองได้อย่างอิสระ แต่พวกเราจะไม่
ลงรายละเอียดเกี่ยวกับกระบวนการนั้นในวันนี้
ดังนั้น นี่คือส่วนของฉัน และตอนนี้
เราจะเข้าสู่
การสาธิตและสิ่งที่เราจะทำใน
ในรูปแบบของ
ที่นี่ ruitao จะมาเจาะลึก
เกี่ยวกับ
หนึ่งในผลิตภัณฑ์แล้วเราจะ
หยุดสักครู่แล้วปล่อยให้พวกคุณทำ Q&A
และโปรดถามคำถามโดยเฉพาะ
เกี่ยวกับ
ตัวอย่างที่เขาเพิ่งทำไป
ตัวอย่างเช่น หากเป็น
ส่วนของการยืม ausd นี้เป็นพียงแค่
เก็บคำถามของคุณไว้
เราจะตอบคำถามสองสามข้อ จากนั้นเขา
จะไปยังการสาธิตถัดไป เราจะทำ
Q&A สั้นๆ
จากนั้นเดโมสุดท้ายเราจะทำ
Q&A อีกครั้ง และจบลงด้วย
หัวข้อ Q&A
เพราะฉันรู้ว่าพวกคุณมี
คำถามมากมาย
ruitao จะตอบปัญหา
ทีนี่
ยอดเยี่ยม ขอบคุณแดน
บทนำที่ยอดเยี่ยมมาก ฉันพึ่งแชร์หน้าจอ
ของฉันเพื่อให้แน่ใจ Dan เห็นหน้าจอไหมครับ
ทุกคนสามารถเห็นหน้าจอของฉันได้ ใช่ไหมครับ
ใช่ เราทำให้มันยอดเยี่ยม นี่คือ
ส่วนของหน้าตาเว็บไซต์ของ karura หรือ
mandala บน testnet แต่
แต่นี่จะเป็นหน้าตาเว็บไซต์
ของ karura
มันเหมือนกับที่แดนบอกว่า karura เอง
เป็นบล็อคเชนเฉพาะ
พร้อมชุดคุณสมบัติในตัว และนี่คือ
ส่วนหน้าเว็ปไซต์สำหรับคุณในการโต้ตอบ
ในฐานะผู้บริโภคในฐานะผู้ค้าเพื่อโต้ตอบ
กับสิ่งนี้
เครือข่ายเฉพาะและเห็นได้ชัดว่า
คุณสมบัติที่สำคัญที่สุด
โดยรวมคือเรามีโหมดกลางคืน และ
ที่เข้ากับชุดสีของ karura พอดี
ชุดสีมันดู ยอดเยี่ยมาก
เราจะได้หน้าตาประมาณนี้
เหมือินกับ d4
ชุดสีเมื่อเราเปิดตัวสิ่งนี้
เราเปิดตัว
เครือข่าย karura และหน้าแรกสุด
ที่ฉันจะแสดง
คือหน้ากระเป๋าเงิน นี่คือที่ที่คุณ
จัดการทรัพย์สินทั้งหมดของคุณ
ภายใน karura parachain
และอย่างที่คุณเห็น
คุณสามารถมี
สิ่งนี้จะเปลี่ยนเป็นโทเค็น kar อย่างแน่นอน
คุณมีโทเค็น ksm ของคุณ
คุณมีโทเค็น kaUSDของคุณ
คุณสามารถโอนไปยังกระเป๋าอื่น ๆ ได้อย่างอิสระ
โดยเพียงแค่โต้ตอบ
กับส่วนหน้าของเว็ปไซต์
คุณสามารถจัดการทรัพย์สินของคุณราวกับ
ว่าเป็นหนึ่งใน
การรวมสินทรัพย์ของคุณ
การเข้าถึงการถ่ายโอนมูลค่า
หรือเข้าถึงสิ่งต่าง ๆ เช่น minting btc
การmint เหรียญ polkaBTC หรือทำการถ่ายโอน parachain
เช่น ถ้าฉันต้องการ
ถ่ายโอน
สินทรัพย์ acala จาก acala ไป อย่างเช่น
hydra decks
ฉันสามารถเลือกที่นี่และทำการแลกเปลี่ยน
ดังนั้นนี่คือ
almost looks like an uh a user very
friendly wallet they can
you can access like um in my opinion way
better than just um
than just using polkadot.js to to to
interact with the
blockchain so this is that's what i was
gonna ask you right
so as we go through this i'm just gonna
ask questions that i think
people in the audience might be
wondering so what you're showing here is
a
wallet that can be used similar to
people have on polka dot js now or even
some of their mobile wallets but
when they connect what they would do to
actually see these numbers here is it
correct that they would go up to the
polka dot
js extension and connect their polka dot
js account to this wallet and it would
show
their live balances within this wallet
is that
yes yes yes definitely and the poke.js
is very similar to the
metamask equivalent on polka dots
you can manage multiple account in this
wallet section as well so i can change
to another demo account here
you can see all the stuff i refresh on
the fly i can change back to my original
demo account
and you can also see a history of your
past transaction
so very very user friendly very very
consumer focused
this is your your your one stop to
access your your assets
on kura
so then do do we want to um see if
there's any questions that would like to
um
to um to answer regarding this wallet
interface or should we carry on to work
on the
next section which is the borrowing uh
the borrowing
of the stable coin
um let's see
it might be hard to actually sort
through this
box it okay so if you guys have
questions specific to one of these
demos i'll be actually watching this the
chat here so
which wall someone says which wallet is
chosen for this is it the
ksm wallet um
well this is like the um
if you use pocket.js as the extension
this is
essentially your access to both kusama
and polkadot
and kura and alcohol like every single
subject-based blockchain they go gonna
all be manageable by pocket.js
so think about this it's like a
multifunction version of metamask you
arrive at carrura and you access to your
current asset using your sam
pog.js extension
yeah so you basically connect one
account from your polka dot js and then
it shows you every wallet that's kind of
connected to that
account yes yes
and obviously in pogo.js you have the
right um your the way to manage like i
would like to use this on alkala
i only wanted to use this um this
particular water address
maybe only on relay chain on kusama all
you can say that i would like to use
this
wallet in all the available power chains
and relay chance so you can
get it's the your the user's um
um ability to choose like where this
wallet is going to be made available and
if you make it available
for garura it will appear here and you
can manage that yep
yeah um p i see this guy name or this
this person named p just was asking
about
the branding here so when the kala is
launched
um it's going to only say akala and have
the akala logo
when carrera launches it'll have the
carrera logo in the upper left
and then this is always going to say
this for the test net so akala mandala
is the test net
um so yeah that will be that will be
only the the name of the
the network when they're live yeah and i
also want to give a little bit hint here
so
kura is the sister network of alcala
right so when they
when they're born they are almost
identical but when they go live and
when the genesis happens um the two
network might take different paths like
you might see assets that will be only
available on kurura because like they
will be
only available on kusama or you might
see feature they'll be only available on
kura
because like it's the wild cousin of
polka dots and you will see the similar
stuff happened on kura as the main
alcohol is the main as well so when they
generalize this um it's the same
but they might evolve into its own
distinctive um
set of features perfect
well let's move on to the next uh the
next demo
we've got keith and um
who else was that sage are both
interested in
in borrowing on the platform so let's
get into that
yeah no problem and this is one the
reason that i we think why kuru is so
useful
when it's become a project you can
unlock the utility
of your kusama token and start to um to
to to borrow against your your
uh your kyokusama token so this is the
borrowing interface you can see an
overview of your current position so you
can see
you have i have already borrowed open a
position on ram bdc
i borrow roughly three thousand dollars
against zero point one run bdc
that's a little bit risky but i mean
that's what um the system allows
um you can actually create loans using
any sort of asset that will be
available in the governance process
allowed to be using crypto
and in this particular interface here i
have dot
l dot which we'll be covering later and
this will be definitely it would be like
kusama
el kikuzama and bitcoins so what i'm
going to
demo here is that i'm going to borrow
more
against my 0.1 ram btc position here
so you can see um the current bitcoin
oracle rate is
roughly that number i'm still quite safe
um to borrow a little bit more
against that 0.1 ram bdc so i'm going to
press generate more
i'm going to press hey i will actually
probably ten dollars more and press
confirm
and this is where the signing comes up i
will gonna type in my key
password and sign the transaction and
boom i have ten dollar more that i can
spend and this is how fast um
and project network looks like and all
this is happening on the fly for real
um and you can actually see this on the
on the on the block scanner that's
provided by sub scan
so um this is amazing right this is um
much much
more um responsive much much more
user-friendly
also i can also replay i can pay back as
i set a position if i think um
i'm going to reduce a little bit of risk
here i can pay 100 year ausd
that's like reducing my calculation
ratio
and any asset that will be available
through the governance process can be
borrowed against
different assets would have different
risk parameters so for example bitcoin
might have a risk parameter
on the medieval credit ratio on the
liquidation ratio on the liquidation fee
jobs ldots ksm lksm they might all have
different
ratio they'll be managed and governed by
the governance process
so that is essentially how you borrow
against um
crychos in kura
let so maybe one thing we can do this
concept
of collateralization and taking loans is
probably new to a lot of people i know
it was new to me
um at one point and basically like to to
make this as simple as possible
um like i think many of us are aware of
how like a home
loan works where typically you might put
like 10 down or 20
down that cash that you put down is what
you're putting
down in order to get the full the full
loan of whatever you're getting for that
house
but with the way this works in crypto um
we're actually over you're over
collateralizing
the loan so that's why these collateral
ratios are over
100 and you're what you're doing like
what it really means of collateral
is that you're actually taking bitcoin
something like bitcoin
you don't need to sell it but you can
pull out
um ausd a stablecoin with your bitcoin
still there not sold and then you can
take the ausd
and either you can send that to people
you can make payments you can
use that to provide liquidity within our
decks but
that's essentially what this collateral
ratio means and i don't know ruta if you
have any more to
add to that yeah essentially give you
more utility um to the asset that you
are holding to
that you might not want to sell or in in
short term
and for example for fukusama for for
lksm those are perfectly great
collectors for you to gain more utility
out of your 16 kusama holdings you can
go long you can go short you can
it's i mean the option is it's in your
hand to decide how you're going to use
this collector
um to trade and ride with the market
and broderick asked what about
interest so are you paying interest when
you're taking out
these loans and how does that work yes
so the interest essentially is what we
call the stabilization fee
if you take a long there will be
definitely some interest occur
and this is also the interest used to
manage the supply and demand
of the stablecar as well as like the um
the way to maintain that the stablecoin
will be
packed to to to a dollar in value and
the increase
um all the stabilization fee will be
managed by the governance process
really depends on demands and supplies
and do you know your interest rate
before you take out the loan
obviously definitely so let's say that
we want to create a lot we're going to
create some ldl ksm and scripto
i'm going to put in maybe 5l uh l ksm
here and i'm gonna taking maybe like two
dollar loan
you can already see that um um
the amount of money that you can borrow
the interest rate in here the
liquidation penalty
and if things goes wrong that where how
you can but
in chance that if you over capitalize
and the position becomes risky
you might get liquidated so this is the
um the
the the figure that you're able to see
before you
create a lawn and the final confirmation
stage you will be
once again so go ahead and confirm all
the numbers and press confirm and this
is how you
open a long position so i just created a
loan
using my lksm and received like two
dollars so you can say if i now go back
to an interface
i have two position open one with
bitcoin one with um lksm
those is like um and i totally have
borrowed probably like few thousand
dollars against both
um lksm and ram bdc okay
that makes sense and someone asked where
does that interest actually go
well the ancient cities actually go to
the treasury um
and being managed by the network right
it's it's essentially
controlled by the network for the long
prosperity of the network
the interest ultimately would be the
surplus within this system and
if you read our white paper regarding
the decentralized sovereign wales fund
the interest is ultimately hold managed
by the token holders
okay um one other question that's that's
relevant i think um the liquidation
concept i think is new to a lot of
people and
my so basically what the he he asked uh
what happens if the
token that is basically collateralized
with the value drops so
liquidation in this sense does not mean
that you kind of like
lose everything that you put down that's
why there was a liquidation percentage
so
in the example rota just showed it said
so what that means is if the price of
the underlying
collateral asset that you put down say
it's bitcoin for example if the price
were to drop
to a point where it became risky
according to what the
the system says here then your
your position would basically be sold at
a at a
rate of a 20 kind of um fee
for that for that liquidation take
taking place
yeah yeah i think to better um think
about liquidation it's more of like
uh if you collateralize and you borrow
against your bitcoin and then pick a job
to a particular price
a fraction of your collection will be
sold and you will see that if you were
just like sold those collectors
at that price you will still hold on to
the the money they borrow against it's
just like
you sold those um characters at a
penalty
yep cool well let's move on to the next
one
okay so the next um section we're gonna
cover is the
uh the decks that's where you can trade
um assets
are gonna be available on kura and asset
is gonna be
available in the wider kusama ecosystem
this is where you can trade so you can
see i just borrowed some ausd or kusd
the stable coin i can already start to
trade for example to trade
uh 100 uh kusd for maybe some
poker btc and i can say that okay this
is what i'm going to trace very similar
to uni swap
an am type of change i can press one
button
and then boom i will be trading and
bought some some poker btc
um the other way i can also trade
against by selling for example some some
program bdc and get some property
um dots or something else as long as
there's liquidity you can trade
within these stacks this stack is super
useful um when
the network um boot shaped it's going to
be one of the very first stacks that's
going to available
on kusama that allow you to trade in a
trustless way
and also because it's like an mm type of
exchange you can also
provide liquidity so you can provide
liquidity in sense of like
supplying a set of pairs into the pool
for example electrical by usd
to dodge and you can supply that will
approve x amount of usd and x amount of
dots
by supplying liquidity into this tax you
are essentially a market maker
and passive money maker you will be
earning the
the liquidity um the trading fee you'll
be earning
um all the um rewards um when you are
providing this liquidity
so every time that people trade um you
essentially help them to trade and
you by doing that you'll be ending some
nice share of the
of the trading fees um by providing this
liquidity um this this exchange itself
as for consumer is already quite useful
but it also has some
actual functionality it's actually the
backbone the unified source of liquidity
um for the whole cruel network which i
will cover later
when we show off the gas feed payment
feature but for now
we can see this is like already a very
very user
friendly consumer friendly way for you
to trade in a trustless way on kusama
and kura
and just uh just to mention again what
rutao mentioned earlier
this this is just our test net so when
carrera launches
these will be ksm focus so what you see
here is ausd
and aca when when carrera launches this
will say
kusd which is the carrera dollar and
it'll say
kar here instead of aca which is the
the utility token of kubura yeah
um another thing okay so ben is asking
something like what's the earnings share
for participating in the liquidity pool
so one thing to mention is that we've
set aside
um it's six percent uh right rutau of
our of the
kar the karua supply for the initial
liquidity provider
program so this is this is a bit of an
alpha leak i think on this on this call
but definitely uh
something that will reward early
liquidity providers who
who bring in whatever it might be if
it's ksm
or what have you um there will be there
will be an opportunity to provide
liquidity for
for any of these pairs on the career
decks from day one when we launched
yes yes i think this is another reason
that why um
we think kuru is going to be so amazing
for kusama token holders because you can
actually put the kusama token into work
for you right you can simply provide
liquidity
uh in the cruel network and start to
enjoy return
um for participating in this network and
for the uh
for the for the rewards when providing
liquidity they actually double reward
in the very first year that we as then
mentioned so you will be earning the
typical
liquidity provider fee that's like uh
pretty much industry standard if you
check out like sushi swap you can check
out that uni swap
um they already pretty much like to eat
the standard liquid liquidity provider
fee
but in additional you will be earning uh
some liquidity reward for the for early
contribution
for kurura and as then said we set aside
a set of
kura token to be used for that
particular
incentive as well a couple people are
asking about
um impermanent loss when providing
liquidity
yeah definitely like if um obviously in
the
in in short run or in short term if you
check
uni swap there's like this problem of
impediment loss
um when you're providing um liquidity
pair to let's say two very volatile
assets uh it's in the in the very
beginning it's almost the same for
providing liquidity
uh in um in kura as well so you will
experience some of the implement loss in
short term
but in long term um if you actually
check the historic data
in long term that pretty much all turns
out to be great um the additional
incentive that we have in place
for kr tokens um as liquidity rewards
for providing
early liquidity will even offstat that
if there's any
even further and we have some exciting
stuff that we may come up later when we
start to roll up
stuff one by one as i said uh or as dan
described
um kuru and alkala a specialized network
right it's like
a network specialized for finance um so
when when we go live it's not going to
stay in this straight we're going to
continue
to improve and continue to grow up new
feature on top of that
that's the hints i can give up today
cool yeah i guess we can move on to the
next
section someone was asking like when you
can do this when you can provide
liquidity when you can use
um the decks and the answer is the
moment we launch
so karua we just need to win the pair
chain slot
auction and the moment we win that um
all these
as you can see right now this is all
built we've been actually waiting
to launch this so the moment we can get
our
our slots in the kusama network we'll go
live and this stuff will all be usable
um from the moment we we get started
yeah so the next section is about liquid
staking and this is super amazing i
i just can't wait to use this feature so
the liquid staking in essentially in a
nutshell is like
it's a meta a trustless staking pool
that you can free
your stake asset so think about as like
if you're holding kusama today
and if you stick with validators which
you should
every time that you want to spend or you
want to move your kusama you have this
typical
seven day uploading period for the
security of the network
and on polkadot it's even longer it's 28
days for unbounding your stack assets
so what we created as what we call
liquid staking essentially
a trustless staking pool that you can
stack using
a kura and every time that you stake you
will be getting a receipt
of your stake assets uh because it's
trustless the receipt of your state
asset
is what we call lksm so lksm is
you bailing as long as you hold on to
lksm
you will be earning the staking reward
it's also safe because it's trustless
it's always guaranteed that you can
redeem for more
uh ksm when you want to redeem the the
ksm back
so um this is something that's extremely
extremely
user-friendly i think everyone should be
using this if you hold a hokusama
um and i'm gonna demonstrate here right
so um for me to stay in this
techniques trusting uh in this trustless
staking pool
it's as simple as i just swap some some
dots or some ksm into lksm
we make the user interface looks like
swapping but inside instead this is not
this is staking
so i'm going to say that i'm going to
stick and this is um
essentially it's taking one ksm and
exchange i get z
i get 10 lks and bad the the this ratio
is determined by the system uh we're
going to improve this
user interface later so it's always say
that uh one
ksm will be equal to one lksm and then
one lksm will be equal to more and more
ksm when you redeem later
that's like if you hold on to lksm you
will be growing very similar to how you
save money in compound your money will
be growing that's like you are earning
interest
but in this particular in the in your
liquid staking you are earning the
staking reward
the lksm go ahead again let me just
explain that so in this case you can see
dot and l dot so
that might be easier so what you're
doing here is you're staking dot
and say you're staking 10 dot you would
get 10
l dot in return and those liquid dots
can be used within
akala if it's dot um but what what
ruitan mentioned is
how this l dot is a receipt for your for
your staked dot
so if you can imagine like on the on the
wallet screen that rue tau showed you
with all of your balances
your l dot balance will actually always
be going up
because it's it's showing you it's a
receipt for your staked dot
so as your staked dot starts earning
more and more staking rewards that'll be
reflected in your
ldot balance so when you go to redeem
your ldot
for like native dot at the end
whenever you want to unstake your l dot
will have gone up
since the moment you actually got your
original l dot if that makes sense
because it's just it's always reflecting
your staking rewards adding on to your
stack of ldap yeah think about
as if eldor is a share of the pool of
the staking pool
and the staking pool is growing size
because there's going to be staking
reward that's
praying to the pool but you can always
redeem um for the same share that you
put it in
so your your that up the the redeeming
number will be always growing so holding
lg holding lksm is as if you are
staking yeah
and it's slightly if you have l or you
have lksm
because we call it liquid right it's
actually transferable within the archive
shot and
within the wider pocket ecosystem you
can send ldap to someone else you can
send lksm to someone else
as he was just moving um as if he's just
moving some
of some some transferrable assets um the
the recipient who gets lg or google
gets klksm can choose to continue to
hold
on the the lks ml dot or they can
continue to
decide to redeem um and get the actual
valina dot back
so this is like the the reason we call
it liquid is that it's transferable it
could be used for other utility as well
and one big utility that you can use
with this l ksm is that
you can actually borrow against um your
lksm
in the demo that i showed earlier is
that you can borrow
against your stack asset so you don't
actually have to give up your
opportunity cost if you say that you
want to borrow against thoughts
you have to choose that hey do i want to
select these thoughts or do i want to
borrow against my dog
but with ldl always lksm this is the
best of both
you could be earning the staking reward
while you're borrowing against a
position
and yeah um dan any any question
yeah one question um from
jack here in the chat is it's basically
like
what he said what happens if you trade
or sell your ldot so you have like the
stake dot you get this l dot
let's say you sell it all and you have
so what happens then to your original
dot like how do you actually
either pay for that or get get the dot
so think about the outdoor it's like an
a receipt or redeems the receipt for
your stakedown right so if you sell your
l dot you actually sell the right
to redeem those stocks so it's as if you
sell the dollar someone else so in the
demo that i just showed
uh earlier if i transfer some ldl to
somewhere else
i was transferring the the redeem right
of the underlying dot
to someone else so it's as if i was
sending dots so if you sew them then you
just slice
your solder dots it's um it's no longer
yours and
yeah the redeem right for that length is
also no longer yours
okay so the the l dot isn't connected
directly to
like a specific dot it's kind of that
pool so if i so if jack here who asked a
question
sent me his l dot i could type that l
dot and redeem it for dot
in the akala pool yes yeah okay
yeah the moment that you the moment that
you stick with the the
liquid sticking pool um the dog enter
the pool
and you essentially get is that what you
essentially get back is the right to
redeem
for the dog and because dog itself is
not functional it's fungible like every
single dog is the same
you can't say that okay that dog is my
dog and that dog is your dog they are
all dogs
yes this guy this sage law said so the
ldad is like the title to a car
so if you sell the title someone else
kind of owns the car
yes since um another good question is
basically could you explain how the the
interest
or the staking interest works since
you're staking
with a kala versus i guess in the in
this case with karua so if you're
staking your ksm with karua it's not
staking like
directly into the kusama chain there's
this there's this kind of application
layer so
they're asking who is paying that
percent interest for
um in the carrera case lksm staking
how does that work well well awesome
like this is a good question right so
the
um think about the um the liquid staking
pool as a trustless staking pool
the dot other the ksm that you deposit
into the pool will be managed by the
network and the
network will then nominate those dots
into the
um validator within the kusama network
and if this dot is
these pool sizes grow in size it will be
managed it will be nominated across
multiple validators in the in the kusama
network
so ultimately the staking reward of the
of um staking by minting the lksm would
be
equivalent to the average eu of the
network it will be safer because like d2
is spread across
multiple validators so even a slash
happens
the risk of like the pool is sort of
like meditated
because only slash a portion a tiny
portion of that but the same
um the sticking reward is also the
average eu
it's like a safe average view of the
expected return
of the network and one key other
fact we need to understand is also the
lksm holders actually can vote for
validators so this is what we are
working progress so
when you meet lksm you guys you have the
the right to say that i
prefer the pool to validate and delegate
the ksm into this set of validators and
ultimately
the pool would check all the input from
the lksm holders
and nominate those um those um kusama
for across all the validators um as
proportion as a portion
okay so yeah so if i'm understanding
correctly just to
to reiterate this for um i forget who
who asked that question but
with kusama now if you're staking
through polka dot js it's you as a user
staking directly to
a validator or a set of validators in
this case
in this case there's kirura in the
middle so you
stake with karua karua distributes the
stake of
everyone on karua to an evenly
distributed set of validators across
kusama and then all the returns coming
in from
those validators are pooled and then
evenly distributed at the average
across all the validators that career is
staking with
yes and if this is like a centralized
staking service then you have the risk
of the
centralized entity being default you
have this chart you have to trust the
centralized entity
um to do the right thing but since um
the the liquid staking protocol that we
currently have
is trustless everything is managed on
chen
uh you can think of like it's like an
advanced version of smart contract
um everyone is staking in a trustless
way and there's no risk of
um of being um managed by one single
centralized entity
so this is the i think this is awesome
this is the way to go um for
um in a sense yokusama even you stick
through the liquid staking
yokusama never leave your custody
yep we have some just really good
questions here so um
kalyan asked um
okay so by staking or by making dot
liquid are we compromising the safety of
the polka dot
chain the dot can be slash still be
slashed right
um what happens then the
so basically he's asking what happens
with like network security and slashing
okay i think this is an awesome question
right so um if the
polka dots network security can be
compromised
by saying that you simply pull up the um
the dot together
and make it transferable and make it
liquid
then i think um it's gonna happen anyway
like there's always a lot of centralized
entities so if you stick with
finance today you can already transfer
your stack asset you can trade it in the
market or things like that
so the thing is that i we don't think
this is going to affect the
um the pokers network security at all
because ultimately
if by simply reprogram or by gaming by
by
building something on top of the network
and you can affect security
then there's actually a security problem
of the underlying layer in this in our
case we don't think that's
gonna have any problem um the other key
stuff to think about if you stick
through this particular
liquid staking pool you actually do not
have the
like the risk-free way to say that you
are no longer getting chance of getting
slashed
so if the liquid staking pool was
delegating or nominating
let's say across 50 validators and one
of those getting slashed
the pool actually will get a hit of
getting this slashed but
the the result of like spreading this
pool
across 50 validator is that even though
you you're getting slash in one
validator
the overall damage for the whole pool is
particularly low and that's why i say
it's a
safe way to stake uh it's getting the
average view of the network
it's not trying to seek for the maximum
return
but it's also a very very user-friendly
way that you can always expect to earn
the expected return of the network
um if you were stating by yourself and
if you're nominating your dot to one
particular
validator and then if that validator was
misbehaving it slashed
then you will get a you will take a
touch by normally getting that validator
if you stick through this pool
there's still chances that value gets
latched but the overall cost
for the pool holders will be even out
and will be
reduced
cool so hopefully that helps kalyan
[Music]
oh another thing to maybe mention or
show
is um one of the current issues on
polka dot and kusama right now is are
the there are two things the staking
minimums
are becoming super high on polka dot and
also on kusama
um so what this allows is
for people to come in and stake dot with
like virtually no minimum right like
what would the yes
what would the actual minimum be so this
is like um
i have friends that has like 40 dots
right and my friend really wants to
steak but you can't because the mini
mistaking amount on product
currently i think it's over 200 which is
um a lot
but in this if you stick through um kura
or if you stick through alcohol
you actually can get you can actually
bypass this limitation
because like the pool itself like this
particular gs uh
controlled by the protocol uh will
actually definitely have more than 200
dots
to nominate so no matter how much how
how small amount you have you can still
deposit into this pool
and the pool by itself can nominate um
the total amount of install to all the
validators so yes
we can definitely bypass that and then
the other thing is um
people who are staking through polka dot
js or
um any of the other kind of more native
staking like not
uh exchanges and centralized stuff with
polka dot js right now
you stake ksm and you have to do this
seven day unbonding period
and then with polka dot it's even longer
it's 28 days so it just takes forever to
unlock
with uh with karua and with akala you
can
in talking maybe you can show this but
um basically you can un-stake
early for a small fee
um and that fee is shown i think as
you're kind of um
not checking out but as you're kind of
going through this process
yeah so fee so in this case you're
you're basically unstaking instantly
right and then you're paying a fee of
.02 dot
yes so the design of the liquid sticking
pool is that if i go to the advanced
tab you will see that we always have
some maintenance some free
dots or some free kusama available for
redeem immediately
so let's say that if an user we really
want to redeem
um the l dot back to dots immediately
you can do so because there's always
a portion to set aside um for free um to
redeem
but if you want to redeem immediately
you need to pay a fee to cover the
otherwise lost return of those free
portion of the
um and also like this is not option this
is not compulsory so if you want to
redeem
there's actually three way for you to
redeem you can say that i want to redeem
now then i will
i will have to pay some fee all you say
that i was gonna redeem
the typical way um that's like waiting
for the standard unbounding period
you can free to do so or you can also
redeem to say that i want to redeem and
there's
a queue of unbounding um dots on the
on the on the on the on the staking pool
because like will be always
rebalanced between the stick dots and
the an unstacked dot so you can choose
that which may be like
five player later you need the dots that
will be at that particular price
so it's actually a lot of like advanced
feature hidden in here that you can
redeem
in multiple way um you can redeem at no
cost or you can redeem immediately
so in that in the middle one that you
just showed um
basically the main difference would be
every
every day closer to the current date
you're just
paying a little bit higher of a fee is
that right yes yes
so thinking about that you want to um
with your money from a fixed term
deposit account
right so you have to pay some fee or you
have to lose some interest if you want
to withdraw money from a fixed um
from a fixed um deposit account and how
much you want to
how urgently you need the money um
depend and you will forfeit
how much interest you will be giving
back
awesome so i think that's um the the
show off
of the uh of the liquid staking protocol
and um all these three particles like
they work with each other
um the liquid staking dots on the lksm
can be used um to borrow um can be used
as character
can betray in the decks as well um and
because we call ourselves like as a as a
specialized network
i would like to really show off
something that's like why we call
ourselves as a specialized network is
because like we can
customize stuff that's outside um the
um outside application layer we can
customize a logic has
in the blockchain layer that can create
something that's like amazing
to boost the user experience much much
friendlier so what i'm going to do here
is i'm going to switch to a brand new
account right
i have this brand new account and i have
nothing else but 500
usd or kusd in this case i have no other
assets
we have this like pay as a goal or like
fix the fee or bring your own gas
i can start to trade immediately as i as
long as i have some assets
in the guru network so i'm going to send
a hundred dollars to
an another address i will just press
confirm i'm going to type in my password
and i can send it and the network is
happily taking
a fetch uh uh the iusd that i sent it
was it will charge
like a half of a dollar of the usd as
the network fee
so this is already a huge um user
experience
boost compared to other blockchains this
is like making the
transaction in akala or in kura much
much
friendlier and another very common
scenario
um that you experience is that uh if you
arrive on
kuru or you arrive on kala kala you have
only dots right you have nothing else
but dogs
um and in this particular cases you
still want to transact
within uh we sing within kurura you can
do so so
i'm gonna borrow against my 1.5
kusama let's pretend it in these cases
i'm going to borrow against that
i have no other assets i have only dots
i can still change that
i can change that and the network is
happy to take a friction off my god
or my kusama as the network fee to allow
me to transact
so this is like what we call uh bring
your own gas flexi
flexi fee and this is like you are not
forced you are not
uh you are not forced to buy some native
tokens just to in order to
to pay for the guest fee we think a
specialized financial network
should be as smooth as possible should
be encouraging
um the user to trader to trade other
than tight you should really get some
token before you can trade
uh so this is the one the special
functionality um that you can see that
the power um
if you can customize the network into
the core level
yeah um this person jack asked a really
good question
um and it's it's exactly right so he's
so um
is there any question regarding like how
we um how we show this um
this fixed flexible fee payment on gas
yeah can you can you hear me
oh can you hear me i think we lost dan
um but don't worry
i can continue to
i'm
rita i'm here can you can you guys hear
me
um i can't hear you dan um
can you hear me then okay oh well
i think for some reason i can see dan
the spinning the spinning okay that's
great
um maybe then i will i will try to
rejoin
or you can you can you can carry in the
conversation i will try to rejoin and
see if you can uh
if i can hear you let me let me try to
rejoin okay
cool
okay well i'm glad it wasn't just me
um so let's see what was i gonna say oh
yeah there was a question about
um from
from who was it jack oh about how the
pay your own gas or what's it
basically the gas fee um bring your own
gas so
as i try to invite roytel back
uh basically you were is it is he right
there you hear me now
yeah i can hear you right now i think
it's awesome like we're building we're
building web
we're building web 3.0 but now the web
2.0
streaming service failed on us okay
i was i was trying to answer the
question so
jack you are exactly right the way that
the gas fee
actually works um on the surface on the
ui
to the user it looks like you're paying
in bitcoin or
link or eth or whatever it might be but
on the back end you're exactly right
it's actually being sent to the akala
dex on the back end and transferred for
the aca which is actually the fee that
has to be paid for that transaction
so you were right there
so yeah ruta do you have anything else
in terms of demo
we've got 51 questions
yeah i would just maybe um in my screen
show off um
what one additional reason that you i
mean all the kusama holders should
support
kura it's like when we launched guru
um dan already hinted there's going to
be a liquidity mining um
reward incentive program so
it'll be super awesome like if you
launch if kura launched
you can not only you can start to trade
your kusama token
you can also earn some return by
providing liquidity
by maintaining stablecoin there's a lot
of fun stuff you can do
by participating in this network as an
early computer so i think this is
a really amazing chance to push straight
no better way to push up kusama with a
set of
useful consumer um protocol along with a
way to participate the network and get
return
get rewards yeah i know we actually had
a question about
that six percent someone kept
someone asking a few times um is
so i guess um bit i need to find
bayes bayes was asking and i just like
there's so many questions
uh well hey
i guess baze will find that question and
come back to it
someone also asked about the crowd loan
and
how they lock and contribute to all that
let's keep the conversation um kind of
focused more on the product today
there's going to be
we've done crowd loan presentations in
the past and we're going to be doing
at least one probably more before that
starts
so trust us we're going to be giving you
probably more education than you even
need on how that whole process works and
we'll
we'll be doing that um when the time
comes we're
we're waiting just like you guys and we
don't know dates or anything like that
but it's it's going to be soon it's it's
looking like
um the question about the liquidity was
six percent of kr will be allocated to
early
liquidity providers how many early
providers will that
apply to and is there like a fixed
amount or how does that
work no because like this is a brand new
area right so
um we think six percent is going to be
distributed across
the very first 12 months is upon network
genesis
and that's the total the minimum total
that we the network is willing to
incentivize um
early adopters and because like this is
a brand new area
we will be reviewing um all the
governance process of the network we're
reviewing
uh where incentive incentive is needed
at most for example if more stable coin
is needed um
every two week the governance process
will review there should be more
incentive deploying
into the stable stable coin meeting if
more tax volume or the more tax
liquidity is needed
um every two weeks the government's
process will say that okay there will be
slightly more incentive in the in the in
the decks at that particular pair
so you'll be constantly updating but the
goal for the network is to give out
um six percent at minimum with for the
various 12 months
for everyone that contributing that's
trading that's providing liquidity
that's meaning stablecoin
um or maintain the lksm token in the
network
so yeah there's so many ways to
participate
and that so i guess there's a little bit
more to his question like
or his or her i don't know um the first
he's saying or he or she is saying like
the first is it is it a cap on
like time how do you how does the six
percent get distributed across that
12 months if there's all these different
ways of
allocating that yeah i think that's like
the
in the very early we because the network
was freshly generous
genocide so we don't know um and what it
really depends on
every constant review of every two weeks
but um
the goal is to to dispute this i think
the very early there will be more
uh incentive as well currency to end
will be slightly less
um because that by then the level should
be already bootstrapped so
i think the best way um to get more the
maximum amount of reward that you're
able to get is to get in early
and constantly checking the governance
process of like where the most incentive
will be located there
and supply um to those um protocols
cool okay well we're hitting an hour
so for those of you who need to go um
feel free we're finished with the
presentation um
we've got a lot of questions so i think
we can spend
maybe 10 minutes working through these
as quickly as we can
and what what we can do and
this is going to take some work but i
think we can we can commit to this is
we'll go through the questions
afterwards that we didn't answer and if
there's any
questions that are like particularly
good questions we'll get some q
a written up and send that as a
follow-up to everybody who is on this
on this call so apologies if we can't
get to your question but we'll
answer as many as we can now and then
respond with the others
so the first
question is um
the most upvoted so they're asking
um i i think one of the most asked
questions is unanswered
was yesterday's build a call email
official
well there's um how do i say that
there's a
community reward event so if you do have
a code
and if you do check the website's
official
icloud.network then it is the official
channel and if you received any emails
from
akala foundation just make sure you're
checking the domain
if it's at akala.network then that's
coming from
the akala foundation
second question is um
okay is there a date for kurora's
auction process i already answered that
no soon
um okay let's see
they're asking if the if u.s citizens
will be eligible for
the crowd loans and parachain auctions
um we are working with regulators
and legals and i don't have a
definitive answer at this stage it's
likely
maybe but we will know that um
it's not a no but it's also not a yes
but we'll know that once um the auction
process opens cool
okay
this okay this question i answered about
l dot and dot
the kind of receipt and how your l dot
balance is going to be constantly going
up in relation to reflect what your dot
balance is doing behind the scenes with
the staking
that's a good question
um so in the intensity stable coin dusty
swings
will be made
so
so the next question i see is um
carrera is intended to be the defy hub
of kusama and akala
will be the defy hub of polka dot um
will this be the only defy hubs or will
there also be other
d5 platforms well we see
the um the poke gonna have like a 100
power chance
so there's going to be always open and
trustless way for people to build right
but what i can say is that currently
karura is going to be the product and we
want the permanent project
in in kusama we had a very well the top
developed project
um in terms of like project completeness
so we have the code set
uh the whole code ready to go being
audited three times
um so i mean as things evolve there will
be more specialized network but i think
at this stage we will say that we
are the most ready the top pronoun
project
to go in this in this direction and
obviously the question regarding like
what the the kusama
the crew are serving kusama and the
akala serving polka dots
the the idea behind is that guru is
always going to serve the kusama
community and the kusama community's
culture
is very different from the polkadot
community sculpture
so i'm always using this example that
for kusama it's like
wilder it's like i don't want to say dgm
but it's more of like
risk-taking aggressiveness um and
vibrance
um polkadot is more of like um serious
um
security uh bankrupt security or things
like that so
upon launch this two network is the same
but they will evolve in their own very
distinctive style i would say
okay i'm gonna keep skip there's a lot
of build-a-collar questions we've
already answered that
um
so this so why i have a kala in kura i
already answered that
too it's basically to serve the d5
demand of of the kusama and polka dot
yeah and then i think there's a lot of
questions in the chat regarding that can
a u.s citizen participate in the crowd
on
i i mentioned earlier that i didn't say
no
but i mean we are working with with
legals and regulators
i don't have a definitive answer today
but we'll find out right
yep um
how many they're asking how many kar
they could
potentially receive as part of the crowd
loan for kusama
um yeah i think i'm very already shared
the numbers right so for the
one year lease the minimum amount of kr
that you are receiving
per kusama contributed is 12. you might
get more but that's the minimum amount
it's guaranteed
and with with that being said we know
that polka dot
has the maximum lease pair chain slot
lease of two years
we don't actually know yet the kusama
team hasn't revealed the the maximum
so when rurita is saying one to 12
plus this is for assuming we have a one
year slot
there's a chance that it could be less
than that or more than that we this is
one of the key things we're waiting on
from
gavin and the team at kusama yeah that's
the culture of kusama like expect health
you don't know until it's live
like a day before yeah
um exchanges
let's we'll skip that and you'll just
find out later
um okay um
they're asking this is a good question
and kind of more recent so
why did akala decide to re-denominate to
1 billion and kr at 100 million
well i think it's mostly due to the
reason that
polkadot itself has a redenomination
it will give out a much nicer ratio like
for example if you
um take kusama you get some kr token you
will see
you will see the similar nice ratio when
you stick dot to get some
aca token as well it's purely for that
reason um
yep um hope to answer that
yeah and the other aspect of it is the
the underlying like
the decimal point problem there was
quite a bit of issues with
um i think polkadot in the beginning
keeping the original token supply
added a lot of complexity with like too
long of decimal places
so that was the other that was the other
reason for
the akala one
i call
okay um
let's see take a couple more
oh someone's asking about the
collectibles tab
uh nfts and maybe i can just add to this
like what is zakala's
kind of i guess thoughts around or
strategy around nfts
i think there's already you can see
there's a collectible tab there's
already
some collectible being given in the test
nets um
because we've been building this test
net for a long time so i think that
hasn't been up and running for over half
a year
it's a way to reward the early uh
participants
in the test net there's already some
entity being minted in the testnet and i
think they would also be carrier
uh to mainnet as well um and
then maybe you can share a little bit
like um about the collectible that maybe
we have some
surprise when we're going to go launch
on the on the crowd on stage i'm not
sure how much you want to share but
maybe
take the stage dan um
yeah i don't think there's too much to
share on that like quite yet so we
we're just thinking around other ways to
kind of think and incentivize
um people who are early contributors and
crowd loan supporters so
um there could be some kind of surprises
that pop up in that
collectibles tab come come time for the
crowd loans yeah i would just say that
we think uh we are we are making history
right so i mean
if you guys uh put supporting along with
this right uh maybe there's a piece of
um
unique collectible that may be earned
through this process
here's a question that i saw pop up a
few times today
um who is this that's a good question
brian
so as traffic picks up within the
network how does this affect
gas and this is a question that
relates to kusama and polka dot um so
maybe you can
answer that one yeah okay awesome
question i think the um
my point of view on gas fee is that we
want to keep the gas as low
as possible it's um the gas fee is not a
way um to boost the network values
in fact the gas fee should be kept as
low to
as possible to encourage transaction
activity happen on the network and
there's that those are the stuff that
bring the network values
um in our rough test as a project and i
think we
see tps scale at a thousand or above
that
so um the way that we calculate gas is
weight based rather than the
the mechanism you most of people
familiar with the ethereum which is like
building
for the photogas fee because
the power chain has much higher capacity
in processing transactions
we think um we're able to maintain a
very low gas fee
um for for for as extend extend
i would say for the for the near short
term to medium term futures um i don't
think that's going to be a problem
and if we are hitting even hitting that
bottleneck of like two thousand
or a thousand transaction per second uh
the ultimate solution um
it's just like in the imagination um
stage at this stage is always
what scavenges polkadot within pogba
does there's a little bit long term but
i don't
want to get kept to carry too much on
that i would say there's always scalable
solution
when building a polka dot and we always
have a way to maintain low gas fee
yeah i want to pulse i showed something
last time that
that people i think liked and i'll just
share just to add on to what you're
saying about polka dot within polka dot
um if i can find it real quick oh yeah
here it is
so it's it's
definitely something that's in the
future but it's it's pretty interesting
to
to kind of think about so i'll just
share this real quick
and i will i will say that this is this
is nothing official
this is a this is something that i built
myself when i heard about polka dot 2.0
and what it could potentially be
and what he what retal is referring to
is like relay chains within relay chains
so what you could have is a kala
starting as a para chain here
but then this eventually deciding to
branch out and build our own relay chain
which then connects into the original
polka dot so you've got polka dot within
polka dot within
polka dot in this diagram and this is
potentially
where we could be heading in the future
kind of fun to think about
we'll see if it comes true
um okay it's let's take like one more
question
carrera tokenomics i pasted the link in
the chat
so akala dot network slash karua slash
token
is a good place to go for that
and yeah let's let's call it a day we've
been here for an hour and 15. like i
said i'll go through the questions and
anything that we didn't answer i'll
try to create a response if it's if it's
a good question
and that's that's about it hopefully you
guys learned something new about
i i know i i learned something new and
had fun looking at the product demos
this will be this is being recorded and
this is going to be live
on our youtube so definitely um
watch out for our twitter we'll post the
link on our twitter and then feel free
to share it with your friends if you
learned something and want to kind of
help spread the word so
um thanks everybody for taking the time
to join us
and we will definitely see you soon yeah
thank you super excited and can't wait
for the product to go live please
support us
bye guys bye guys