สวัสดีทุกคน ฉัน Dan Reecer เป็น VP
of Growth ที่ Acala และ Karura
ลแะวันนี้ฉันจะให้คุณเห็นภาพรวมของ DeFi,
Polkadot Kusama และส่วน
สำคัญที่สุดของ Acala
และ
Karura
เราจะเริ่มด้วย
เบสิคว่า DeFi คืออะไร
ทำไมการเคลื่อนไหวนี้ถึงได้เริ่มต้นขึ้น
และแก้ปัญหาอะไรได้บ้าง
จากนั้นเราจะย้ายไปที่พูดถึงบริบท
ที่จำเป็นของ Polkadot และ Kusama,
ก่อนจะไปพูดถึง Acala และ Karura
คริปโตและ DeFi แน่นอนว่าเริ่มประมาณปี
2008-2009
และอะไรที่การเงินแบบกระจายอำนาจ
พยายามจะแก้
ปัญหาของระบบการเงิน
หลายล้านคนทั่วโลก
ขึ้นอยู่กับประเทศที่คนอยู่อาศัย
มีหลากหลายวิธีการเข้าถึง
ระบบการเงินเพื่อจะได้รับ
ผลลัพธ์ทางการเงินที่ดีขึ้น
มากกว่าคนอื่น ๆ ในประเภท
ที่แค่โชคดีกว่า
นอกจากนี้ยังมีปัญหาบางอย่างกับ
รัฐบาล: แต่ละรัฐบาล
ทั่วโลกก็มี
การควบคุมระบบการเงินไม่มากก็น้อยในแต่ละประเทศ
และผู้คนที่อาศัยอยู่ใน
รัฐบาลที่มีการควบคุม
ระบบเศรษฐกิจ
และสร้างปัญหาอย่าง เงินเฟ้อ
DeFi สร้างทางให้ผู้คนมีการ
เข้าถึงระบบการเงินแบบใหม่
สำหรับโอกาสที่ดีกว่าสำหรับเงินของพวกเขา
ดังนั้นระบบใหม่นี้จึงเปิดกว้างมาก มัน
ต้องการ
ข้อจำกัดน้อยลงเพื่อให้คุณสามารถเข้าถึงได้
ไม่ต้องมี
บัตรประจำตัว ไม่ต้องมีบัญชีธนาคาร
ไม่ต้องมีแต้มเครดิต ระบบการเงินที่เปิดกว้างมากขึ้น
ที่เราทุกคนร่วมกันสร้างณ ตอนนี้
โดยฟังก์ชันหลักของ DeFi เหมือนมากๆกับ
ฟังก์ชันหลักของโลกการเงินแบบดั้งเดิมที่สร้าง
ทางไปสู่
DeFi คุณจะมีตลาดการเงิน
ซึ่งเป็นเหมือน peer-to-peer
การยืมและการให้ยืม
การซื้ออนุพันธ์ การแลกเปลี่ยนแบบกระจายอำนาจ
อีกฟังก์ชันหนึ่งคือ stablecoin ที
สำคัญมากๆสำหรับระบบนิเวศน์ของ DeFi แน่นอน
เพราะว่า
ทรัพย์สินที่ผันผวนเช่น Bitcoin และ
Ethereum ซึ่งผันผวนมาก
คุณจะมีเหรียญ stablecoin ซึ่งจะ
อนุญาติให้ผู้คนถือสิ่งที่
จริงๆมันเป็นการรักษาความเสถียรด้วย PEG
ของมูลค่า
นี่ทำให้ฉันช็อคมากเมื่อฉันทำสไลด์
ย้อนกลับไปเมื่อหนึ่งปีที่แล้ว
ในเมษายน ปี 2020
จำนวนมูลค่ารวมที่ถูกล็อคใน DeFi
อยู่ที่ประมาณ 800 ล้านดอลลาร์
และก้าวไปข้างหน้าอย่างรวดเร็วจนถึงวันนี้
เพิ่มเป็น 82 หรือ 83 เท่า
จากมูลค่ารวมของปีที่แล้วที่
ล็อคในโปรโตคอลของ
DeFi
DeFi ในฤดูร้อน 2020 อย่างน้อยก็
ฤดูร้อนซีกโลกเหนือ
ถึงจะเปรียบความร้อนแรงของ DeFi ได้
มีทีมใหม่ๆ
จำนวนมาก สภาพคล่องใหม่ๆไหลเข้าสู่
DeFi ที่เป็นเทรนด์ในตอนนี้
เรากำลังดูมันเติบโตต่อไป
ตลาดเงิน Compound คือหนึ่งในทีมที่
บุกเบิกบนพื้นที่ของ Ethereum ได้ดีที่สุด
นี่คือตัวอย่างของ
หนึ่งใน use case ที่สำคัญบน DeFi
ตอนนี้
ที่คุณเห็นด้านซ้ายมือนี้คุญจะเห็น
supply ของตลาด และด้านขวานี้
คุณจะเห็น ผู้ยืม
ด้านซ้าย ถ้าฉันมี DAI เป็น stablecoin
ฉันสามารถเข้าไปและเติม
สภาพคล่องสู่ตลาด จะได้รับ 6.8%
อยากน้อยก็วันนี้ ด้านขวาก็เหมือนกัน
ถ้าฉันต้องการออกและคิดว่า
ราคา Bitcoin จะสูงขึ้น หรือฉัน
ต้องการใช้ stablecoin ฉันสามารถไป
ยืม
Dai ด้วยการค้ำประกัน
เท่าที่ฉันสามารถจ่ายค่า
ธรรมเนียมของ stablecoin นี้ได้
นั่นทำให้มันกลายเป็นเหมือน
การยืมแบบ peer-to-peer
โดยมีตัวกลางคือ Compound
Stablecoin เป็นอีกหนึ่งสิ่งที่สำคัญสำหรับ
DeFi ซึ่งมี
4 แบบหลักๆ
จะมี
ชื่อดังอย่าง USDC ทีเป็น
เหรียญของ coinbase
ซึ่งมีการค้ำประกันด้วยเงิน fiat
ดังนั้นมีจะเหมือนมีเงิน US dollar ในธนาคาร
แบ็คหลังทุกๆเหรียญ USDC นั่นจะนำปัญหา
มาสู่ตลาด
และอันที่สามนี่ คุณสามาถเห็นว่า
เป็นคริปโตที่มีการค้ำประกัน ดังนั้นมัน
เป็นชนิดเหรียญที่มี algorithmic แบ็คหลัง
stablecoin
MakerDAO DAI คือตัวอย่างที่ดีที่สุด
สำหรับการอธิบาย
Acala และ Karura ทั้งคู่ สร้างเหรียญ
stablecoin เป็นของตัวเอง ดังนั้นจะมี
aUSD เงินดอลลาร์ของ Acala โดยคุณจะเห็นบน
สไลด์นี้
และ kUSD สำหรับเครือข่ายลูกอย่าง
Karura  ซึ่งเป็นดอลลาร์เกาหลี
อีกหนึ่งมูลค่าตัวอย่างที่
ขึ้นที่ Colombia
พวกเขาสร้างมันด้วย Substrate
เทคโนโลยี เหมือนกับ
ที่สร้าง Acala และพวกเขามี
การพิสูจน์แล้วว่าเป็นตัวอย่างที่ยอดเยี่ยมของ
stablecoin ที่ใช้ในโลกแห่งความเป็นจริง ดังนั้น
พวกเขามีคน Columbia จำนวนมาก
ที่ต้องการส่งเงินจากที่บ้านไปสู่
ครอบครัวและเพื่อนใน Venezuela
และพวกเขาส่งมันมากกว่า 8 ล้าน
ดอลลาร์ โดยใช้ แอปพลิเคชันที่ใช้
เหรียญ stablecoin
Uniswap เป็นอีกหนึ่งตัวอย่างสำคัญ
ของเมเจอร์โปรโตคอล DeFi
บน Ethereum
ซึ่งมันถูกเรียกว่า automated
market maker
เอ็กเชนจ์แบบกระจายอำนาจ ซึ่งมัน
เป็นการ swap ธรรมดา จาก token นึงไปเป็นอันอื่น
และทางที่ทำให้มันเป็นขึ้นมาได้คือ
ในเบื้องหลังมีผู้คน
ได้เพิ่มสภาพคล่องไปทุกๆคู่บน
Uniswap
ในทางกลับกัน การให้สภาพคล่องไปที่คู่เหรียญ
พวกเขาจะได้รับ LP token และได้รับ
รางวัลจากการเป็นผู้ให้สภาพคล่อง
ดังนั้นเรามีเบื้องหลัง
ใน DeFi และในระบบนิเวศน์ทั้งหมด,
ตัวอย่างที่เด่นชัดของ Ethereum DeFi
เราจะย้ายไปพูดถึง
Polkadot และ ทำไม Polkadot ถึงถูกสร้างขึ้น
ดังนั้นคนที่คิดค้น Ethereum virtual machine
และคนที่สร้างภาษาโปรแกรมมิ่ง Solidity
เขาคือ Gavin Wood ผู้รับรู้
ว่า Ethereum จะไม่สามารถ
ขยายได้มากกว่านี้
ข้ามมาปัจจุบันปี 2021 เขาพูดถูก
ดูที่ค่าธรรมเนียม Gas บน Ethereum
Ethereum ไม่สามารถขยายสเกลได้ ทุกคนต่างรอ
Ethereum 2.0
ซึ่งจะใช้เวลาเป็นปีในการสร้าง
ในขณะเดียวกัน Gavin
Robert Habermeiner และ Peter Czaban
ผู้ร่วมก่อตั้ง Polkadot
พวกได้สร้าง Kusama ซึ่งเป็นเหมือน
เครือข่ายญาติของ
Polkadot ซึ่งจะพูดทีหลัง Gavin
สร้าง Polkadot เพื่อ
ต้องการ
สร้างระบบนิเวศน์แบบ multi-chain เพื่อสู้กับ
บล็อคเชน
แบบเดี่ยวๆ อย่างเช่น Bitcoin และ
Ethereum
มีสิ่งที่ต้องปรับแต่งเพิ่มเติมสำหรับการสร้างบล็อคเชน
แพลตฟอร์มเช่น Ethereum นั้น
เราจะเรียกว่าเป็นบล็อกเชน Layer หนึ่ง แต่
พวกเขาพยายามจะทำให้ทุกอย่างอยู่
ในหนึ่ง chain มันไม่ได้ถูกกำหนดและ
optimized for any specific purpose.
With Substrate, which is the framework
that Gavin created for building on Polkadot
and Kusama,
with Substrate we can actually custombuild
blockchains and
and alter the blockchain at the core
level
for a specific use. So in Acala and Karura
case we have
optimized the core of our blockchain
platform,
which is a layer one equivalent to
Ethereum, we've optimized that
for DeFi specifically. When we
launch
on Acala and on Polkadot, we'll be plugging
into this
existing network of other blockchains
that we can communicate
value and data with and also, potentially
even more importantly, the security of
Polkadot. So, Polkadot is now
a 40 plus billion dollar network, so all
of that value
is held within these validator nodes
and all those validators are able to
help
validate transactions for
accuracy and also secure
all the parachains that connect to the
Polkadot relaychain, as you can see in
this
diagram here. Polkadot will also,
not only connect blockchains within
Polkadot, but it will also bridge to
existing networks like Ethereum
and like Bitcoin. And then, as I mentioned,
we've got Kusama as well. Kusama is the
exact same code base,
the same architecture as Polkadot with
this
relaychain in the middle and then all
these parachains are
these customized blockchains built
on top of Kusama's Layer 0
meta-protocol,
as we call it. Polkadot and Kusama will
exist
together and this pink dot in the middle
is meant to show you that these two
networks will be bridged as soon as both
are live. So
anything built on Kusama will be able to
communicate with any
parachain or application on Polkadot.
Kusama is slightly different than Polkadot
in that
one, it's faster and not in terms of
transaction speed, but in terms of
how quickly you can get things done and
approved through governance. So
developers love Kusama because you can
actually push code changes much quicker.
It takes seven days to upgrade Kusama
versus
28 days to get approvals through
governance on Polkadot.
Kusama is also what I like to call an
innovation network,
also sometimes called a canary network,
but this is where
innovation will happen. You can test
things on testnet
and then bring them to Kusama,
which is a real world environment
with real value, and on Kusama is where
you really start to see how things work
out in the wild. Just like Polkadot,
Kusama is a proof-of-stake
network
so
the validators are running proof of
stake and then you can also stake KSM to
earn
staking rewards as you hold KSM.
As I mentioned, where Polkadot and
Kusama will be bridged,
we've used this strategy also in the way
that we launched our network. So
we're building Acala, which is
the DeFi hub of Polkadot.
We are also building Karura, which is the
DeFi hub of Kusama.
A lot of times people ask what will
the future be for Karura once Akala
launches, the answer is that both Acala
and Karura will be running in parallel
together.
Acala will make Karura better and Karura
will make Acala better,
just like the relationship between
Polkadot and Kusama will
continue to operate in parallel together.
Acala and Karura were both founded by
these four people on the slide.
You've got Ruitao, our CEO, Bette
our COO. I work with them quite a
bit they're both more on the business
side
but both are also very technical
engineering minds,
product people with great experience
not only in the blockchain world but
also in traditional product development.
Then you've got Fuyao on the upper right.
So Fuyao is
leading and managing
everything in China, based in
Shanghai. He's also the Founder and CEO
of Polkawallet
and met up with the with Ruitao, Bette and
Bryan
I think about a couple years ago at a
hackathon and the four of them created
the networks Acala and Karura together.
And then last but not least you've got
Bryan Chen. Bryan is one of the best
substrate developers in the world.
He's our CTO and that leads all of our
development.
Bryan also founded and leads the
Substrate Developer Academy
and continues to build and give
back to the Substrate Community as he
grows
the number of developers who are
building with the Substrate framework.
Acala is backed by several top firms so
Pantera,
coinbase Ventures, DCG,
Polychain Capital, just to name a few,
Hypersphere from
our friend Jack and several others on
the slide here and then
many others as well.
So let's get into Acala and Karura.
Acala is
two things: it's a platform for
building
applications on top of, as well as our
own set of applications that we've built
on our blockchain.
This is kind of a new category
development that I haven't seen done
before,
where our team is actually launching the
blockchain itself a Layer 1 blockchain
like Ethereum,
while also launching applications on top
of that chain.
Our decentralized exchange you could
think of as similar to Uniswap,
our borrowing market for the Acala Dollar
and Karura dollar, you could think of as
similar to Maker
and then we've got liquid staking as
well. This is essentially like a Layer 1
blockchain,
like Ethereum launching from day one
with Maker and Uniswap on top,
plus liquid staking. Very excited to
get this out in
in live. This diagram helps illustrate
what i just mentioned.
The Acala DEX, the liquid staking
product and the aUSD stablecoin are
built into the Layer 1 blockchain
itself and then on top of our blockchain
we've built front-end applications
that leverage
these DeFi primitives, as we call them,
that are built into the blockchain.
When Acala launches,
you'll not only be able to build
applications on Acala, but you'll be
able to use
all the applications that we've built
ourselves. Then of course at the
bottom here you've got Polkadot, which
is the
the multi-chain network kind
of securing
Acala and providing cross-chain
capability.
These are the three products that I have just
mentioned and then the fourth one I'll
just mention it very quickly.
The Decentralized Sovereign Wealth Fund
or our treasury
will be built up over time in order
to help create
self-sustainability for Acala and for
Karura.
In Acala's case, we hope to build up this
Decentralized Sovereign Wealth Fund
enough so that in the future,
when we need to bid on a slot in a
parachain auction,
we can actually bid with our own
Sovereign Wealth Fund instead of
needing to raise KSM or DOT through
a crowdloan.
When Ruitao, Bette, Fuyao and Bryan
were deciding
where to build Acala, there were several
options: there was Ethereum 2, there was
Cosmos.
There were several different choices
that they evaluated, but of course
they decided to choose Polkadot. But why
did they choose Polkadot? It's because
of these
kind of six core things: the crosschain
ability and interoperability,
the ability to use Substrate to
customize the chain specifically for
DeFi,
the ability to handle extremely high
transaction rates or transaction volume
through Polkadot,
the ability to govern the network on
chain, so
getting the whole community of ACA
holders to help take part in governance,
versus with Ethereum just one person or
a group of Founders
get to decide the future of the network.
The plug-and-play security is a huge
aspect where we don't have to actually
go out and recruit our own set of
validators to secure our network.
That's why we want to earn a slot on
Polkadot and plug into this existing
network of security.
Last in the bottom right is the
ability to upgrade
without forking.Over time we'll be
able to upgrade the blockchain itself
without needing to fork the community
like we've seen with
maybe ETH and ETH Classic and other
communities over time.
Here's a few of our products, just some
screenshots of them.
On YouTube you can see some product
demos of our products and also
on our applications website
apps.acala.network you can actually go in and
use them live on testnet.
This is what our aUSD product looks
like where people can actually come in
and collateralize, for example, Bitcoin
and take out a loan
of aUSD with their Bitcoin as collateral
without ever having to sell
their Bitcoin. Liquid DOT staking is the
process of staking DOT
to earn interest on your DOT, but, while
your DOT
is staked in earning staking rewards,
you also receive what's called LDOT or
liquid DOT
and this is kind of like a receipt for
your DOT that is
staked and the LDOT that you hold will
actually increase
in value, the number will increase,
because it's going to be reflecting
the returns that your underlying stake
DOT are earning.
With that LDOT you can actually, just
like the name says, it becomes liquid, so
you can
come and use your LDTO and use that
within
all of our DeFi platforms, like the last
slide that i just showed you with aUSD.
I could stake DOT, take out LDOT
and then with the LDOT I could
collateralize that and take out a loan
for aUSD and use that
for whatever purpose I wanted.
The Acala DEX looks
some looks like this: so there will be
trading pairs that you can trade, so in
this example it's Acala
ACA, an aUSD stablecoin,
and the way this is is enabled is
because on the back end there's a whole
pool of liquidity where people are
earning rewards for providing liquidity
to certain pairs.
In this case if I'm trading on the ACA
and aUSD pair,
I would be using liquidity from people
who are providing liquidity to that pair
on the back end.
I won't go through all these token
utility
use cases for ACA, but at its most basic
level, ACA is the governance token for
Acala
and will be used for processing all the
transaction fees on the network.
Now let's get into Karura.
Karura is a platform just like Acala,
a blockchain platform and a set of
applications
all optimized for innovation
and experimentation on Kusama. This is
going to be a really fun
network to be involved in because
there's going to be a lot of new
products launching here,
trying out new risk parameters, new
features
that will go to Karura and then, if proven,
we'll move on to Acala.
We will be launching this
first
on Kusama and the upcoming parachain
auction is all about
Karura. Karura will be launching on Kusama
and this Layer 1 blockchain will have
the same DeFi primitives as Acala does.
In this case the Karura DEX, the liquid
staking for KSM,
instead of for DOT on Acala, and then the
Karura dollar kUSD as the stable coin.
The Karura apps that
we've already built on top of our
blockchain will leverage
all those products that have built been
built into the blockchain itself.
Here's a look at the UI at the
application layer.
On the last slide what I showed you up
here,
these apps look like this:
this would be like creating a loan on
the left you could go and do a swap,
do your liquid staking. This will all
be ready
the day we launch on Kusama.
Just to reiterate, Kusama and
Polkadot will be bridged and
and Karura and Acala will continue to
operate together even after Acala
launches.
After Acala launches, we will be
operating two networks in parallel
and those will continue to operate
together.
The distribution of the KAR supply looks
like this:
so we reduced the amount of tokens going
to the founding team and and shifted
that to the community.
We've also got some backers and early
backers from
when we first started the project and
then, when you break down the community
side,
we have auction rewards for the
parachain auction
and liquidity program, which I'll walk
through next,
some ecosystem development and some
rewards that are
being kind of reserved, as well as
treasury
allocation to keep in the Karura treasury for
the development of the network. Same
token utility for Karura as Acala. This
will be used for transaction fees and
governance of the network as well as
several other different use cases like
deploying smart contracts and other
use cases.
How do we launch on Kusama?
We need to win an auction against
other pairchain teams in order to
launch in this
slot here on Kusama. That process
looks like this.
What you can see here, where this
trophy, is this is the the biggest event,
from here
to here. This is the parachain auction,
where we
and other teams are bidding against each
other in an auction
to try to win this first slot on Kusama.
The goal for the Karura team is absolutely
to win
the auction number one.
We want to be the first team to launch on
Kusama.
Before the auction starts, there will
also be this thing called a crowdloan
that opens.
A crowdloan is actually how the
community can contribute KSM as you see
here
to our crowdloan, so that we can use all
the KSM
that we have in our crowdloan as our
bid
in the auction. When we win the
auction,
Karura will then launch on Kusama and
when that happens all the KSM that was
contributed back here
to the crowdloan will be locked in the
Kusama
relaychain. It will not be touched, it
can't be touched by the team at all.
And then at the same time the native
token of Karura will be issued
to all the contributors at a 12 to 1
minimum
ratio. KAR gets distributed to everyone
who contributed KSM and then Karura would
launch,
all the DeFi applications would be live
and we would be
kind of in business. At the end
of the 48-week slot,
all the KSM that was contributed by
anyone who
participated in the crowdloan would then be
returned to them.
This is what the Karura crowdloan will
look like.
We will start with a minimum of 12 KAR
for every 1 KSM.
This is the reward that everyone who
contributes KSM in the
crowdloan would
get
in KAR. So depending on the participation,
the amount of KAR could be much higher
than 12 but this is just the baseline
that we've set.
Down here you can see the
30%.
What this is referring to is that 30%
of the tokens, that are
distributed to contributors, will be
liquid when the network launches, the
other 70% will then
will then vest over the remainder of
the 48 weeks, so gradually
every day.
Now, in terms of the liquidity mining
program,
another thing that I'm really
excited to get started, so 19%
of the first year's circulating supply
of KAR
will be distributed in the form of
liquidity mining or liquidity provider
programs.
This translates to 6% of the
total supply
and just keep in mind the supply of
Karura is fixed, it will never increase.
So pretty significant opportunity to be
involved in
the early liquidity providing program.
Liquidity mining rewards can be
distributed in 3 primary ways:
through
providing liquidity in the DEXs, through
minting kUSD stablecoins
and then for staking KSM
for liquid KSM or LKSM.
These interest rates or these APY
will that will definitely vary over time.
There's going to be times when certain
trading pairs or certain
protocols need more liquidity and in
that case
the APY would be would rise
for the ones that need more liquidity
and potentially decline for the ones who
are sufficiently liquid at the time.
This is an example of of one person
and
having the ability to earn these
liquidity mining
rewards through these three main
mechanisms, minting stable coins
for a specific APY at that time,
providing liquidity to the DEXs,
and then minting LKSM.
These numbers here are not final
or set and these will
continually vary and be
adjusted,
but this is what the decks could
look like. One of the first pairs that
will go live is
the KAR to KSM pair. There will be
rewards for that pair
at some APY given the day.
There could also be other pairs like KSM,
kUSD,
kUSD BTC, and this will all continue to
evolve
over time. Also
with the stablecoin we will see
liquidity mining rewards for people who
actually go
and take out a loan of KUSD.
For minting a stablecoin by taking out
a loan you would earn additional
kUSD on that reward.
And then last LKSM. So there will be
additional incentives for minting
LKSM through the action of actually
staking
KSM and those rewards would be
distributed in
KAR.
There's also crosschain assets that
will be making it their way to
Karura. These are yet to be finalized,
but things like Bitcoin and Ethereum,
if we needed more Bitcoin liquidity from
say one of the bridges, we could also
incentivize people to bring Bitcoin over
to
Karura. That's it.
Thanks for for the patience and
sitting through this. I hope you learned
something new.
I know we have a team
watching at the meetup here in China,
we've also got our team online,
we're always on Discord
or on Twitter. So feel free to ask us
questions.
One thing that I would encourage you to
do after today is to go to
apps.akala.network
Everything that you've seen today is
live on testnet and ready to launch as
soon as we win
the auction on Kusama and the
auction on Polkadot.
So definitely go in and test out these
things. You can get testnet
tokens through that website
and then try things out. Our goal is to
win
the first parachain auction on Kusama
with Karura and our goal is to win the
first parachain auction on
Polkadot with Acala, so we really
appreciate your
support in helping achieve this this
goal.
If you have the desire to follow us on
any of our Social channels, there's
the linktree for Acala and a linktree
for
Karura. We've basically put every different
link that we have in the community
on these websites, so you can
find anywhere to follow us there.
So that's it. Hopefully you guys have a
good day/good night.
Thanks for watching and we'll talk soon!
Bye.