[Musique]
et c'est une des raisons pour lesquelles
nous pensons que Karura est si utile
lorsque ce sera une parachain vous pourrez
déverrouillez l'utilité de votre jeton Kusama
et commencer à
à emprunter contre votre
your
jeton Kusama
donc ça c'est l'interface d'emprunts
vous pouvez avoir une vue d'ensemble sur votre
position actuelle , vous voyez
j'ai déjà emprunté
j'ai ouvert une position sur renBTC
j'ai emprunté environ trois mille
dollars contre
0.1 renBTC
c'est un peu risqué mais bon c'est ce que
le système permet
vous pouvez créer des prêts en utilisant
tout types d'actifs qui seront rendus disponibles
et autorisés par le processus de gouvernance
à être un collatéral
et sur cette interface spécifiquement ici
j'ai DOT
LDOT, que nous verrons plus tard
ce sera certainement comme ça
ce sera Kusama
LKSM et Bitcoin donc
ce que je vais montrer
est que je vais emprunter
plus
contre ma position 0.1 renBTC ici
donc vous pouvez voir le taux du bitcoin actuel
le taux de l'oracle est
à peu près ce chiffre je suis encore suffisamment en sécurité
pour emprunter un peu plus contre
ce 0.1 renBTC
alors je vais appuyer sur générer plus
je voudrais emprunter genre
peut-être dix dollars de plus
et j'appuie sur confirmer et c'est là que
la signature arrive je vais entrer
ma clé
mon mot de passe et signer la transaction
boom j'ai dix dollars de plus
que je peux dépenser et c'est rapide à ce point
et le réseau de production ressemble à ça
tout ceci se passe à la volée
pour de vrai
um and you can actually see this on the
on the on the block scanner that's
provided by sub scan
so um this is amazing right this is um
much much
more um responsive much much more user
friendly
also i can also replay right i can pay
back i set a position if i think um
i'm going to reduce a little bit of risk
here i can pay about 100 year ausd
that's like reducing my calculation
ratio
and any asset that will be available
through the governance process can be
borrowed against
different assets would have different
risk parameters so for example bitcoin
might have a risk parameter
on the medieval credit ratio on the
liquidation ratio on the liquidation fee
uh dots l dots ksm lksm they might all
have different
ratio they'll be managed and governed by
the governance process
so that is uh essentially how you borrow
against um
kratchos uh in guru
yeah let so maybe one thing we can do
this concept
of collateralization and taking loans is
probably new to a lot of people i know
it was new to me
um at one point and basically like to to
make this as simple as possible
um like i think many of us are aware of
how like a home
loan works where typically you might put
like 10 down or 20
down that cash that you put down is what
you're putting
down in order to get the full the full
loan of whatever you're getting for that
house
but with the way this works in crypto um
we're actually over you're over
collateralizing
the loan so that's why these collateral
ratios are over
100 and you're what you're doing like
what it really means of collateral
is that you're actually taking bitcoin
something like bitcoin
you don't need to sell it but you can
pull out
ausd a stablecoin with your bitcoin
still there
not sold and then you can take the ausd
and either
you can send that to people you can make
payments you can use that to provide
liquidity within our decks but
that's essentially what this collateral
ratio means
yeah essentially give you more utility
um to the asset that you are holding to
that you might not want to sell or in
short term
and for example for fukusama for for
lksm those are perfectly great collector
for you to gain more utility
out of your 16 kusama holdings you can
go long you can go short you can
it's i mean the option is it's in your
hand to decide how you're going to use
this collector um to trade and write
with the market
what about interest so are you paying
interest when you're taking out
these loans and how does that work yes
so the interest essentially is what we
call the stabilization fee
um if you take a long there will be
definitely some interest occur
um and this is also the interest used to
manage the
supply and demand of the stablecar as
well as like the
um the way to maintain that the
stablecoin will be packed to to
a dollar in value and the interest um
all the state
stabilization fee will be managed by the
governance process
really depends on demands and supplies
and do you know your interest rate
before you take out the loan
obviously definitely so let's say that
we want to create a lot we're going to
create some ldl ksm and spectro
i'm going to put in maybe 5l uh l ksm
here and i'm going to take maybe a two
dollar loan
you can already see that um um
the amount of money that you can borrow
the interest rate in here the
liquidation penalty
yeah if things goes wrong that where how
you can but in chance that if you over
capitalize and the position becomes
risky
you might get liquidated so this is the
um the
the the figure that you're able to see
before you
create a lawn and the final confirmation
stage you will be
once again so go ahead and confirm all
the numbers
and press confirm and this is how you
open a long position so
i just created a loan using my lksm and
received like two
dollars so you can say if i now go back
to the interface
i have two position open one with
bitcoin one with um
lksm those is like um and i totally have
borrowed
probably like few thousand dollars
against both um lksm
and ram btc okay that makes sense
and someone asked where does that
interest actually go
well the n26 actually go to the treasury
um
and being managed by the network right
it's uh it's essentially
uh controlled by the network for the
long prosperity of the network
the interest ultimately would be the
surplus within this system
and if you read our white paper
regarding the decentralized solving
wheels fund
the interest is ultimately hold managed
by the token holders
okay the liquidation concept i think is
new to a lot of people
what happens if the token that is
basically collateralized
the value drops so liquidation in this
sense does not mean that you kind of
like lose everything that you put down
that's why there was a liquidation
percentage so in the example rotate just
showed it said 20
yeah i think to better um think about
liquidation it's more of like
uh if you collect allies and you borrow
against your bitcoin and then pick a job
to a particular price
a fraction of your collector will be
sold and you will see that if you were
just like sold those collectors
at that price you would still hold on to
the the money they borrow against it's
just like
you sold those characters at a penalty
you